WE
WE COVER
WE COVER IS
AVAILABLE
AVAILABLE ON
WE COVER IS
AVAILABLE ON OUR
AVAILABLE ON OUR WEBSITE
WE COVER IS
AVAILABLE ON OUR WEBSITE AT
C-SPAN.ORG.
>>
>> HILLARY
C-SPAN.ORG.
>> HILLARY CLINTON
>> HILLARY CLINTON HELD
C-SPAN.ORG.
>> HILLARY CLINTON HELD A
>> HILLARY CLINTON HELD A TOWN
HALL
HALL MEETING
>> HILLARY CLINTON HELD A TOWN
HALL MEETING IN
HALL MEETING IN MANCHESTER,
>> HILLARY CLINTON HELD A TOWN
HALL MEETING IN MANCHESTER, NEW
HAMPSHIRE.
THE
THE FORMER
HAMPSHIRE.
THE FORMER SECRETARY
THE FORMER SECRETARY OF
HAMPSHIRE.
THE FORMER SECRETARY OF STATE
TALKED
TALKED ABOUT
THE FORMER SECRETARY OF STATE
TALKED ABOUT LAST
TALKED ABOUT LAST WEEK'S
THE FORMER SECRETARY OF STATE
TALKED ABOUT LAST WEEK'S LAST
SHOOTING
SHOOTING --
TALKED ABOUT LAST WEEK'S LAST
SHOOTING -- MASS
SHOOTING -- MASS SHOOTING
TALKED ABOUT LAST WEEK'S LAST
SHOOTING -- MASS SHOOTING IN
OREGON
OREGON AND
SHOOTING -- MASS SHOOTING IN
OREGON AND SPOKE
OREGON AND SPOKE WITH
SHOOTING -- MASS SHOOTING IN
OREGON AND SPOKE WITH A
OREGON AND SPOKE WITH A MOTHER
WHOSE
WHOSE SECURE
OREGON AND SPOKE WITH A MOTHER
WHOSE SECURE OLD
WHOSE SECURE OLD SON
OREGON AND SPOKE WITH A MOTHER
WHOSE SECURE OLD SON WAS
WHOSE SECURE OLD SON WAS KILLED
IN
IN THE
WHOSE SECURE OLD SON WAS KILLED
IN THE SANDY
IN THE SANDY HOOK
WHOSE SECURE OLD SON WAS KILLED
IN THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING
IN THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING --
SIX
SIX YEAR
IN THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING --
SIX YEAR OLD
SIX YEAR OLD WAS
IN THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING --
SIX YEAR OLD WAS KILLED
SIX YEAR OLD WAS KILLED IN
IN THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING --
SIX YEAR OLD WAS KILLED IN THE
SANDY
SANDY HOOK
SIX YEAR OLD WAS KILLED IN THE
SANDY HOOK SHOOTING.
>>
>> LATEST
SANDY HOOK SHOOTING.
>> LATEST GENTLEMEN,
>> LATEST GENTLEMEN, PLEASE
WELCOME
WELCOME AARON
>> LATEST GENTLEMEN, PLEASE
WELCOME AARON STEVENS
WELCOME AARON STEVENS CALLING,
AND
AND HILLARY
WELCOME AARON STEVENS CALLING,
AND HILLARY CLINTON.
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> FIRST
[APPLAUSE]
>> FIRST OF
>> FIRST OF ALL,
[APPLAUSE]
>> FIRST OF ALL, I
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WANT
[APPLAUSE]
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
YOU
YOU ALL
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
YOU ALL FOR
YOU ALL FOR YOUR
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
YOU ALL FOR YOUR PATIENCE.
PATIENCE
PATIENCE IS
YOU ALL FOR YOUR PATIENCE.
PATIENCE IS A
PATIENCE IS A VIRTUE.
THANK
THANK YOU
PATIENCE IS A VIRTUE.
THANK YOU VERY
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE
YOU'RE IN
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE IN THE
YOU'RE IN THE 20TH
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE IN THE 20TH SEND
YOU'RE IN THE 20TH SEND IT
DISTRICT
DISTRICT --
YOU'RE IN THE 20TH SEND IT
DISTRICT -- SENATE
DISTRICT -- SENATE DISTRICT.
ALWAYS
ALWAYS THINK
DISTRICT -- SENATE DISTRICT.
ALWAYS THINK OF
ALWAYS THINK OF LUDA
DISTRICT -- SENATE DISTRICT.
ALWAYS THINK OF LUDA LISANDRO.
WE
WE ARE
ALWAYS THINK OF LUDA LISANDRO.
WE ARE HERE
WE ARE HERE TODAY
ALWAYS THINK OF LUDA LISANDRO.
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO LISTEN
ALWAYS THINK OF LUDA LISANDRO.
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO LISTEN TO
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO LISTEN TO A
WOMAN
WOMAN WHO
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO LISTEN TO A
WOMAN WHO HAS
WOMAN WHO HAS EVERY
WE ARE HERE TODAY TO LISTEN TO A
WOMAN WHO HAS EVERY CREDENTIAL
POSSIBLE
POSSIBLE TO
WOMAN WHO HAS EVERY CREDENTIAL
POSSIBLE TO LEAD
POSSIBLE TO LEAD THIS
WOMAN WHO HAS EVERY CREDENTIAL
POSSIBLE TO LEAD THIS COUNTRY
POSSIBLE TO LEAD THIS COUNTRY AS
WE
WE MOVE
POSSIBLE TO LEAD THIS COUNTRY AS
WE MOVE FORWARD.
[CHEERING]
WE
WE HAVE
[CHEERING]
WE HAVE A
WE HAVE A WOMAN
[CHEERING]
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO IS
[CHEERING]
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO IS NOT
AFRAID
AFRAID TO
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO IS NOT
AFRAID TO TALK
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO IS NOT
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT GUNS.
SHE
SHE IS
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT GUNS.
SHE IS NOT
SHE IS NOT AFRAID
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT GUNS.
SHE IS NOT AFRAID TO
SHE IS NOT AFRAID TO ADDRESS
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT GUNS.
SHE IS NOT AFRAID TO ADDRESS THE
ISSUE
ISSUE HAD
SHE IS NOT AFRAID TO ADDRESS THE
ISSUE HAD ON
ISSUE HAD ON --
SHE IS NOT AFRAID TO ADDRESS THE
ISSUE HAD ON -- HEAD
ISSUE HAD ON -- HEAD ON.
YOU
YOU ARE
ISSUE HAD ON -- HEAD ON.
YOU ARE IN
YOU ARE IN A
ISSUE HAD ON -- HEAD ON.
YOU ARE IN A COMMUNITY
YOU ARE IN A COMMUNITY COLLEGE
TODAY,
TODAY, WE
YOU ARE IN A COMMUNITY COLLEGE
TODAY, WE KNOW
TODAY, WE KNOW WHAT
YOU ARE IN A COMMUNITY COLLEGE
TODAY, WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY, WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO
THE
THE COMMUNITY
TODAY, WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO
THE COMMUNITY COLLEGE
THE COMMUNITY COLLEGE IN
TODAY, WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO
THE COMMUNITY COLLEGE IN OREGON.
WE
WE KNOW,
THE COMMUNITY COLLEGE IN OREGON.
WE KNOW, WITH
WE KNOW, WITH GREAT
THE COMMUNITY COLLEGE IN OREGON.
WE KNOW, WITH GREAT SADNESS,
THAT
THAT THOSE
WE KNOW, WITH GREAT SADNESS,
THAT THOSE WHO
THAT THOSE WHO PASSED
WE KNOW, WITH GREAT SADNESS,
THAT THOSE WHO PASSED AWAY
PASSED
PASSED AWAY
THAT THOSE WHO PASSED AWAY
PASSED AWAY FOR
PASSED AWAY FOR NO
THAT THOSE WHO PASSED AWAY
PASSED AWAY FOR NO REASON
PASSED AWAY FOR NO REASON AT
ALL.
NONE
NONE WHATSOEVER.
WE
WE HAVE
NONE WHATSOEVER.
WE HAVE A
WE HAVE A WOMAN
NONE WHATSOEVER.
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO HAS
NONE WHATSOEVER.
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO HAS WITHIN
HERSELF
HERSELF THE
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO HAS WITHIN
HERSELF THE ABILITY
HERSELF THE ABILITY TO
WE HAVE A WOMAN WHO HAS WITHIN
HERSELF THE ABILITY TO MAKE
HERSELF THE ABILITY TO MAKE A
DIFFERENCE.
[APPLAUSE]
YOU
YOU WILL
[APPLAUSE]
YOU WILL HAVE
YOU WILL HAVE AN
[APPLAUSE]
YOU WILL HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY
YOU WILL HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO
VOTE
VOTE FOR
YOU WILL HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO
VOTE FOR HER
VOTE FOR HER IN
YOU WILL HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO
VOTE FOR HER IN THE
VOTE FOR HER IN THE NEW
HAMPSHIRE
HAMPSHIRE PRIMARY
VOTE FOR HER IN THE NEW
HAMPSHIRE PRIMARY AND
HAMPSHIRE PRIMARY AND THE
GENERAL
GENERAL ELECTION.
[APPLAUSE]
WITHOUT
WITHOUT FURTHER
[APPLAUSE]
WITHOUT FURTHER ADO,
WITHOUT FURTHER ADO, I
[APPLAUSE]
WITHOUT FURTHER ADO, I WILL
INTRODUCE
INTRODUCE AARON
WITHOUT FURTHER ADO, I WILL
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN WHO
WITHOUT FURTHER ADO, I WILL
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN WHO IS
THE
THE WOMAN
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN WHO IS
THE WOMAN FROM
THE WOMAN FROM THE
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN WHO IS
THE WOMAN FROM THE NORTH
THE WOMAN FROM THE NORTH AND
INTRODUCE AARON CURRAN WHO IS
THE WOMAN FROM THE NORTH AND --
SHE
SHE HAS
THE WOMAN FROM THE NORTH AND --
SHE HAS THOSE
SHE HAS THOSE TWO
THE WOMAN FROM THE NORTH AND --
SHE HAS THOSE TWO CHILDREN,
SOCIOLOGY
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR,
SHE HAS THOSE TWO CHILDREN,
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR, SOCIAL
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR, SOCIAL WORKER,
SAID
SAID IT
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR, SOCIAL WORKER,
SAID IT DID
SAID IT DID NOT
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR, SOCIAL WORKER,
SAID IT DID NOT PAY
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A
SOCIOLOGY MAJOR, SOCIAL WORKER,
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A LOT
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A LOT OF
WORKER
WORKER --
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A LOT OF
WORKER -- A
WORKER -- A LOT
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A LOT OF
WORKER -- A LOT OF
WORKER -- A LOT OF MONEY
SAID IT DID NOT PAY A LOT OF
WORKER -- A LOT OF MONEY BUT
WORKER -- A LOT OF MONEY BUT SHE
LOVES
LOVES IT
WORKER -- A LOT OF MONEY BUT SHE
LOVES IT BECAUSE
LOVES IT BECAUSE SHE
WORKER -- A LOT OF MONEY BUT SHE
LOVES IT BECAUSE SHE WAS
LOVES IT BECAUSE SHE WAS TAKING
CARE
CARE OF
LOVES IT BECAUSE SHE WAS TAKING
CARE OF PEOPLE.
ISN'T
ISN'T THAT
CARE OF PEOPLE.
ISN'T THAT WHAT
ISN'T THAT WHAT LIFE
CARE OF PEOPLE.
ISN'T THAT WHAT LIFE IS
ISN'T THAT WHAT LIFE IS ALL
ABOUT?
WE
WE HESITATE
ABOUT?
WE HESITATE ZERO
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE
ABOUT?
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE --
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE -- WE
HAVE
HAVE TO
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE -- WE
HAVE TO TAKE
HAVE TO TAKE CARE
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE -- WE
HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF
HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE
WE HESITATE ZERO PEOPLE -- WE
HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE IN
THE
THE COUNTRY
HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE IN
THE COUNTRY IS
THE COUNTRY IS BETTER
HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE IN
THE COUNTRY IS BETTER OFF
BECAUSE
BECAUSE OF
THE COUNTRY IS BETTER OFF
BECAUSE OF THAT.
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> HELLO.
I
I WILL
>> HELLO.
I WILL HAVE
I WILL HAVE TO
>> HELLO.
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT A
>> HELLO.
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT A LITTLE
BIT
BIT WITH
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT A LITTLE
BIT WITH MY
BIT WITH MY PAPER,
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT A LITTLE
BIT WITH MY PAPER, I
BIT WITH MY PAPER, I AM
I WILL HAVE TO CHEAT A LITTLE
BIT WITH MY PAPER, I AM NOT
BIT WITH MY PAPER, I AM NOT AS
WELL
WELL PRACTICED.
I
I AM
WELL PRACTICED.
I AM THE
I AM THE MOTHER
WELL PRACTICED.
I AM THE MOTHER OF
I AM THE MOTHER OF TWO
WELL PRACTICED.
I AM THE MOTHER OF TWO CHILDREN
AND
AND I
I AM THE MOTHER OF TWO CHILDREN
AND I HAVE
AND I HAVE THE
I AM THE MOTHER OF TWO CHILDREN
AND I HAVE THE HONOR
AND I HAVE THE HONOR OF
INTRODUCING
INTRODUCING HILLARY
AND I HAVE THE HONOR OF
INTRODUCING HILLARY CLINTON
TODAY.
I
I LIVE
TODAY.
I LIVE IN
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER
TODAY.
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER AND
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER AND MY
TODAY.
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER AND MY HOME
IS
IS ABOUT
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER AND MY HOME
IS ABOUT THREE
IS ABOUT THREE MILES
I LIVE IN MANCHESTER AND MY HOME
IS ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY.
IT'S
IT'S A
IS ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY
IS ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY AND
IN
IN ANOTHER
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY AND
IN ANOTHER TIME,
IN ANOTHER TIME, WE
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY AND
IN ANOTHER TIME, WE COULD
IN ANOTHER TIME, WE COULD HAVE
POSED
POSED IN
IN ANOTHER TIME, WE COULD HAVE
POSED IN A
POSED IN A NORMAN
IN ANOTHER TIME, WE COULD HAVE
POSED IN A NORMAN ROCKWELL
PAINTING.
TO
TO ME,
PAINTING.
TO ME, THE
TO ME, THE DEVASTATING
CONSEQUENCES
CONSEQUENCES OF
TO ME, THE DEVASTATING
CONSEQUENCES OF GUN
CONSEQUENCES OF GUN VIOLENCE
HAVE
HAVE ALWAYS
CONSEQUENCES OF GUN VIOLENCE
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A
CONSEQUENCES OF GUN VIOLENCE
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A CONCERN.
WHAT
WHAT DEALS
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A CONCERN.
WHAT DEALS LIKE
WHAT DEALS LIKE A
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A CONCERN.
WHAT DEALS LIKE A PAST
WHAT DEALS LIKE A PAST LIFE,
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN A CONCERN.
WHAT DEALS LIKE A PAST LIFE, I
WAS
WAS A
WHAT DEALS LIKE A PAST LIFE, I
WAS A SOCIAL
WAS A SOCIAL WORKER
WHAT DEALS LIKE A PAST LIFE, I
WAS A SOCIAL WORKER AND
WAS A SOCIAL WORKER AND I
HANDLED
HANDLED MOSTLY
WAS A SOCIAL WORKER AND I
HANDLED MOSTLY DOMESTIC
HANDLED MOSTLY DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
AND
AND SEXUAL
HANDLED MOSTLY DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
AND SEXUAL ASSAULT
AND SEXUAL ASSAULT CASES.
WHAT
WHAT STRESSED
AND SEXUAL ASSAULT CASES.
WHAT STRESSED ME
WHAT STRESSED ME OVER
AND SEXUAL ASSAULT CASES.
WHAT STRESSED ME OVER AND
WHAT STRESSED ME OVER AND OVER
WAS
WAS THE
WHAT STRESSED ME OVER AND OVER
WAS THE IMMEDIACY
WAS THE IMMEDIACY OF
WHAT STRESSED ME OVER AND OVER
WAS THE IMMEDIACY OF GUN
VIOLENCE.
WHEN
WHEN GUNS
VIOLENCE.
WHEN GUNS ENTER
WHEN GUNS ENTER A
VIOLENCE.
WHEN GUNS ENTER A CONFLICT,
THERE
THERE IS
WHEN GUNS ENTER A CONFLICT,
THERE IS NO
THERE IS NO CHANCE
WHEN GUNS ENTER A CONFLICT,
THERE IS NO CHANCE TO
RECONSIDER,
RECONSIDER, IT
THERE IS NO CHANCE TO
RECONSIDER, IT IS
RECONSIDER, IT IS JUST
THERE IS NO CHANCE TO
RECONSIDER, IT IS JUST OVER.
WATCHING
WATCHING THE
RECONSIDER, IT IS JUST OVER.
WATCHING THE ASSAULT
WATCHING THE ASSAULT WEAPON
BRENT
BRENT --
WATCHING THE ASSAULT WEAPON
BRENT -- BAND
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE
WATCHING THE ASSAULT WEAPON
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE IN
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE IN 2004,
WATCHING THE ASSAULT WEAPON
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE IN 2004, I
COULD
COULD NOT
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE IN 2004, I
COULD NOT UNDERSTAND
COULD NOT UNDERSTAND WHY
BRENT -- BAND EXPIRE IN 2004, I
COULD NOT UNDERSTAND WHY WE
COULD
COULD NOT
COULD NOT UNDERSTAND WHY WE
COULD NOT MAKE
COULD NOT MAKE PROGRESS
COULD NOT UNDERSTAND WHY WE
COULD NOT MAKE PROGRESS OR
COULD NOT MAKE PROGRESS OR AN
ACT
ACT POLICIES
COULD NOT MAKE PROGRESS OR AN
ACT POLICIES TO
ACT POLICIES TO PREVENT
COULD NOT MAKE PROGRESS OR AN
ACT POLICIES TO PREVENT GUN
VIOLENCE
VIOLENCE AND
ACT POLICIES TO PREVENT GUN
VIOLENCE AND DEATH
VIOLENCE AND DEATH FROM
ACT POLICIES TO PREVENT GUN
VIOLENCE AND DEATH FROM GUNS.
LAST
LAST MONTH,
VIOLENCE AND DEATH FROM GUNS.
LAST MONTH, EVERYTHING
LAST MONTH, EVERYTHING CHANGED
FOR
FOR OUR
LAST MONTH, EVERYTHING CHANGED
FOR OUR FAMILY.
A
A WOMAN
FOR OUR FAMILY.
A WOMAN NOT
A WOMAN NOT SO
FOR OUR FAMILY.
A WOMAN NOT SO DIFFERENT
A WOMAN NOT SO DIFFERENT FROM
MYSELF
MYSELF OR
A WOMAN NOT SO DIFFERENT FROM
MYSELF OR ANYONE
MYSELF OR ANYONE ELSE
A WOMAN NOT SO DIFFERENT FROM
MYSELF OR ANYONE ELSE IN
MYSELF OR ANYONE ELSE IN OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD
NEIGHBORHOOD WAS
MYSELF OR ANYONE ELSE IN OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD WAS SHOT
NEIGHBORHOOD WAS SHOT AND
MYSELF OR ANYONE ELSE IN OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD WAS SHOT AND KILLED
ON
ON MY
NEIGHBORHOOD WAS SHOT AND KILLED
ON MY STREET.
IT
IT WAS
ON MY STREET.
IT WAS A
IT WAS A SUNDAY
ON MY STREET.
IT WAS A SUNDAY EVENING
IT WAS A SUNDAY EVENING AND
THERE
THERE IS
IT WAS A SUNDAY EVENING AND
THERE IS NO
THERE IS NO INFORMATION.
MY
MY FIRST
THERE IS NO INFORMATION.
MY FIRST THOUGHT
MY FIRST THOUGHT WHEN
THERE IS NO INFORMATION.
MY FIRST THOUGHT WHEN TO
MY FIRST THOUGHT WHEN TO MY
KIDS.
THOMAS
THOMAS WHO
KIDS.
THOMAS WHO IS
THOMAS WHO IS TOO
KIDS.
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY TO
KIDS.
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY TO BE
HERE
HERE TODAY
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY TO BE
HERE TODAY IS
HERE TODAY IS IN
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY TO BE
HERE TODAY IS IN FIRST
HERE TODAY IS IN FIRST GRADE
THOMAS WHO IS TOO WIGGLY TO BE
HERE TODAY IS IN FIRST GRADE AND
ELEANOR
ELEANOR IS
HERE TODAY IS IN FIRST GRADE AND
ELEANOR IS IN
ELEANOR IS IN --
THE
THE NIGHT
ELEANOR IS IN --
THE NIGHT BEFORE
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE
ELEANOR IS IN --
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE SHOOTING,
OUR
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE SHOOTING,
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD HAD
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD HAD A
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE SHOOTING,
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD HAD A COOKOUT
FOR
FOR EVERYONE
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD HAD A COOKOUT
FOR EVERYONE ON
FOR EVERYONE ON THE
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD HAD A COOKOUT
FOR EVERYONE ON THE STREET
FOR EVERYONE ON THE STREET AND
THE
THE KIDS
FOR EVERYONE ON THE STREET AND
THE KIDS WERE
THE KIDS WERE RUNNING
FOR EVERYONE ON THE STREET AND
THE KIDS WERE RUNNING AROUND
THE KIDS WERE RUNNING AROUND THE
NEIGHBORHOOD
NEIGHBORHOOD PLAYING
THE KIDS WERE RUNNING AROUND THE
NEIGHBORHOOD PLAYING HIDE
NEIGHBORHOOD PLAYING HIDE AND
SEEK
SEEK INTO
NEIGHBORHOOD PLAYING HIDE AND
SEEK INTO THE
SEEK INTO THE NIGHT.
WHAT
WHAT A
SEEK INTO THE NIGHT.
WHAT A DIFFERENCE
WHAT A DIFFERENCE 24
SEEK INTO THE NIGHT.
WHAT A DIFFERENCE 24 HOURS
WHAT A DIFFERENCE 24 HOURS MIGHT
HAVE
HAVE MADE.
IF
IF YOU
HAVE MADE.
IF YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE A
HAVE MADE.
IF YOU ARE A PARENT,
IF YOU ARE A PARENT, GUN
VIOLENCE
VIOLENCE PREVENTION
IF YOU ARE A PARENT, GUN
VIOLENCE PREVENTION HAS
VIOLENCE PREVENTION HAS TO
IF YOU ARE A PARENT, GUN
VIOLENCE PREVENTION HAS TO BE
VIOLENCE PREVENTION HAS TO BE AN
ISSUE
ISSUE FOR
VIOLENCE PREVENTION HAS TO BE AN
ISSUE FOR YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
IF
IF YOU
[APPLAUSE]
IF YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE A
[APPLAUSE]
IF YOU ARE A HUSBAND,
IF YOU ARE A HUSBAND, A
[APPLAUSE]
IF YOU ARE A HUSBAND, A BROTHER,
A
A SISTER,
IF YOU ARE A HUSBAND, A BROTHER,
A SISTER, A
A SISTER, A WIFE,
IF YOU ARE A HUSBAND, A BROTHER,
A SISTER, A WIFE, GUN
A SISTER, A WIFE, GUN VIOLENCE
PREVENTION
PREVENTION HAS
A SISTER, A WIFE, GUN VIOLENCE
PREVENTION HAS TO
PREVENTION HAS TO BE
A SISTER, A WIFE, GUN VIOLENCE
PREVENTION HAS TO BE AN
PREVENTION HAS TO BE AN ISSUE
FOR
FOR YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
FROM
FROM OREGON
[APPLAUSE]
FROM OREGON TO
FROM OREGON TO SOUTH
[APPLAUSE]
FROM OREGON TO SOUTH CAROLINA
AND
AND EVERYWHERE
FROM OREGON TO SOUTH CAROLINA
AND EVERYWHERE IN
AND EVERYWHERE IN BETWEEN,
FROM OREGON TO SOUTH CAROLINA
AND EVERYWHERE IN BETWEEN, GUN
VIOLENCE
VIOLENCE IS
AND EVERYWHERE IN BETWEEN, GUN
VIOLENCE IS LEAVING
VIOLENCE IS LEAVING FAMILIES
STRUGGLING
STRUGGLING WITH
VIOLENCE IS LEAVING FAMILIES
STRUGGLING WITH UNIMAGINABLE
GRIEF
GRIEF AND
STRUGGLING WITH UNIMAGINABLE
GRIEF AND LOSS.
AS
AS A
GRIEF AND LOSS.
AS A NATION,
AS A NATION, WE
GRIEF AND LOSS.
AS A NATION, WE CAN
AS A NATION, WE CAN DO
GRIEF AND LOSS.
AS A NATION, WE CAN DO BETTER.
IF
IF WE
AS A NATION, WE CAN DO BETTER.
IF WE ELECT
IF WE ELECT THE
AS A NATION, WE CAN DO BETTER.
IF WE ELECT THE RIGHT
IF WE ELECT THE RIGHT PERSON,
THIS
THIS IS
IF WE ELECT THE RIGHT PERSON,
THIS IS A
THIS IS A FIGHT
IF WE ELECT THE RIGHT PERSON,
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT WE
IF WE ELECT THE RIGHT PERSON,
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT WE CAN
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT WE CAN WIN.
I
I THINK
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT WE CAN WIN.
I THINK HILLARY
I THINK HILLARY CLINTON
THIS IS A FIGHT THAT WE CAN WIN.
I THINK HILLARY CLINTON IS
I THINK HILLARY CLINTON IS THE
PERSON
PERSON WHO
I THINK HILLARY CLINTON IS THE
PERSON WHO CAN
PERSON WHO CAN WIN
I THINK HILLARY CLINTON IS THE
PERSON WHO CAN WIN THAT
PERSON WHO CAN WIN THAT FIGHT
FOR
FOR US.
[APPLAUSE]
SHE
SHE HAS
[APPLAUSE]
SHE HAS THE
SHE HAS THE TENACITY
[APPLAUSE]
SHE HAS THE TENACITY TO
SHE HAS THE TENACITY TO TACKLE
GUN
GUN VIOLENCE
SHE HAS THE TENACITY TO TACKLE
GUN VIOLENCE AND
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE
SHE HAS THE TENACITY TO TACKLE
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE NEVER
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE NEVER GIVES
UP
UP AND
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE NEVER GIVES
UP AND SHE
UP AND SHE HAS
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE NEVER GIVES
UP AND SHE HAS A
UP AND SHE HAS A RECORD
GUN VIOLENCE AND SHE NEVER GIVES
UP AND SHE HAS A RECORD OF
ACHIEVING
ACHIEVING RESULTS.
PLEASE
PLEASE JOIN
ACHIEVING RESULTS.
PLEASE JOIN ME
PLEASE JOIN ME IN
ACHIEVING RESULTS.
PLEASE JOIN ME IN THIS
PLEASE JOIN ME IN THIS FIGHT
ACHIEVING RESULTS.
PLEASE JOIN ME IN THIS FIGHT AND
JOIN
JOIN ME
PLEASE JOIN ME IN THIS FIGHT AND
JOIN ME IN
JOIN ME IN WELCOMING
PLEASE JOIN ME IN THIS FIGHT AND
JOIN ME IN WELCOMING OUR
JOIN ME IN WELCOMING OUR NEXT
PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT, HILLARY
JOIN ME IN WELCOMING OUR NEXT
PRESIDENT, HILLARY CLINTON.
[APPLAUSE
[APPLAUSE AND
PRESIDENT, HILLARY CLINTON.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU,
THANK
THANK YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU,
THANK YOU VERY
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M
I'M DELIGHTED
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M DELIGHTED AND
I'M DELIGHTED AND HONORED
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M DELIGHTED AND HONORED TO
I'M DELIGHTED AND HONORED TO BE
HERE.
LUDA
LUDA LISANDRO
HERE.
LUDA LISANDRO HAS
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN
HERE.
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN A
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN A FRIEND
OF
OF MINE
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN A FRIEND
OF MINE FOR
OF MINE FOR A
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN A FRIEND
OF MINE FOR A LONG
OF MINE FOR A LONG TIME,
LUDA LISANDRO HAS BEEN A FRIEND
OF MINE FOR A LONG TIME, AND
OF MINE FOR A LONG TIME, AND A
SENATOR
SENATOR REPRESENTING
OF MINE FOR A LONG TIME, AND A
SENATOR REPRESENTING THIS
DISTRICT.
I
I THANK
DISTRICT.
I THANK HIM
I THANK HIM VERY
DISTRICT.
I THANK HIM VERY MUCH
I THANK HIM VERY MUCH FOR
DISTRICT.
I THANK HIM VERY MUCH FOR HIS
SUPPORT
SUPPORT AND
I THANK HIM VERY MUCH FOR HIS
SUPPORT AND HIS
SUPPORT AND HIS FRIENDSHIP.
I
I WANT
SUPPORT AND HIS FRIENDSHIP.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO THANK
SUPPORT AND HIS FRIENDSHIP.
I WANT TO THANK ERIN
I WANT TO THANK ERIN AND
SUPPORT AND HIS FRIENDSHIP.
I WANT TO THANK ERIN AND ELEANOR
FOR
FOR BEING
I WANT TO THANK ERIN AND ELEANOR
FOR BEING WITH
FOR BEING WITH US.
ERIN'S
ERIN'S STORY
FOR BEING WITH US.
ERIN'S STORY IS
ERIN'S STORY IS UNFORTUNATELY
WAY
WAY TOO
ERIN'S STORY IS UNFORTUNATELY
WAY TOO COMMON.
WE
WE ARE
WAY TOO COMMON.
WE ARE HERE
WE ARE HERE ON
WAY TOO COMMON.
WE ARE HERE ON THE
WE ARE HERE ON THE CAMPUS
WAY TOO COMMON.
WE ARE HERE ON THE CAMPUS OF
WE ARE HERE ON THE CAMPUS OF A
WONDERFUL
WONDERFUL COMMUNITY
WE ARE HERE ON THE CAMPUS OF A
WONDERFUL COMMUNITY COLLEGE,
VERY
VERY MUCH
WONDERFUL COMMUNITY COLLEGE,
VERY MUCH LIKE
VERY MUCH LIKE THE
WONDERFUL COMMUNITY COLLEGE,
VERY MUCH LIKE THE ONE
VERY MUCH LIKE THE ONE IN
OREGON.
WHERE
WHERE YOUNG
OREGON.
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE WERE
OREGON.
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE WERE GOING
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE WERE GOING TO
SCHOOL,
SCHOOL, AND
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE WERE GOING TO
SCHOOL, AND SOME
SCHOOL, AND SOME NOT
WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE WERE GOING TO
SCHOOL, AND SOME NOT SO
SCHOOL, AND SOME NOT SO YOUNG.
THE
THE VICTIMS
SCHOOL, AND SOME NOT SO YOUNG.
THE VICTIMS I
THE VICTIMS I READ
SCHOOL, AND SOME NOT SO YOUNG.
THE VICTIMS I READ ARE
THE VICTIMS I READ ARE BETWEEN
18 YEARS
18 YEARS OLD
THE VICTIMS I READ ARE BETWEEN
18 YEARS OLD AND
18 YEARS OLD AND 67
THE VICTIMS I READ ARE BETWEEN
18 YEARS OLD AND 67 YEARS
18 YEARS OLD AND 67 YEARS OLD.
PEOPLE
PEOPLE ATTENDING
18 YEARS OLD AND 67 YEARS OLD.
PEOPLE ATTENDING CLASSES
PEOPLE ATTENDING CLASSES AND
IMPROVING
IMPROVING THEIR
PEOPLE ATTENDING CLASSES AND
IMPROVING THEIR SKILLS,
TEACHING,
TEACHING, LEARNING,
IMPROVING THEIR SKILLS,
TEACHING, LEARNING, THINKING
ABOUT
ABOUT THE
TEACHING, LEARNING, THINKING
ABOUT THE FUTURE.
WHICH
WHICH WAS
ABOUT THE FUTURE.
WHICH WAS SO
WHICH WAS SO ENDED,
ABOUT THE FUTURE.
WHICH WAS SO ENDED, SENSELESSLY,
TRAGICALLY.
ON
ON THAT
TRAGICALLY.
ON THAT VERY
ON THAT VERY SAME
TRAGICALLY.
ON THAT VERY SAME DAY
ON THAT VERY SAME DAY THAT
TRAGICALLY.
ON THAT VERY SAME DAY THAT THOSE
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WERE
ON THAT VERY SAME DAY THAT THOSE
PEOPLE WERE KILLED
PEOPLE WERE KILLED IN
ON THAT VERY SAME DAY THAT THOSE
PEOPLE WERE KILLED IN OREGON,
PEOPLE WERE KILLED IN OREGON, A
FIVE-MONTH-OLD
FIVE-MONTH-OLD BABY
PEOPLE WERE KILLED IN OREGON, A
FIVE-MONTH-OLD BABY STRAPPED
INTO
INTO HER
FIVE-MONTH-OLD BABY STRAPPED
INTO HER CAR
INTO HER CAR SEAT
FIVE-MONTH-OLD BABY STRAPPED
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE
FIVE-MONTH-OLD BABY STRAPPED
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE BACK
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE BACK OF
A
A CAR
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE BACK OF
A CAR WAS
A CAR WAS KILLED
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE BACK OF
A CAR WAS KILLED BY
A CAR WAS KILLED BY A
INTO HER CAR SEAT IN THE BACK OF
A CAR WAS KILLED BY A STRAY
BULLET
BULLET IN
A CAR WAS KILLED BY A STRAY
BULLET IN CLEVELAND.
THE
THE THIRD
BULLET IN CLEVELAND.
THE THIRD BABY
THE THIRD BABY IN
BULLET IN CLEVELAND.
THE THIRD BABY IN JUST
THE THIRD BABY IN JUST A
BULLET IN CLEVELAND.
THE THIRD BABY IN JUST A FEW
MONTHS
MONTHS TO
THE THIRD BABY IN JUST A FEW
MONTHS TO BE
MONTHS TO BE MURDERED
THE THIRD BABY IN JUST A FEW
MONTHS TO BE MURDERED IN
CLEVELAND.
BETWEEN
BETWEEN 88
CLEVELAND.
BETWEEN 88 AND
BETWEEN 88 AND 92
CLEVELAND.
BETWEEN 88 AND 92 PEOPLE
BETWEEN 88 AND 92 PEOPLE A
CLEVELAND.
BETWEEN 88 AND 92 PEOPLE A DAY
ARE
ARE KILLED
BETWEEN 88 AND 92 PEOPLE A DAY
ARE KILLED BY
ARE KILLED BY GUNS
BETWEEN 88 AND 92 PEOPLE A DAY
ARE KILLED BY GUNS IN
ARE KILLED BY GUNS IN AMERICA.
THE
THE LAST
ARE KILLED BY GUNS IN AMERICA.
THE LAST FIGURES
THE LAST FIGURES WE
ARE KILLED BY GUNS IN AMERICA.
THE LAST FIGURES WE HAVE
THE LAST FIGURES WE HAVE FOR
ARE KILLED BY GUNS IN AMERICA.
THE LAST FIGURES WE HAVE FOR A
WHOLE
WHOLE YEAR
THE LAST FIGURES WE HAVE FOR A
WHOLE YEAR IS
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE
THE LAST FIGURES WE HAVE FOR A
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE THAN
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE THAN 33,000.
IT
IT IS
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE THAN 33,000.
IT IS THE
IT IS THE LEADING
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE THAN 33,000.
IT IS THE LEADING CAUSE
IT IS THE LEADING CAUSE OF
WHOLE YEAR IS MORE THAN 33,000.
IT IS THE LEADING CAUSE OF DEATH
FOR
FOR YOUNG
IT IS THE LEADING CAUSE OF DEATH
FOR YOUNG AFRICAN-AMERICAN
FOR YOUNG AFRICAN-AMERICAN MEN,
THE
THE SECOND
FOR YOUNG AFRICAN-AMERICAN MEN,
THE SECOND LEADING
THE SECOND LEADING CAUSE
FOR YOUNG AFRICAN-AMERICAN MEN,
THE SECOND LEADING CAUSE FOR
YOUNG
YOUNG HISPANIC
THE SECOND LEADING CAUSE FOR
YOUNG HISPANIC MEN,
YOUNG HISPANIC MEN, THE
THE SECOND LEADING CAUSE FOR
YOUNG HISPANIC MEN, THE FOURTH
LEADING
LEADING CAUSE
YOUNG HISPANIC MEN, THE FOURTH
LEADING CAUSE FOR
LEADING CAUSE FOR YOUNG
YOUNG HISPANIC MEN, THE FOURTH
LEADING CAUSE FOR YOUNG WHITE
MEN.
THIS
THIS EPIDEMIC
MEN.
THIS EPIDEMIC OF
THIS EPIDEMIC OF GUN
MEN.
THIS EPIDEMIC OF GUN VIOLENCE
KNOWS
KNOWS NO
THIS EPIDEMIC OF GUN VIOLENCE
KNOWS NO BOUNDARIES.
IT
IT KNOWS
KNOWS NO BOUNDARIES.
IT KNOWS NO
IT KNOWS NO LIMITS.
AND
AND WHEN
IT KNOWS NO LIMITS.
AND WHEN THIS
AND WHEN THIS HAPPENS,
IT KNOWS NO LIMITS.
AND WHEN THIS HAPPENS, PEOPLE
ARE
ARE QUICK
AND WHEN THIS HAPPENS, PEOPLE
ARE QUICK TO
ARE QUICK TO SAY
AND WHEN THIS HAPPENS, PEOPLE
ARE QUICK TO SAY THAT
ARE QUICK TO SAY THAT THEY
AND WHEN THIS HAPPENS, PEOPLE
ARE QUICK TO SAY THAT THEY OFFER
THEIR
THEIR THOUGHTS
ARE QUICK TO SAY THAT THEY OFFER
THEIR THOUGHTS AND
THEIR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS.
THAT
THAT IS
THEIR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS.
THAT IS NOT
THAT IS NOT ENOUGH.
HOW
HOW MANY
THAT IS NOT ENOUGH.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
HOW MANY PEOPLE HAVE
THAT IS NOT ENOUGH.
HOW MANY PEOPLE HAVE TO
HOW MANY PEOPLE HAVE TO DIE
BEFORE
BEFORE WE
HOW MANY PEOPLE HAVE TO DIE
BEFORE WE ACTUALLY
BEFORE WE ACTUALLY ACT?
BEFORE
BEFORE WE
BEFORE WE ACTUALLY ACT?
BEFORE WE COME
BEFORE WE COME TOGETHER
BEFORE WE ACTUALLY ACT?
BEFORE WE COME TOGETHER AS
BEFORE WE COME TOGETHER AS A
NATION.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW,
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, ON
THE
THE REPUBLICAN
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, ON
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE,
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE, MR.
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, ON
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE, MR. TRUMP
WAS
WAS ASKED
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE, MR. TRUMP
WAS ASKED ABOUT
WAS ASKED ABOUT IT
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE, MR. TRUMP
WAS ASKED ABOUT IT AND
WAS ASKED ABOUT IT AND SAID
SOMETHING
SOMETHING LIKE
WAS ASKED ABOUT IT AND SAID
SOMETHING LIKE YOU
SOMETHING LIKE YOU KNOW,
WAS ASKED ABOUT IT AND SAID
SOMETHING LIKE YOU KNOW, THINGS
LIKE
LIKE THAT
SOMETHING LIKE YOU KNOW, THINGS
LIKE THAT HAPPEN
LIKE THAT HAPPEN IN
SOMETHING LIKE YOU KNOW, THINGS
LIKE THAT HAPPEN IN THE
LIKE THAT HAPPEN IN THE WORLD.
GOVERNOR
GOVERNOR BUSH
LIKE THAT HAPPEN IN THE WORLD.
GOVERNOR BUSH SAID
GOVERNOR BUSH SAID YEAH,
LIKE THAT HAPPEN IN THE WORLD.
GOVERNOR BUSH SAID YEAH, STUFF
HAPPENS.
NO.
THAT
THAT IS
NO.
THAT IS AN
THAT IS AN ADMISSION
NO.
THAT IS AN ADMISSION OF
THAT IS AN ADMISSION OF DEFEAT
AND
AND SURRENDER.
TO
TO A
AND SURRENDER.
TO A PROBLEM
TO A PROBLEM THAT
AND SURRENDER.
TO A PROBLEM THAT IS
TO A PROBLEM THAT IS KILLING
33,000
33,000 AMERICANS.
IT
IT IS
33,000 AMERICANS.
IT IS TIME
IT IS TIME FOR
33,000 AMERICANS.
IT IS TIME FOR US
IT IS TIME FOR US TO
33,000 AMERICANS.
IT IS TIME FOR US TO SAY
IT IS TIME FOR US TO SAY WAIT
33,000 AMERICANS.
IT IS TIME FOR US TO SAY WAIT A
MINUTE,
MINUTE, WE
IT IS TIME FOR US TO SAY WAIT A
MINUTE, WE ARE
MINUTE, WE ARE BETTER
IT IS TIME FOR US TO SAY WAIT A
MINUTE, WE ARE BETTER THAN
MINUTE, WE ARE BETTER THAN THIS.
OUR
OUR COUNTRY
MINUTE, WE ARE BETTER THAN THIS.
OUR COUNTRY IS
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER
MINUTE, WE ARE BETTER THAN THIS.
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER THAN
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER THAN THIS.
AND
AND THERE
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER THAN THIS.
AND THERE ARE
AND THERE ARE STEPS
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER THAN THIS.
AND THERE ARE STEPS WE
AND THERE ARE STEPS WE CAN
OUR COUNTRY IS BETTER THAN THIS.
AND THERE ARE STEPS WE CAN TAKE
--
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT IMPROVE
GUN
GUN SAFETY
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT IMPROVE
GUN SAFETY AND
GUN SAFETY AND FURTHER
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT IMPROVE
GUN SAFETY AND FURTHER THE
PREVENTION
PREVENTION OF
GUN SAFETY AND FURTHER THE
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE BY
GUN SAFETY AND FURTHER THE
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE BY GUNS.
AND
AND TODAY,
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE BY GUNS.
AND TODAY, IM
AND TODAY, IM --
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE BY GUNS.
AND TODAY, IM -- I
AND TODAY, IM -- I AM
PREVENTION OF VIOLENCE BY GUNS.
AND TODAY, IM -- I AM PROPOSING
WHAT
WHAT I
AND TODAY, IM -- I AM PROPOSING
WHAT I CONSIDER
WHAT I CONSIDER TO
AND TODAY, IM -- I AM PROPOSING
WHAT I CONSIDER TO BE
WHAT I CONSIDER TO BE COMMON
SENSE
SENSE APPROACHES.
A
A MAJORITY
SENSE APPROACHES.
A MAJORITY OF
A MAJORITY OF AMERICANS
SENSE APPROACHES.
A MAJORITY OF AMERICANS SUPPORT
UNIVERSAL
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND
A MAJORITY OF AMERICANS SUPPORT
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IN
IN FACT,
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IN FACT, A
IN FACT, A MAJORITY
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IN FACT, A MAJORITY OF
IN FACT, A MAJORITY OF GUN
OWNERS
OWNERS SUPPORT
IN FACT, A MAJORITY OF GUN
OWNERS SUPPORT UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
WE
WE HAD
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
WE HAD A
WE HAD A BIPARTISAN
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
WE HAD A BIPARTISAN BILL
WE HAD A BIPARTISAN BILL THAT
DIDN'T
DIDN'T MAKE
WE HAD A BIPARTISAN BILL THAT
DIDN'T MAKE IT
DIDN'T MAKE IT THROUGH
WE HAD A BIPARTISAN BILL THAT
DIDN'T MAKE IT THROUGH THE
SENATE.
BUT
BUT WE
SENATE.
BUT WE NEED
BUT WE NEED TO
SENATE.
BUT WE NEED TO GO
BUT WE NEED TO GO BACK
SENATE.
BUT WE NEED TO GO BACK AND,
BUT WE NEED TO GO BACK AND, WITH
ALL
ALL OF
BUT WE NEED TO GO BACK AND, WITH
ALL OF OUR
ALL OF OUR HEARTS,
BUT WE NEED TO GO BACK AND, WITH
ALL OF OUR HEARTS, WORKING
ALL OF OUR HEARTS, WORKING NOT
JUST
JUST IN
ALL OF OUR HEARTS, WORKING NOT
JUST IN WASHINGTON,
JUST IN WASHINGTON, BUT
ALL OF OUR HEARTS, WORKING NOT
JUST IN WASHINGTON, BUT FROM
JUST IN WASHINGTON, BUT FROM A
GRASSROOTS
GRASSROOTS UP,
JUST IN WASHINGTON, BUT FROM A
GRASSROOTS UP, DEMAND
GRASSROOTS UP, DEMAND THAT
JUST IN WASHINGTON, BUT FROM A
GRASSROOTS UP, DEMAND THAT WE
HAVE
HAVE UNIVERSAL
GRASSROOTS UP, DEMAND THAT WE
HAVE UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
AND
AND WE
CHECKS.
AND WE HAVE
AND WE HAVE TO
CHECKS.
AND WE HAVE TO ALSO
AND WE HAVE TO ALSO --
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: WE
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE TO
CLOSE
CLOSE THE
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE TO
CLOSE THE LOOPHOLES.
YOU
YOU KNOW,
CLOSE THE LOOPHOLES.
YOU KNOW, WE'VE
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT
CLOSE THE LOOPHOLES.
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT WHAT
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT WHAT IS
CALLED
CALLED THE
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT WHAT IS
CALLED THE GUN
CALLED THE GUN SHOW
YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT WHAT IS
CALLED THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE,
AND
AND WE'VE
CALLED THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE,
AND WE'VE GOT
AND WE'VE GOT WHAT'S
CALLED THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE,
AND WE'VE GOT WHAT'S NOW
AND WE'VE GOT WHAT'S NOW BEING
CALLED
CALLED THE
AND WE'VE GOT WHAT'S NOW BEING
CALLED THE CHARLESTON
CALLED THE CHARLESTON LOOPHOLE.
WHEN
WHEN THE
CALLED THE CHARLESTON LOOPHOLE.
WHEN THE BRADY
WHEN THE BRADY BILL
CALLED THE CHARLESTON LOOPHOLE.
WHEN THE BRADY BILL WAS
WHEN THE BRADY BILL WAS PASSED,
WHICH
WHICH WASN'T
WHEN THE BRADY BILL WAS PASSED,
WHICH WASN'T EASY,
WHICH WASN'T EASY, AS
WHEN THE BRADY BILL WAS PASSED,
WHICH WASN'T EASY, AS YOU
RECALL,
RECALL, BUT
WHICH WASN'T EASY, AS YOU
RECALL, BUT IT
RECALL, BUT IT DID
WHICH WASN'T EASY, AS YOU
RECALL, BUT IT DID PASS.
EXCEPTIONS
EXCEPTIONS WERE
RECALL, BUT IT DID PASS.
EXCEPTIONS WERE MADE
EXCEPTIONS WERE MADE FOR
RECALL, BUT IT DID PASS.
EXCEPTIONS WERE MADE FOR GUN
SHOWS,
SHOWS, AND
EXCEPTIONS WERE MADE FOR GUN
SHOWS, AND THEN
SHOWS, AND THEN LATER,
EXCEPTIONS WERE MADE FOR GUN
SHOWS, AND THEN LATER, IT
SHOWS, AND THEN LATER, IT WAS
EXTENDED
EXTENDED TO
SHOWS, AND THEN LATER, IT WAS
EXTENDED TO INCLUDE
EXTENDED TO INCLUDE ONLINE
SALES.
40%
40% OF
SALES.
40% OF GUNS
40% OF GUNS ARE
SALES.
40% OF GUNS ARE SOLD
40% OF GUNS ARE SOLD AT
SALES.
40% OF GUNS ARE SOLD AT GUN
SHOWS,
SHOWS, ONLINE
40% OF GUNS ARE SOLD AT GUN
SHOWS, ONLINE SALES.
WE
WE NEED
SHOWS, ONLINE SALES.
WE NEED TO
WE NEED TO CLOSE
SHOWS, ONLINE SALES.
WE NEED TO CLOSE THAT
WE NEED TO CLOSE THAT LOOPHOLE.
SO
SO THAT
WE NEED TO CLOSE THAT LOOPHOLE.
SO THAT WHEN
SO THAT WHEN WE
WE NEED TO CLOSE THAT LOOPHOLE.
SO THAT WHEN WE HAVE
SO THAT WHEN WE HAVE A
WE NEED TO CLOSE THAT LOOPHOLE.
SO THAT WHEN WE HAVE A UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND
BACKGROUND CHECK
SO THAT WHEN WE HAVE A UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND CHECK --
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IT
HILLARY CLINTON: IT WILL
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IT WILL COVER
EVERYBODY.
ANOTHER
ANOTHER LOOPHOLE
EVERYBODY.
ANOTHER LOOPHOLE IS
ANOTHER LOOPHOLE IS WHAT
HAPPENED
HAPPENED WHEN
ANOTHER LOOPHOLE IS WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN THE
HAPPENED WHEN THE YOUNG
ANOTHER LOOPHOLE IS WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN THE YOUNG MAN
HAPPENED WHEN THE YOUNG MAN WHO
MURDERED
MURDERED THE
HAPPENED WHEN THE YOUNG MAN WHO
MURDERED THE NINE
MURDERED THE NINE PEOPLE
HAPPENED WHEN THE YOUNG MAN WHO
MURDERED THE NINE PEOPLE AT
BIBLE
BIBLE STUDY,
MURDERED THE NINE PEOPLE AT
BIBLE STUDY, IN
BIBLE STUDY, IN THE
MURDERED THE NINE PEOPLE AT
BIBLE STUDY, IN THE CHURCH
BASEMENT
BASEMENT IN
BIBLE STUDY, IN THE CHURCH
BASEMENT IN CHARLESTON
BASEMENT IN CHARLESTON --
APPLIED
APPLIED FOR
BASEMENT IN CHARLESTON --
APPLIED FOR A
APPLIED FOR A GUN.
THE
THE LOOPHOLES
APPLIED FOR A GUN.
THE LOOPHOLES THAT
THE LOOPHOLES THAT THEY
APPLIED FOR A GUN.
THE LOOPHOLES THAT THEY DON'T
GET
GET THE
THE LOOPHOLES THAT THEY DON'T
GET THE BACKGROUND
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK
THE LOOPHOLES THAT THEY DON'T
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK DONE
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK DONE IN
THREE
THREE DAYS,
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK DONE IN
THREE DAYS, YOU
THREE DAYS, YOU CAN
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK DONE IN
THREE DAYS, YOU CAN STILL
THREE DAYS, YOU CAN STILL GO
GET THE BACKGROUND CHECK DONE IN
THREE DAYS, YOU CAN STILL GO BY
THE
THE GUN.
IT
IT TURNS
THE GUN.
IT TURNS OUT
IT TURNS OUT HE
THE GUN.
IT TURNS OUT HE HAD
IT TURNS OUT HE HAD A
THE GUN.
IT TURNS OUT HE HAD A CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND,
BACKGROUND, AND
IT TURNS OUT HE HAD A CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND, AND YOU
BACKGROUND, AND YOU KNOW
IT TURNS OUT HE HAD A CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND, AND YOU KNOW HOW
RECORD-KEEPING
RECORD-KEEPING IS.
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WILL
RECORD-KEEPING IS.
PEOPLE WILL START
PEOPLE WILL START --
RECORD-KEEPING IS.
PEOPLE WILL START -- WERE
PEOPLE WILL START -- WERE STILL
SEARCHING
SEARCHING THROUGH
PEOPLE WILL START -- WERE STILL
SEARCHING THROUGH IT.
AT
AT THE
SEARCHING THROUGH IT.
AT THE END
AT THE END OF
SEARCHING THROUGH IT.
AT THE END OF THREE
AT THE END OF THREE DAYS,
SEARCHING THROUGH IT.
AT THE END OF THREE DAYS, HE
GOES
GOES AND
AT THE END OF THREE DAYS, HE
GOES AND BUYS
GOES AND BUYS A
AT THE END OF THREE DAYS, HE
GOES AND BUYS A GUN,
GOES AND BUYS A GUN, AS
AT THE END OF THREE DAYS, HE
GOES AND BUYS A GUN, AS WE
GOES AND BUYS A GUN, AS WE DON'T
YET
YET HAVE
GOES AND BUYS A GUN, AS WE DON'T
YET HAVE IT
YET HAVE IT AUTOMATED
GOES AND BUYS A GUN, AS WE DON'T
YET HAVE IT AUTOMATED ENOUGH,
YET HAVE IT AUTOMATED ENOUGH, WE
DON'T
DON'T HAVE
YET HAVE IT AUTOMATED ENOUGH, WE
DON'T HAVE INFORMATION
DON'T HAVE INFORMATION SHARED
FROM
FROM ALL
DON'T HAVE INFORMATION SHARED
FROM ALL LEVELS
FROM ALL LEVELS OF
DON'T HAVE INFORMATION SHARED
FROM ALL LEVELS OF GOVERNMENT.
AND
AND HE
FROM ALL LEVELS OF GOVERNMENT.
AND HE GOT
AND HE GOT HIS
FROM ALL LEVELS OF GOVERNMENT.
AND HE GOT HIS GUN.
AND
AND WAS
AND HE GOT HIS GUN.
AND WAS DETERMINED
AND WAS DETERMINED TO
AND HE GOT HIS GUN.
AND WAS DETERMINED TO GO
AND WAS DETERMINED TO GO AND
AND HE GOT HIS GUN.
AND WAS DETERMINED TO GO AND USE
IT
IT TO
AND WAS DETERMINED TO GO AND USE
IT TO KILL
IT TO KILL NINE
AND WAS DETERMINED TO GO AND USE
IT TO KILL NINE INNOCENT
IT TO KILL NINE INNOCENT PEOPLE.
WE
WE ALSO
IT TO KILL NINE INNOCENT PEOPLE.
WE ALSO MUST
WE ALSO MUST ADDRESS
IT TO KILL NINE INNOCENT PEOPLE.
WE ALSO MUST ADDRESS THE
WE ALSO MUST ADDRESS THE VERY
SERIOUS
SERIOUS PROBLEM
WE ALSO MUST ADDRESS THE VERY
SERIOUS PROBLEM OF
SERIOUS PROBLEM OF MILITARY
STYLE
STYLE WEAPONS
SERIOUS PROBLEM OF MILITARY
STYLE WEAPONS ON
STYLE WEAPONS ON OUR
SERIOUS PROBLEM OF MILITARY
STYLE WEAPONS ON OUR STREETS.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW,
PEOPLE
PEOPLE DON'T
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW,
PEOPLE DON'T REALLY
PEOPLE DON'T REALLY HAVE
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW,
PEOPLE DON'T REALLY HAVE A
CHANCE.
LOTS
LOTS OF
CHANCE.
LOTS OF TIMES,
LOTS OF TIMES, WHEN
CHANCE.
LOTS OF TIMES, WHEN TERRIBLE
MURDERS
MURDERS LIKE
LOTS OF TIMES, WHEN TERRIBLE
MURDERS LIKE THIS
MURDERS LIKE THIS TAKE
LOTS OF TIMES, WHEN TERRIBLE
MURDERS LIKE THIS TAKE PLACE,
SOMEONE
SOMEONE WILL
MURDERS LIKE THIS TAKE PLACE,
SOMEONE WILL SAY
SOMEONE WILL SAY IF
MURDERS LIKE THIS TAKE PLACE,
SOMEONE WILL SAY IF WE
SOMEONE WILL SAY IF WE ONLY
MURDERS LIKE THIS TAKE PLACE,
SOMEONE WILL SAY IF WE ONLY HAD
MORE
MORE GUNS.
YOU
YOU WALK
MORE GUNS.
YOU WALK INTO
YOU WALK INTO CLASS,
MORE GUNS.
YOU WALK INTO CLASS, YOU
YOU WALK INTO CLASS, YOU ARE
DRIVING
DRIVING YOUR
YOU WALK INTO CLASS, YOU ARE
DRIVING YOUR BABY
DRIVING YOUR BABY AROUND
YOU WALK INTO CLASS, YOU ARE
DRIVING YOUR BABY AROUND IN
DRIVING YOUR BABY AROUND IN A
CAR
CAR SEAT,
DRIVING YOUR BABY AROUND IN A
CAR SEAT, YOU
CAR SEAT, YOU ARE
DRIVING YOUR BABY AROUND IN A
CAR SEAT, YOU ARE GOING
CAR SEAT, YOU ARE GOING TO
CHURCH.
AND
AND SOMEBODY
CHURCH.
AND SOMEBODY HAS
AND SOMEBODY HAS AN
CHURCH.
AND SOMEBODY HAS AN AUTOMATIC
WEAPON,
WEAPON, OR
AND SOMEBODY HAS AN AUTOMATIC
WEAPON, OR EVEN
WEAPON, OR EVEN WORSE
AND SOMEBODY HAS AN AUTOMATIC
WEAPON, OR EVEN WORSE --
WEAPON, OR EVEN WORSE -- AN
ASSAULT
ASSAULT WEAPON
WEAPON, OR EVEN WORSE -- AN
ASSAULT WEAPON THAT
ASSAULT WEAPON THAT IS
WEAPON, OR EVEN WORSE -- AN
ASSAULT WEAPON THAT IS A
MILITARY
MILITARY INSTRUMENT
ASSAULT WEAPON THAT IS A
MILITARY INSTRUMENT OF
MILITARY INSTRUMENT OF WAR,
ASSAULT WEAPON THAT IS A
MILITARY INSTRUMENT OF WAR, AND
YOU
YOU ARE
MILITARY INSTRUMENT OF WAR, AND
YOU ARE SOMEHOW
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED
MILITARY INSTRUMENT OF WAR, AND
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED TO
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED TO BE
ABLE
ABLE TO
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED TO BE
ABLE TO STOP
ABLE TO STOP THAT
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED TO BE
ABLE TO STOP THAT WITH
ABLE TO STOP THAT WITH YOUR
YOU ARE SOMEHOW SUPPOSED TO BE
ABLE TO STOP THAT WITH YOUR OWN
GUN?
THAT
THAT HAS
GUN?
THAT HAS NEVER
THAT HAS NEVER MADE
GUN?
THAT HAS NEVER MADE ANY
THAT HAS NEVER MADE ANY SENSE.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND
HILLARY CLINTON: AND SO
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND SO FROM
HILLARY CLINTON: AND SO FROM MY
PERSPECTIVE,
PERSPECTIVE, WE
HILLARY CLINTON: AND SO FROM MY
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT
HILLARY CLINTON: AND SO FROM MY
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT TO
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT TO KEEP
GUNS
GUNS OUT
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT TO KEEP
GUNS OUT OF
GUNS OUT OF THE
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT TO KEEP
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF
PERSPECTIVE, WE HAVE GOT TO KEEP
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF PEOPLE
WHO
WHO SHOULD
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF PEOPLE
WHO SHOULD NOT
WHO SHOULD NOT HAVE
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF PEOPLE
WHO SHOULD NOT HAVE THEM.
DOMESTIC
DOMESTIC ABUSERS,
WHO SHOULD NOT HAVE THEM.
DOMESTIC ABUSERS, PEOPLE
DOMESTIC ABUSERS, PEOPLE WITH
SERIOUS
SERIOUS MENTAL
DOMESTIC ABUSERS, PEOPLE WITH
SERIOUS MENTAL HEALTH
SERIOUS MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
THERE'S
THERE'S GOT
SERIOUS MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
THERE'S GOT TO
THERE'S GOT TO BE
SERIOUS MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
THERE'S GOT TO BE A
THERE'S GOT TO BE A BETTER
TRACKING
TRACKING AND
THERE'S GOT TO BE A BETTER
TRACKING AND RECORD-KEEPING.
I
I REMEMBER
TRACKING AND RECORD-KEEPING.
I REMEMBER THE
I REMEMBER THE TERRIBLE
TRACKING AND RECORD-KEEPING.
I REMEMBER THE TERRIBLE MASSACRE
AT
AT VIRGINIA
I REMEMBER THE TERRIBLE MASSACRE
AT VIRGINIA TECH.
THE
THE SHOOTER
AT VIRGINIA TECH.
THE SHOOTER THERE
THE SHOOTER THERE HAD
AT VIRGINIA TECH.
THE SHOOTER THERE HAD BEEN
INVOLUNTARILY
INVOLUNTARILY COMMITTED.
AND
AND THERE
INVOLUNTARILY COMMITTED.
AND THERE WAS
AND THERE WAS NO
INVOLUNTARILY COMMITTED.
AND THERE WAS NO RECORD
AND THERE WAS NO RECORD OF
INVOLUNTARILY COMMITTED.
AND THERE WAS NO RECORD OF IT.
AND
AND IF
AND THERE WAS NO RECORD OF IT.
AND IF THERE
AND IF THERE IS
AND THERE WAS NO RECORD OF IT.
AND IF THERE IS INFORMATION
ABOUT
ABOUT PEOPLE
AND IF THERE IS INFORMATION
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO ARE
AND IF THERE IS INFORMATION
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO ARE EXCELLENT,
--
-- EX
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO ARE EXCELLENT,
-- EX FELONS,
-- EX FELONS, WHO
ABOUT PEOPLE WHO ARE EXCELLENT,
-- EX FELONS, WHO ARE
-- EX FELONS, WHO ARE SUFFERING
AND
AND SERIOUS
-- EX FELONS, WHO ARE SUFFERING
AND SERIOUS MENTAL
AND SERIOUS MENTAL ILLNESS,
-- EX FELONS, WHO ARE SUFFERING
AND SERIOUS MENTAL ILLNESS, WHO
ARE
ARE DOMESTIC
AND SERIOUS MENTAL ILLNESS, WHO
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS,
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS, YOU
AND SERIOUS MENTAL ILLNESS, WHO
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS, YOU GOT
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS, YOU GOT TO
GET
GET THAT
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS, YOU GOT TO
GET THAT INFORMATION
GET THAT INFORMATION INTO
ARE DOMESTIC ABUSERS, YOU GOT TO
GET THAT INFORMATION INTO THE
RECORD-KEEPING,
RECORD-KEEPING, SO
GET THAT INFORMATION INTO THE
RECORD-KEEPING, SO THAT
RECORD-KEEPING, SO THAT THE
UNIVERSAL
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND
RECORD-KEEPING, SO THAT THE
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS WILL
ACTUALLY
ACTUALLY SHOW
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS WILL
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU THAT
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS WILL
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU THAT HERE
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU THAT HERE IS
SOMEBODY
SOMEBODY WHO
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU THAT HERE IS
SOMEBODY WHO SHOULDN'T
SOMEBODY WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE
ACTUALLY SHOW YOU THAT HERE IS
SOMEBODY WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE IT.
PEOPLE
PEOPLE SAY
SOMEBODY WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE IT.
PEOPLE SAY TO
PEOPLE SAY TO ME
SOMEBODY WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE IT.
PEOPLE SAY TO ME DOES
PEOPLE SAY TO ME DOES THIS
REALLY
REALLY WORK?
I
I CAN
REALLY WORK?
I CAN TELL
I CAN TELL YOU
REALLY WORK?
I CAN TELL YOU THIS.
THE
THE BEST
I CAN TELL YOU THIS.
THE BEST DATA
THE BEST DATA THAT
I CAN TELL YOU THIS.
THE BEST DATA THAT WE
THE BEST DATA THAT WE HAVE
I CAN TELL YOU THIS.
THE BEST DATA THAT WE HAVE IS
THAT
THAT SINCE
THE BEST DATA THAT WE HAVE IS
THAT SINCE THE
THAT SINCE THE BRADY
THE BEST DATA THAT WE HAVE IS
THAT SINCE THE BRADY BILL
IMPLEMENTED
IMPLEMENTED BACKGROUND
THAT SINCE THE BRADY BILL
IMPLEMENTED BACKGROUND CHECKS,
MORE
MORE THAN
IMPLEMENTED BACKGROUND CHECKS,
MORE THAN 2.4
MORE THAN 2.4 MILLION
IMPLEMENTED BACKGROUND CHECKS,
MORE THAN 2.4 MILLION PEOPLE
HAVE
HAVE BEEN
MORE THAN 2.4 MILLION PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN STOPPED
HAVE BEEN STOPPED FROM
MORE THAN 2.4 MILLION PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN STOPPED FROM BUYING
HAVE BEEN STOPPED FROM BUYING A
GUN.
AND
AND OVER
GUN.
AND OVER ONE
AND OVER ONE MILLION
GUN.
AND OVER ONE MILLION OF
AND OVER ONE MILLION OF THOSE
WERE
WERE FELONS.
THERE
THERE WERE
WERE FELONS.
THERE WERE RECORDS
THERE WERE RECORDS OF
WERE FELONS.
THERE WERE RECORDS OF THOSE
PARTICULAR
PARTICULAR POTENTIAL
THERE WERE RECORDS OF THOSE
PARTICULAR POTENTIAL PURCHASERS.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND
HILLARY CLINTON: AND I
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND I WANT
HILLARY CLINTON: AND I WANT TO
WORK
WORK WITH
HILLARY CLINTON: AND I WANT TO
WORK WITH ALL
WORK WITH ALL OF
HILLARY CLINTON: AND I WANT TO
WORK WITH ALL OF YOU.
I
I WANT
WORK WITH ALL OF YOU.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO WORK
WORK WITH ALL OF YOU.
I WANT TO WORK WITH
I WANT TO WORK WITH SENSIBLE
WORK WITH ALL OF YOU.
I WANT TO WORK WITH SENSIBLE GUN
SAFETY
SAFETY ADVOCATES
I WANT TO WORK WITH SENSIBLE GUN
SAFETY ADVOCATES AS
SAFETY ADVOCATES AS WELL
I WANT TO WORK WITH SENSIBLE GUN
SAFETY ADVOCATES AS WELL AS
SAFETY ADVOCATES AS WELL AS GUN
OWNERS.
I
I WANT
OWNERS.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO WORK
OWNERS.
I WANT TO WORK WITH
I WANT TO WORK WITH PEOPLE
OWNERS.
I WANT TO WORK WITH PEOPLE FROM
THE
THE GRASSROOTS
I WANT TO WORK WITH PEOPLE FROM
THE GRASSROOTS UP
THE GRASSROOTS UP COME
I WANT TO WORK WITH PEOPLE FROM
THE GRASSROOTS UP COME ALL
THE GRASSROOTS UP COME ALL THE
WAY
WAY TO
THE GRASSROOTS UP COME ALL THE
WAY TO WASHINGTON.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE HOW
WAY TO WASHINGTON.
BECAUSE HOW MUCH
BECAUSE HOW MUCH LONGER
WAY TO WASHINGTON.
BECAUSE HOW MUCH LONGER WILL
BECAUSE HOW MUCH LONGER WILL WE
JUST
JUST SHRUG?
OH
OH MY
JUST SHRUG?
OH MY GOSH,
OH MY GOSH, SOMETHING
JUST SHRUG?
OH MY GOSH, SOMETHING ELSE
TERRIBLE
TERRIBLE HAPPENED.
WHETHER
WHETHER IT'S
TERRIBLE HAPPENED.
WHETHER IT'S IN
WHETHER IT'S IN YOUR
NEIGHBORHOOD,
NEIGHBORHOOD, OR
WHETHER IT'S IN YOUR
NEIGHBORHOOD, OR A
NEIGHBORHOOD, OR A COMMUNITY
COLLEGE.
OR,
OR, THE
COLLEGE.
OR, THE MURDER
OR, THE MURDER OF
COLLEGE.
OR, THE MURDER OF CHILDREN
OR, THE MURDER OF CHILDREN IN
THEIR
THEIR CLASSROOMS?
WE
WE ARE
THEIR CLASSROOMS?
WE ARE TO
WE ARE TO GO
THEIR CLASSROOMS?
WE ARE TO GO TO
WE ARE TO GO TO THE
THEIR CLASSROOMS?
WE ARE TO GO TO THE TOWN
WE ARE TO GO TO THE TOWN HALL
PORTION
PORTION OF
WE ARE TO GO TO THE TOWN HALL
PORTION OF THIS.
BUT
BUT I
PORTION OF THIS.
BUT I WANT
BUT I WANT TO
PORTION OF THIS.
BUT I WANT TO ASK
BUT I WANT TO ASK ONE
PORTION OF THIS.
BUT I WANT TO ASK ONE OF
BUT I WANT TO ASK ONE OF THE
MOTHERS
MOTHERS FROM
BUT I WANT TO ASK ONE OF THE
MOTHERS FROM SANDY
MOTHERS FROM SANDY HOOK,
BUT I WANT TO ASK ONE OF THE
MOTHERS FROM SANDY HOOK, IF
MOTHERS FROM SANDY HOOK, IF YOU
WOULDN'T
WOULDN'T MIND,
MOTHERS FROM SANDY HOOK, IF YOU
WOULDN'T MIND, TO
WOULDN'T MIND, TO JUST
MOTHERS FROM SANDY HOOK, IF YOU
WOULDN'T MIND, TO JUST COME
WOULDN'T MIND, TO JUST COME JOIN
ME
ME FOR
WOULDN'T MIND, TO JUST COME JOIN
ME FOR A
ME FOR A MINUTE.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
ME FOR A MINUTE.
BECAUSE I WANT
BECAUSE I WANT YOU
ME FOR A MINUTE.
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO HEAR
ME FOR A MINUTE.
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO HEAR FROM
HER.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE SO
HER.
BECAUSE SO MANY
BECAUSE SO MANY OF
HER.
BECAUSE SO MANY OF THE
BECAUSE SO MANY OF THE PARENTS
--
-- [APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
-- [APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW,
-- [APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, SO
MANY
MANY OF
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, SO
MANY OF THE
MANY OF THE PARENTS
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU KNOW, SO
MANY OF THE PARENTS OF
MANY OF THE PARENTS OF THESE
PRECIOUS
PRECIOUS CHILDREN
MANY OF THE PARENTS OF THESE
PRECIOUS CHILDREN WHO
PRECIOUS CHILDREN WHO ARE
MURDERED
MURDERED HAVE
PRECIOUS CHILDREN WHO ARE
MURDERED HAVE TAKEN
MURDERED HAVE TAKEN THE
UNIMAGINABLE
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF
MURDERED HAVE TAKEN THE
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THAT
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THAT THEY
HAVE
HAVE BEEN
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THAT THEY
HAVE BEEN BEARING,
HAVE BEEN BEARING, AND
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THAT THEY
HAVE BEEN BEARING, AND HAVE
TRIED
TRIED TO
HAVE BEEN BEARING, AND HAVE
TRIED TO BE
TRIED TO BE THE
HAVE BEEN BEARING, AND HAVE
TRIED TO BE THE VOICES
TRIED TO BE THE VOICES THAT
HAVE BEEN BEARING, AND HAVE
TRIED TO BE THE VOICES THAT WE
NEED
NEED TO
TRIED TO BE THE VOICES THAT WE
NEED TO HEAR.
I
I WANT
NEED TO HEAR.
I WANT YOU
I WANT YOU TO
NEED TO HEAR.
I WANT YOU TO INTRODUCE
I WANT YOU TO INTRODUCE YOURSELF
AND
AND MAYBE
I WANT YOU TO INTRODUCE YOURSELF
AND MAYBE TALK
AND MAYBE TALK ABOUT
I WANT YOU TO INTRODUCE YOURSELF
AND MAYBE TALK ABOUT WHAT
AND MAYBE TALK ABOUT WHAT YOU
AND
AND OTHER
AND MAYBE TALK ABOUT WHAT YOU
AND OTHER PARENTS
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE
AND MAYBE TALK ABOUT WHAT YOU
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE TRYING
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE TRYING TO
DO
DO TO
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE TRYING TO
DO TO GET
DO TO GET THE
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE TRYING TO
DO TO GET THE CHANGES
DO TO GET THE CHANGES THAT
AND OTHER PARENTS ARE TRYING TO
DO TO GET THE CHANGES THAT ARE
NECESSARY.
>>
>> THANK
NECESSARY.
>> THANK YOU.
MY
MY NAME
>> THANK YOU.
MY NAME IS
MY NAME IS NICOLE
>> THANK YOU.
MY NAME IS NICOLE HOCKLEY,
MY NAME IS NICOLE HOCKLEY, AND
THE
THE MANAGING
MY NAME IS NICOLE HOCKLEY, AND
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR AT
MY NAME IS NICOLE HOCKLEY, AND
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR AT SANDY
HOOK
HOOK PROMISE
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR AT SANDY
HOOK PROMISE AND
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR AT SANDY
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO THE
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO THE MOTHER
OF
OF DYLAN,
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO THE MOTHER
OF DYLAN, WHO
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO THE MOTHER
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX YEARS
HOOK PROMISE AND ALSO THE MOTHER
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX YEARS OLD
WHEN
WHEN HE
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX YEARS OLD
WHEN HE WAS
WHEN HE WAS KILLED
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX YEARS OLD
WHEN HE WAS KILLED AT
WHEN HE WAS KILLED AT SANDY
OF DYLAN, WHO WAS SIX YEARS OLD
WHEN HE WAS KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
GUN
GUN VIOLENCE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
GUN VIOLENCE PREVENTION
GUN VIOLENCE PREVENTION WAS
NOWHERE
NOWHERE ON
GUN VIOLENCE PREVENTION WAS
NOWHERE ON MY
NOWHERE ON MY RADAR.
BEFORE
BEFORE LOSING
NOWHERE ON MY RADAR.
BEFORE LOSING MY
BEFORE LOSING MY SON.
I
I WISH
BEFORE LOSING MY SON.
I WISH IT
I WISH IT HAD
BEFORE LOSING MY SON.
I WISH IT HAD BEEN.
I
I WISH
I WISH IT HAD BEEN.
I WISH I
I WISH I HAD
I WISH IT HAD BEEN.
I WISH I HAD DONE
I WISH I HAD DONE SOMETHING
I WISH IT HAD BEEN.
I WISH I HAD DONE SOMETHING LONG
BEFORE
BEFORE SOMETHING
I WISH I HAD DONE SOMETHING LONG
BEFORE SOMETHING THAT
BEFORE SOMETHING THAT I
I WISH I HAD DONE SOMETHING LONG
BEFORE SOMETHING THAT I THOUGHT
COULD
COULD NEVER
BEFORE SOMETHING THAT I THOUGHT
COULD NEVER HIT
COULD NEVER HIT MY
BEFORE SOMETHING THAT I THOUGHT
COULD NEVER HIT MY COMMUNITY
COULD NEVER HIT MY COMMUNITY HIT
ME.
AS
AS PART
ME.
AS PART OF
AS PART OF SANDY
ME.
AS PART OF SANDY HOOK
AS PART OF SANDY HOOK PROMISE,
WE
WE FOCUS
AS PART OF SANDY HOOK PROMISE,
WE FOCUS VERY
WE FOCUS VERY MUCH
AS PART OF SANDY HOOK PROMISE,
WE FOCUS VERY MUCH ON
WE FOCUS VERY MUCH ON GUN
AS PART OF SANDY HOOK PROMISE,
WE FOCUS VERY MUCH ON GUN SAFETY
LEGISLATION.
AND
AND THE
LEGISLATION.
AND THE COMMONSENSE
AND THE COMMONSENSE PRACTICES
YOU
YOU ARE
AND THE COMMONSENSE PRACTICES
YOU ARE SPEAKING
YOU ARE SPEAKING OF,
AND THE COMMONSENSE PRACTICES
YOU ARE SPEAKING OF, SO
YOU ARE SPEAKING OF, SO THANK
YOU
YOU FOR
YOU ARE SPEAKING OF, SO THANK
YOU FOR TAKING
YOU FOR TAKING THIS
YOU ARE SPEAKING OF, SO THANK
YOU FOR TAKING THIS ON
YOU FOR TAKING THIS ON AND
SPEAKING
SPEAKING OUT.
WE
WE ALSO
SPEAKING OUT.
WE ALSO VERY
WE ALSO VERY MUCH
SPEAKING OUT.
WE ALSO VERY MUCH FOCUSED
WE ALSO VERY MUCH FOCUSED ON
WHAT
WHAT CAN
WE ALSO VERY MUCH FOCUSED ON
WHAT CAN WE
WHAT CAN WE DO
WE ALSO VERY MUCH FOCUSED ON
WHAT CAN WE DO TO
WHAT CAN WE DO TO GET
WE ALSO VERY MUCH FOCUSED ON
WHAT CAN WE DO TO GET AHEAD
WHAT CAN WE DO TO GET AHEAD OF
THE
THE VIOLENCE?
TO
TO GET
THE VIOLENCE?
TO GET UPSTREAM
TO GET UPSTREAM OF
THE VIOLENCE?
TO GET UPSTREAM OF IT
TO GET UPSTREAM OF IT AND
THE VIOLENCE?
TO GET UPSTREAM OF IT AND HELP
IDENTIFY
IDENTIFY AND
TO GET UPSTREAM OF IT AND HELP
IDENTIFY AND INTERVENE,
IDENTIFY AND INTERVENE, HELP
PEOPLE
PEOPLE LEARN
IDENTIFY AND INTERVENE, HELP
PEOPLE LEARN HOW
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO
IDENTIFY AND INTERVENE, HELP
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO KNOW
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO KNOW THE
SIGNS
SIGNS OF
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO KNOW THE
SIGNS OF SOMEONE
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO KNOW THE
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO IS
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO IS AT
PEOPLE LEARN HOW TO KNOW THE
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO IS AT RISK,
AND
AND GET
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO IS AT RISK,
AND GET HELP
AND GET HELP BEFORE
SIGNS OF SOMEONE WHO IS AT RISK,
AND GET HELP BEFORE THEY
AND GET HELP BEFORE THEY EVEN
GET
GET TO
AND GET HELP BEFORE THEY EVEN
GET TO THE
GET TO THE STATE
AND GET HELP BEFORE THEY EVEN
GET TO THE STATE OF
GET TO THE STATE OF PICKING
AND GET HELP BEFORE THEY EVEN
GET TO THE STATE OF PICKING UP
GET TO THE STATE OF PICKING UP A
WEAPON
WEAPON TO
GET TO THE STATE OF PICKING UP A
WEAPON TO HURT
WEAPON TO HURT SOMEONE
GET TO THE STATE OF PICKING UP A
WEAPON TO HURT SOMEONE ELSE.
I
I THINK
WEAPON TO HURT SOMEONE ELSE.
I THINK IT
I THINK IT IS
WEAPON TO HURT SOMEONE ELSE.
I THINK IT IS A
I THINK IT IS A COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION
SOLUTION THAT
I THINK IT IS A COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION THAT IS
SOLUTION THAT IS NEEDED
I THINK IT IS A COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION THAT IS NEEDED BETWEEN
GUN
GUN ACCESS
SOLUTION THAT IS NEEDED BETWEEN
GUN ACCESS AND
GUN ACCESS AND RESPONSIBILITY,
AS
AS WELL
GUN ACCESS AND RESPONSIBILITY,
AS WELL AS
AS WELL AS MENTAL
GUN ACCESS AND RESPONSIBILITY,
AS WELL AS MENTAL HEALTH
AS WELL AS MENTAL HEALTH AND
WELLNESS.
AND
AND WORKING
WELLNESS.
AND WORKING TOGETHER
AND WORKING TOGETHER WITH
WELLNESS.
AND WORKING TOGETHER WITH ALL
AND WORKING TOGETHER WITH ALL OF
THE
THE OTHER
AND WORKING TOGETHER WITH ALL OF
THE OTHER ORGANIZATIONS,
THE OTHER ORGANIZATIONS, AND
AND WORKING TOGETHER WITH ALL OF
THE OTHER ORGANIZATIONS, AND ALL
THE
THE OTHER
THE OTHER ORGANIZATIONS, AND ALL
THE OTHER PEOPLE,
THE OTHER PEOPLE, AS
THE OTHER ORGANIZATIONS, AND ALL
THE OTHER PEOPLE, AS WELL
THE OTHER PEOPLE, AS WELL AS
YOURSELF,
YOURSELF, I
THE OTHER PEOPLE, AS WELL AS
YOURSELF, I HAVE
YOURSELF, I HAVE ABSOLUTE
THE OTHER PEOPLE, AS WELL AS
YOURSELF, I HAVE ABSOLUTE FAITH
THAT
THAT WE
YOURSELF, I HAVE ABSOLUTE FAITH
THAT WE CAN
THAT WE CAN DELIVER
YOURSELF, I HAVE ABSOLUTE FAITH
THAT WE CAN DELIVER THE
THAT WE CAN DELIVER THE SOLUTION
AND
AND PROTECT
THAT WE CAN DELIVER THE SOLUTION
AND PROTECT CHILDREN
AND PROTECT CHILDREN ACROSS
AMERICA.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
YOU
YOU KNOW,
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, I
YOU KNOW, I THINK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE JUST
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE JUST HEARD
REALLY
REALLY REINFORCES
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE JUST HEARD
REALLY REINFORCES HOW
REALLY REINFORCES HOW NOBODY
KNOWS
KNOWS WHAT
REALLY REINFORCES HOW NOBODY
KNOWS WHAT MIGHT
KNOWS WHAT MIGHT HAPPEN.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE WE
KNOWS WHAT MIGHT HAPPEN.
BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T
BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T DONE
KNOWS WHAT MIGHT HAPPEN.
BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T DONE WHAT
BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T DONE WHAT WE
NEED
NEED TO
BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T DONE WHAT WE
NEED TO DO.
TO
TO TRY
NEED TO DO.
TO TRY AND
TO TRY AND MAKE
NEED TO DO.
TO TRY AND MAKE ANY
TO TRY AND MAKE ANY OF
NEED TO DO.
TO TRY AND MAKE ANY OF US,
TO TRY AND MAKE ANY OF US, BUT
PARTICULARLY
PARTICULARLY OUR
TO TRY AND MAKE ANY OF US, BUT
PARTICULARLY OUR CHILDREN,
PARTICULARLY OUR CHILDREN, SAFE.
THAT'S
THAT'S WHAT
PARTICULARLY OUR CHILDREN, SAFE.
THAT'S WHAT BEHIND
THAT'S WHAT BEHIND THE
PARTICULARLY OUR CHILDREN, SAFE.
THAT'S WHAT BEHIND THE PROPOSALS
I'M
I'M MAKING.
THEY
THEY ARE
I'M MAKING.
THEY ARE NOT
THEY ARE NOT NEW.
THERE'S
THERE'S NOTHING
THEY ARE NOT NEW.
THERE'S NOTHING UNIQUE
THERE'S NOTHING UNIQUE ABOUT
THEM,
THEM, OTHER
THERE'S NOTHING UNIQUE ABOUT
THEM, OTHER THAN
THEM, OTHER THAN THE
THERE'S NOTHING UNIQUE ABOUT
THEM, OTHER THAN THE FACT
THEM, OTHER THAN THE FACT THAT
THERE'S NOTHING UNIQUE ABOUT
THEM, OTHER THAN THE FACT THAT I
AM
AM SO
THEM, OTHER THAN THE FACT THAT I
AM SO DETERMINED
AM SO DETERMINED WE'RE
THEM, OTHER THAN THE FACT THAT I
AM SO DETERMINED WE'RE GOING
AM SO DETERMINED WE'RE GOING TO
DO
DO EVERYTHING
AM SO DETERMINED WE'RE GOING TO
DO EVERYTHING WE
DO EVERYTHING WE POSSIBLY
AM SO DETERMINED WE'RE GOING TO
DO EVERYTHING WE POSSIBLY CAN
DO EVERYTHING WE POSSIBLY CAN TO
GET
GET THIS
DO EVERYTHING WE POSSIBLY CAN TO
GET THIS DONE.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I KNOW
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I KNOW THERE
ARE
ARE A
HILLARY CLINTON: I KNOW THERE
ARE A LOT
ARE A LOT OF
HILLARY CLINTON: I KNOW THERE
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE.
WE
WE HAVE
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE.
WE HAVE A
WE HAVE A BIG
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE.
WE HAVE A BIG GROUP
WE HAVE A BIG GROUP FROM
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE.
WE HAVE A BIG GROUP FROM MOMS
DEMAND
DEMAND ACTION,
WE HAVE A BIG GROUP FROM MOMS
DEMAND ACTION, AND
DEMAND ACTION, AND FROM
WE HAVE A BIG GROUP FROM MOMS
DEMAND ACTION, AND FROM DAD'S
DEMAND ACTION, AND FROM DAD'S AS
WELL.
I
I WANT
WELL.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO COMMEND
WELL.
I WANT TO COMMEND THEM.
THEY
THEY ARE
I WANT TO COMMEND THEM.
THEY ARE GRASSROOTS
THEY ARE GRASSROOTS ORGANIZATION
THAT
THAT IS
THEY ARE GRASSROOTS ORGANIZATION
THAT IS REALLY
THAT IS REALLY TRYING
THEY ARE GRASSROOTS ORGANIZATION
THAT IS REALLY TRYING TO
THAT IS REALLY TRYING TO BRING
THESE
THESE ISSUES
THAT IS REALLY TRYING TO BRING
THESE ISSUES TO
THESE ISSUES TO THE
THAT IS REALLY TRYING TO BRING
THESE ISSUES TO THE PUBLIC
ATTENTION.
WE
WE NEED
ATTENTION.
WE NEED MORE
WE NEED MORE OF
ATTENTION.
WE NEED MORE OF THAT.
I
I HAVE
WE NEED MORE OF THAT.
I HAVE SAID
I HAVE SAID WE
WE NEED MORE OF THAT.
I HAVE SAID WE NEED
I HAVE SAID WE NEED A
WE NEED MORE OF THAT.
I HAVE SAID WE NEED A MOVEMENT,
THAT
THAT PEOPLE
I HAVE SAID WE NEED A MOVEMENT,
THAT PEOPLE REALLY
THAT PEOPLE REALLY WILL
I HAVE SAID WE NEED A MOVEMENT,
THAT PEOPLE REALLY WILL BE
THAT PEOPLE REALLY WILL BE PART
OF,
OF, NO
THAT PEOPLE REALLY WILL BE PART
OF, NO MATTER
OF, NO MATTER WHAT
THAT PEOPLE REALLY WILL BE PART
OF, NO MATTER WHAT OTHER
OF, NO MATTER WHAT OTHER ISSUES
THAT
THAT IS
OF, NO MATTER WHAT OTHER ISSUES
THAT IS ON
THAT IS ON YOUR
OF, NO MATTER WHAT OTHER ISSUES
THAT IS ON YOUR MIND,
THAT IS ON YOUR MIND, THAT
OF, NO MATTER WHAT OTHER ISSUES
THAT IS ON YOUR MIND, THAT YOU
CARE
CARE ABOUT
THAT IS ON YOUR MIND, THAT YOU
CARE ABOUT --
CARE ABOUT -- OUR
THAT IS ON YOUR MIND, THAT YOU
CARE ABOUT -- OUR SAFETY.
THE
THE GREAT
CARE ABOUT -- OUR SAFETY.
THE GREAT HOPE
THE GREAT HOPE THAT
CARE ABOUT -- OUR SAFETY.
THE GREAT HOPE THAT WE
THE GREAT HOPE THAT WE CAN
PROTECT
PROTECT PEOPLE
THE GREAT HOPE THAT WE CAN
PROTECT PEOPLE WHO
PROTECT PEOPLE WHO ARE
THE GREAT HOPE THAT WE CAN
PROTECT PEOPLE WHO ARE GOING
ABOUT
ABOUT THEIR
PROTECT PEOPLE WHO ARE GOING
ABOUT THEIR DAILY
ABOUT THEIR DAILY BUSINESS
SHOULD
SHOULD BE
ABOUT THEIR DAILY BUSINESS
SHOULD BE AT
SHOULD BE AT THE
ABOUT THEIR DAILY BUSINESS
SHOULD BE AT THE TOP.
AND
AND THEREFORE,
SHOULD BE AT THE TOP.
AND THEREFORE, I'M
AND THEREFORE, I'M REALLY
SHOULD BE AT THE TOP.
AND THEREFORE, I'M REALLY ASKING
EVERYBODY,
EVERYBODY, REGARDLESS
AND THEREFORE, I'M REALLY ASKING
EVERYBODY, REGARDLESS OF
POLITICS
POLITICS OR
EVERYBODY, REGARDLESS OF
POLITICS OR PARTISANSHIP
POLITICS OR PARTISANSHIP OR
CANDIDATES
CANDIDATES OR
POLITICS OR PARTISANSHIP OR
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING ELSE
POLITICS OR PARTISANSHIP OR
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING ELSE TO
THINK
THINK OF
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING ELSE TO
THINK OF THE
THINK OF THE WAYS
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING ELSE TO
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT EACH
CANDIDATES OR ANYTHING ELSE TO
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT EACH OF
US
US CAN
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT EACH OF
US CAN DO
US CAN DO MORE
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT EACH OF
US CAN DO MORE TO
US CAN DO MORE TO TRY
THINK OF THE WAYS THAT EACH OF
US CAN DO MORE TO TRY TO
US CAN DO MORE TO TRY TO PROVIDE
THAT
THAT MEASURE
US CAN DO MORE TO TRY TO PROVIDE
THAT MEASURE OF
THAT MEASURE OF GUN
US CAN DO MORE TO TRY TO PROVIDE
THAT MEASURE OF GUN SAFETY
THAT MEASURE OF GUN SAFETY THAT
WILL
WILL SAVE
THAT MEASURE OF GUN SAFETY THAT
WILL SAVE LIVES
WILL SAVE LIVES AND
THAT MEASURE OF GUN SAFETY THAT
WILL SAVE LIVES AND PREVENT
VIOLENCE.
LET
LET ME
VIOLENCE.
LET ME START
LET ME START BY
VIOLENCE.
LET ME START BY ASKING
LET ME START BY ASKING PEOPLE,
IF
IF YOU
LET ME START BY ASKING PEOPLE,
IF YOU WANT
IF YOU WANT TO
LET ME START BY ASKING PEOPLE,
IF YOU WANT TO SAY
IF YOU WANT TO SAY SOMETHING
WHERE
WHERE YOU
IF YOU WANT TO SAY SOMETHING
WHERE YOU HAVE
WHERE YOU HAVE A
IF YOU WANT TO SAY SOMETHING
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT TO
IF YOU WANT TO SAY SOMETHING
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT TO MAKE
ON
ON THIS,
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT TO MAKE
ON THIS, OR
ON THIS, OR ANY
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT TO MAKE
ON THIS, OR ANY ISSUE,
ON THIS, OR ANY ISSUE, I
WHERE YOU HAVE A COMMENT TO MAKE
ON THIS, OR ANY ISSUE, I WOULD
LIKE
LIKE TO
ON THIS, OR ANY ISSUE, I WOULD
LIKE TO START
LIKE TO START THIS
ON THIS, OR ANY ISSUE, I WOULD
LIKE TO START THIS ISSUE
LIKE TO START THIS ISSUE BECAUSE
I
I KNOW
LIKE TO START THIS ISSUE BECAUSE
I KNOW THERE
I KNOW THERE ARE
LIKE TO START THIS ISSUE BECAUSE
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE
SPECIFICALLY
SPECIFICALLY ON
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE AND
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE AND I
WANT
WANT TO
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE AND I
WANT TO BE
WANT TO BE SURE
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE AND I
WANT TO BE SURE TO
WANT TO BE SURE TO HEAR
SPECIFICALLY ON THIS ISSUE AND I
WANT TO BE SURE TO HEAR FROM
THEM.
FORMER
FORMER CONGRESSMAN
THEM.
FORMER CONGRESSMAN DIX
FORMER CONGRESSMAN DIX SWEAT,
HELLO.
>>
>> IT'S
HELLO.
>> IT'S WONDERFUL
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO
HELLO.
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HAVE
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HAVE YOU
HERE,
HERE, ALWAYS
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HAVE YOU
HERE, ALWAYS A
HERE, ALWAYS A PLEASURE
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HAVE YOU
HERE, ALWAYS A PLEASURE TO
HERE, ALWAYS A PLEASURE TO BE
WITH
WITH MY
HERE, ALWAYS A PLEASURE TO BE
WITH MY GOOD
WITH MY GOOD FRIENDS
HERE, ALWAYS A PLEASURE TO BE
WITH MY GOOD FRIENDS THE
CLINTONS.
I
I WANT
CLINTONS.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO GIVE
CLINTONS.
I WANT TO GIVE EVERYONE
I WANT TO GIVE EVERYONE A
BACKGROUND
BACKGROUND ON
I WANT TO GIVE EVERYONE A
BACKGROUND ON OUR
BACKGROUND ON OUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH
WITH REGARDS
BACKGROUND ON OUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH REGARDS TO
WITH REGARDS TO GUNS.
IN
IN 1994,
WITH REGARDS TO GUNS.
IN 1994, I
IN 1994, I VOTED
WITH REGARDS TO GUNS.
IN 1994, I VOTED IN
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR
WITH REGARDS TO GUNS.
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR OF
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR OF A
CRIME
CRIME BILL
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR OF A
CRIME BILL THAT
CRIME BILL THAT HAD
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR OF A
CRIME BILL THAT HAD IN
CRIME BILL THAT HAD IN IT
IN 1994, I VOTED IN FAVOR OF A
CRIME BILL THAT HAD IN IT AN
ASSAULT
ASSAULT WEAPONS
CRIME BILL THAT HAD IN IT AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN FOR
CRIME BILL THAT HAD IN IT AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN FOR 17
ASSAULT
ASSAULT WEAPONS
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN FOR 17
ASSAULT WEAPONS OUT
ASSAULT WEAPONS OUT OF
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN FOR 17
ASSAULT WEAPONS OUT OF NEARLY
800 WEAPONS
800 WEAPONS THAT
ASSAULT WEAPONS OUT OF NEARLY
800 WEAPONS THAT WERE
800 WEAPONS THAT WERE ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS OUT OF NEARLY
800 WEAPONS THAT WERE ON THE
STREET.
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> I'M
[APPLAUSE]
>> I'M NOT
>> I'M NOT LOOKING
[APPLAUSE]
>> I'M NOT LOOKING FOR
>> I'M NOT LOOKING FOR ANY
ATTENTION,
ATTENTION, BUT
>> I'M NOT LOOKING FOR ANY
ATTENTION, BUT I
ATTENTION, BUT I RECEIVED
>> I'M NOT LOOKING FOR ANY
ATTENTION, BUT I RECEIVED A
LETTER
LETTER PRIOR
ATTENTION, BUT I RECEIVED A
LETTER PRIOR TO
LETTER PRIOR TO THE
ATTENTION, BUT I RECEIVED A
LETTER PRIOR TO THE VOTE
LETTER PRIOR TO THE VOTE THAT
ATTENTION, BUT I RECEIVED A
LETTER PRIOR TO THE VOTE THAT I
THOUGHT
THOUGHT WOULD
LETTER PRIOR TO THE VOTE THAT I
THOUGHT WOULD BE
THOUGHT WOULD BE WORTH
LETTER PRIOR TO THE VOTE THAT I
THOUGHT WOULD BE WORTH SHARING
WITH
WITH THE
THOUGHT WOULD BE WORTH SHARING
WITH THE PEOPLE
WITH THE PEOPLE HERE.
I
I SHARED
WITH THE PEOPLE HERE.
I SHARED IT
I SHARED IT WITH
WITH THE PEOPLE HERE.
I SHARED IT WITH HILLARY
EARLIER.
IT
IT IS
EARLIER.
IT IS A
IT IS A LETTER
EARLIER.
IT IS A LETTER FROM
IT IS A LETTER FROM RONALD
REAGAN,
REAGAN, AND
IT IS A LETTER FROM RONALD
REAGAN, AND IT
REAGAN, AND IT IS
IT IS A LETTER FROM RONALD
REAGAN, AND IT IS DATED
REAGAN, AND IT IS DATED MAY
IT IS A LETTER FROM RONALD
REAGAN, AND IT IS DATED MAY 5,
1994,
1994, AND
REAGAN, AND IT IS DATED MAY 5,
1994, AND IT'S
1994, AND IT'S WRITTEN
REAGAN, AND IT IS DATED MAY 5,
1994, AND IT'S WRITTEN TO
CONGRESSMAN
CONGRESSMAN DIX
1994, AND IT'S WRITTEN TO
CONGRESSMAN DIX SWEAT.
HE
HE WRITES
CONGRESSMAN DIX SWEAT.
HE WRITES --
HE WRITES -- HERE'S
CONGRESSMAN DIX SWEAT.
HE WRITES -- HERE'S A
HE WRITES -- HERE'S A COPY
CONGRESSMAN DIX SWEAT.
HE WRITES -- HERE'S A COPY OF
THE
THE LETTER.
I'M
I'M READING
THE LETTER.
I'M READING OFF
I'M READING OFF OF
THE LETTER.
I'M READING OFF OF HIS
I'M READING OFF OF HIS OWN
HANDWRITING.
"
" FRED
HANDWRITING.
" FRED RYAN
" FRED RYAN TOLD
HANDWRITING.
" FRED RYAN TOLD ME
" FRED RYAN TOLD ME OF
HANDWRITING.
" FRED RYAN TOLD ME OF YOUR
CONVERSATION,
CONVERSATION, AND
" FRED RYAN TOLD ME OF YOUR
CONVERSATION, AND I
CONVERSATION, AND I KNOW
" FRED RYAN TOLD ME OF YOUR
CONVERSATION, AND I KNOW YOU
WERE
WERE THINKING
CONVERSATION, AND I KNOW YOU
WERE THINKING VERY
WERE THINKING VERY CAREFULLY
ABOUT
ABOUT THE
WERE THINKING VERY CAREFULLY
ABOUT THE ASSAULT
ABOUT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
WERE THINKING VERY CAREFULLY
ABOUT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BILL.
AS
AS A
ABOUT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BILL.
AS A LONGTIME
AS A LONGTIME GUN
ABOUT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BILL.
AS A LONGTIME GUN OWNER
AS A LONGTIME GUN OWNER AND
SUPPORTER
SUPPORTER OF
AS A LONGTIME GUN OWNER AND
SUPPORTER OF THE
SUPPORTER OF THE RIGHT
AS A LONGTIME GUN OWNER AND
SUPPORTER OF THE RIGHT TO
SUPPORTER OF THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS,
ARMS, I
SUPPORTER OF THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS, I TOO
ARMS, I TOO HAVE
SUPPORTER OF THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS, I TOO HAVE CAREFULLY
THOUGHT
THOUGHT ABOUT
ARMS, I TOO HAVE CAREFULLY
THOUGHT ABOUT THIS
THOUGHT ABOUT THIS ISSUE.
I'M
I'M CONVINCED
THOUGHT ABOUT THIS ISSUE.
I'M CONVINCED THAT
I'M CONVINCED THAT THE
LIMITATIONS
LIMITATIONS IMPOSED
I'M CONVINCED THAT THE
LIMITATIONS IMPOSED IN
LIMITATIONS IMPOSED IN THIS
I'M CONVINCED THAT THE
LIMITATIONS IMPOSED IN THIS BILL
ARE
ARE ABSOLUTELY
LIMITATIONS IMPOSED IN THIS BILL
ARE ABSOLUTELY NECESSARY.
I
I KNOW
ARE ABSOLUTELY NECESSARY.
I KNOW THERE'S
I KNOW THERE'S A
ARE ABSOLUTELY NECESSARY.
I KNOW THERE'S A HEAVY
I KNOW THERE'S A HEAVY PRESSURE
ON
ON YOU
I KNOW THERE'S A HEAVY PRESSURE
ON YOU TO
ON YOU TO GO
I KNOW THERE'S A HEAVY PRESSURE
ON YOU TO GO THE
ON YOU TO GO THE OTHER
I KNOW THERE'S A HEAVY PRESSURE
ON YOU TO GO THE OTHER WAY.
BUT
BUT I
ON YOU TO GO THE OTHER WAY.
BUT I STRONGLY
BUT I STRONGLY URGE
ON YOU TO GO THE OTHER WAY.
BUT I STRONGLY URGE YOU
BUT I STRONGLY URGE YOU TO
ON YOU TO GO THE OTHER WAY.
BUT I STRONGLY URGE YOU TO JOIN
ME
ME IN
BUT I STRONGLY URGE YOU TO JOIN
ME IN SUPPORTING
ME IN SUPPORTING THIS
BUT I STRONGLY URGE YOU TO JOIN
ME IN SUPPORTING THIS BILL.
IT
IT MUST
ME IN SUPPORTING THIS BILL.
IT MUST BE
IT MUST BE PASSED.
SINCERELY,
SINCERELY, RONALD
IT MUST BE PASSED.
SINCERELY, RONALD REAGAN.
"
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> I'VE
[APPLAUSE]
>> I'VE WATCHED
>> I'VE WATCHED HILLARY
[APPLAUSE]
>> I'VE WATCHED HILLARY AND
>> I'VE WATCHED HILLARY AND HER
HUSBAND
HUSBAND BILL
>> I'VE WATCHED HILLARY AND HER
HUSBAND BILL WORKED
HUSBAND BILL WORKED WITH
>> I'VE WATCHED HILLARY AND HER
HUSBAND BILL WORKED WITH PEOPLE
ON
ON BOTH
HUSBAND BILL WORKED WITH PEOPLE
ON BOTH SIDES
ON BOTH SIDES OF
HUSBAND BILL WORKED WITH PEOPLE
ON BOTH SIDES OF THE
ON BOTH SIDES OF THE AISLE
HUSBAND BILL WORKED WITH PEOPLE
ON BOTH SIDES OF THE AISLE FOR
NEARLY
NEARLY 30
ON BOTH SIDES OF THE AISLE FOR
NEARLY 30 YEARS.
SHE
SHE IS
NEARLY 30 YEARS.
SHE IS SOMEONE
SHE IS SOMEONE WHO
NEARLY 30 YEARS.
SHE IS SOMEONE WHO IS
SHE IS SOMEONE WHO IS GOING
NEARLY 30 YEARS.
SHE IS SOMEONE WHO IS GOING TO
SOLVE
SOLVE THIS
SHE IS SOMEONE WHO IS GOING TO
SOLVE THIS PROBLEM.
SHE
SHE IS
SOLVE THIS PROBLEM.
SHE IS GOING
SHE IS GOING TO
SOLVE THIS PROBLEM.
SHE IS GOING TO BE
SHE IS GOING TO BE A
SOLVE THIS PROBLEM.
SHE IS GOING TO BE A LEADER
SHE IS GOING TO BE A LEADER WHO
WILL
WILL MAKE
SHE IS GOING TO BE A LEADER WHO
WILL MAKE THIS
WILL MAKE THIS PROBLEM
ULTIMATELY,
ULTIMATELY, GO
WILL MAKE THIS PROBLEM
ULTIMATELY, GO AWAY.
I
I HAVE
ULTIMATELY, GO AWAY.
I HAVE EVERY
I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE
ULTIMATELY, GO AWAY.
I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE THAT
I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE THAT AS
OUR
OUR PRESIDENT,
I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE THAT AS
OUR PRESIDENT, HILLARY,
OUR PRESIDENT, HILLARY, YOU
I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE THAT AS
OUR PRESIDENT, HILLARY, YOU WILL
BE
BE ABLE
OUR PRESIDENT, HILLARY, YOU WILL
BE ABLE TO
BE ABLE TO TACKLE
OUR PRESIDENT, HILLARY, YOU WILL
BE ABLE TO TACKLE THIS
BE ABLE TO TACKLE THIS PROBLEM
THAT
THAT WE
BE ABLE TO TACKLE THIS PROBLEM
THAT WE BEGAN
THAT WE BEGAN TRYING
BE ABLE TO TACKLE THIS PROBLEM
THAT WE BEGAN TRYING TO
THAT WE BEGAN TRYING TO TACKLE
BACK
BACK IN
THAT WE BEGAN TRYING TO TACKLE
BACK IN THE
BACK IN THE 1990'S.
AND
AND I'M
BACK IN THE 1990'S.
AND I'M SO
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL
BACK IN THE 1990'S.
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP,
LEADERSHIP, AND
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP, AND I
LEADERSHIP, AND I LOOK
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP, AND I LOOK FORWARD
TO
TO SUPPORTING
LEADERSHIP, AND I LOOK FORWARD
TO SUPPORTING YOU
TO SUPPORTING YOU IN
LEADERSHIP, AND I LOOK FORWARD
TO SUPPORTING YOU IN THE
UPCOMING
UPCOMING ELECTIONS.
THANK
THANK YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU,
THANK
THANK YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU,
THANK YOU VERY
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL,
WELL, WE
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL, WE HAVE
WELL, WE HAVE A
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL, WE HAVE A LOT
WELL, WE HAVE A LOT TO
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL, WE HAVE A LOT TO TALK
ABOUT,
ABOUT, THAT'S
WELL, WE HAVE A LOT TO TALK
ABOUT, THAT'S FOR
ABOUT, THAT'S FOR SURE.
THIS
THIS GENTLEMAN
ABOUT, THAT'S FOR SURE.
THIS GENTLEMAN IN
THIS GENTLEMAN IN THE
ABOUT, THAT'S FOR SURE.
THIS GENTLEMAN IN THE GREEN
SHIRT.
TO
TO >>
SHIRT.
TO >> THANK
TO >> THANK YOU.
WE
WE ARE
TO >> THANK YOU.
WE ARE ALL
WE ARE ALL THE
TO >> THANK YOU.
WE ARE ALL THE WAY
WE ARE ALL THE WAY FROM
TO >> THANK YOU.
WE ARE ALL THE WAY FROM ARIZONA,
I
I GREW
WE ARE ALL THE WAY FROM ARIZONA,
I GREW UP
I GREW UP IN
WE ARE ALL THE WAY FROM ARIZONA,
I GREW UP IN TUCSON,
I GREW UP IN TUCSON, ARIZONA.
I
I AM
I GREW UP IN TUCSON, ARIZONA.
I AM A
I AM A GUN
I GREW UP IN TUCSON, ARIZONA.
I AM A GUN OWNER
I AM A GUN OWNER AND
I GREW UP IN TUCSON, ARIZONA.
I AM A GUN OWNER AND THE
I AM A GUN OWNER AND THE SUPPORT
OF
OF THE
I AM A GUN OWNER AND THE SUPPORT
OF THE SECOND
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
ESPECIALLY
ESPECIALLY WITH
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
ESPECIALLY WITH MENTAL
ESPECIALLY WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
AS
AS YOU
ESPECIALLY WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
AS YOU KNOW,
AS YOU KNOW, IN
ESPECIALLY WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON,
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON, WE
ESPECIALLY WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON, WE HAD
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON, WE HAD A
PERSON
PERSON WHO
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON, WE HAD A
PERSON WHO HAD
PERSON WHO HAD ALL
AS YOU KNOW, IN TUCSON, WE HAD A
PERSON WHO HAD ALL KINDS
PERSON WHO HAD ALL KINDS OF
TROUBLE
TROUBLE AND
PERSON WHO HAD ALL KINDS OF
TROUBLE AND WAS
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE
PERSON WHO HAD ALL KINDS OF
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE TO
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE TO BUY
PERSON WHO HAD ALL KINDS OF
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE TO BUY A
GUN,
GUN, AS
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE TO BUY A
GUN, AS YOU
GUN, AS YOU SAID,
TROUBLE AND WAS ABLE TO BUY A
GUN, AS YOU SAID, VIRGINIA
GUN, AS YOU SAID, VIRGINIA TECH,
LOUISIANA,
LOUISIANA, THAT
GUN, AS YOU SAID, VIRGINIA TECH,
LOUISIANA, THAT PERSON
LOUISIANA, THAT PERSON HAD
GUN, AS YOU SAID, VIRGINIA TECH,
LOUISIANA, THAT PERSON HAD BEEN
COMMITTED.
AUTO
AUTO FROM
COMMITTED.
AUTO FROM A
AUTO FROM A GUN
COMMITTED.
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER,
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER, FROM
COMMITTED.
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER, FROM A
RED
RED STATE,
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER, FROM A
RED STATE, AND
RED STATE, AND A
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER, FROM A
RED STATE, AND A PERSON
RED STATE, AND A PERSON WHO
AUTO FROM A GUN OWNER, FROM A
RED STATE, AND A PERSON WHO OWNS
GUNS,
GUNS, MORE
RED STATE, AND A PERSON WHO OWNS
GUNS, MORE POWER
GUNS, MORE POWER TO
RED STATE, AND A PERSON WHO OWNS
GUNS, MORE POWER TO YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
THANK
THANK YOU.
YES,
YES, THE
THANK YOU.
YES, THE LADY
YES, THE LADY RIGHT
THANK YOU.
YES, THE LADY RIGHT HERE.
HERE
HERE COMES
YES, THE LADY RIGHT HERE.
HERE COMES THE
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>>
>> THANKS
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>> THANKS FOR
>> THANKS FOR PICKING
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>> THANKS FOR PICKING ON
>> THANKS FOR PICKING ON ME.
I
I HAVE
>> THANKS FOR PICKING ON ME.
I HAVE A
I HAVE A QUESTION
>> THANKS FOR PICKING ON ME.
I HAVE A QUESTION ABOUT
I HAVE A QUESTION ABOUT THE
>> THANKS FOR PICKING ON ME.
I HAVE A QUESTION ABOUT THE CDC,
AND
AND RESEARCH
I HAVE A QUESTION ABOUT THE CDC,
AND RESEARCH THAT
AND RESEARCH THAT WAS
I HAVE A QUESTION ABOUT THE CDC,
AND RESEARCH THAT WAS CUT
AND RESEARCH THAT WAS CUT OFF
EARLY
EARLY IN
AND RESEARCH THAT WAS CUT OFF
EARLY IN THE
EARLY IN THE 90'S
AND RESEARCH THAT WAS CUT OFF
EARLY IN THE 90'S BY
EARLY IN THE 90'S BY THE
REPUBLICAN
REPUBLICAN PARTY.
I
I THINK
REPUBLICAN PARTY.
I THINK THAT
I THINK THAT IF
REPUBLICAN PARTY.
I THINK THAT IF YOU
I THINK THAT IF YOU CAN
REPUBLICAN PARTY.
I THINK THAT IF YOU CAN BRING
THAT
THAT BACK,
I THINK THAT IF YOU CAN BRING
THAT BACK, IF
THAT BACK, IF WE
I THINK THAT IF YOU CAN BRING
THAT BACK, IF WE COULD
THAT BACK, IF WE COULD CONVINCE
LEGISLATURE
LEGISLATURE TO
THAT BACK, IF WE COULD CONVINCE
LEGISLATURE TO FUND
LEGISLATURE TO FUND RESEARCH
INTO
INTO GUN
LEGISLATURE TO FUND RESEARCH
INTO GUN VIOLENCE,
INTO GUN VIOLENCE, WHAT
LEGISLATURE TO FUND RESEARCH
INTO GUN VIOLENCE, WHAT CAUSES
IT
IT --
INTO GUN VIOLENCE, WHAT CAUSES
IT -- I
IT -- I THINK
INTO GUN VIOLENCE, WHAT CAUSES
IT -- I THINK WE'RE
IT -- I THINK WE'RE HITTING
INTO GUN VIOLENCE, WHAT CAUSES
IT -- I THINK WE'RE HITTING A
LOT
LOT OF
IT -- I THINK WE'RE HITTING A
LOT OF MARKS
LOT OF MARKS WITH
IT -- I THINK WE'RE HITTING A
LOT OF MARKS WITH THAT
LOT OF MARKS WITH THAT BECAUSE
WE
WE ARE
LOT OF MARKS WITH THAT BECAUSE
WE ARE GETTING
WE ARE GETTING MENTAL
LOT OF MARKS WITH THAT BECAUSE
WE ARE GETTING MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES,
ISSUES, WE
WE ARE GETTING MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES, WE ARE
ISSUES, WE ARE GETTING
WE ARE GETTING MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES, WE ARE GETTING WHAT
ISSUES, WE ARE GETTING WHAT ROLE
GUNS
GUNS PLAY,
ISSUES, WE ARE GETTING WHAT ROLE
GUNS PLAY, HOW
GUNS PLAY, HOW QUICKLY
ISSUES, WE ARE GETTING WHAT ROLE
GUNS PLAY, HOW QUICKLY PEOPLE
CAN
CAN OFF
GUNS PLAY, HOW QUICKLY PEOPLE
CAN OFF SOMEONE
CAN OFF SOMEONE WITH
GUNS PLAY, HOW QUICKLY PEOPLE
CAN OFF SOMEONE WITH A
CAN OFF SOMEONE WITH A GUN
GUNS PLAY, HOW QUICKLY PEOPLE
CAN OFF SOMEONE WITH A GUN WHEN
THEY
THEY WANT
CAN OFF SOMEONE WITH A GUN WHEN
THEY WANT TO.
IF
IF WE
THEY WANT TO.
IF WE CAN
IF WE CAN JUST
THEY WANT TO.
IF WE CAN JUST ANALYZE
IF WE CAN JUST ANALYZE THAT
DATA,
DATA, I
IF WE CAN JUST ANALYZE THAT
DATA, I THINK
DATA, I THINK WE
IF WE CAN JUST ANALYZE THAT
DATA, I THINK WE WILL
DATA, I THINK WE WILL BE
IF WE CAN JUST ANALYZE THAT
DATA, I THINK WE WILL BE A
DATA, I THINK WE WILL BE A LOT
BETTER
BETTER PLACE.
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
BETTER PLACE.
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I AGREE
BETTER PLACE.
HILLARY CLINTON: I AGREE WITH
YOU.
WHAT
WHAT SHE
YOU.
WHAT SHE IS
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING
YOU.
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING TO
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING TO IS
YOU.
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING TO IS THAT
THE
THE CENTERS
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING TO IS THAT
THE CENTERS FOR
THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE
WHAT SHE IS REFERRING TO IS THAT
THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL
IS
IS RESPONSIBLE
THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR LOOKING
THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR LOOKING AT
PUBLIC
PUBLIC HEALTH
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR LOOKING AT
PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUES.
IF
IF THERE
PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUES.
IF THERE IS
IF THERE IS DIRTY
PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUES.
IF THERE IS DIRTY WATER
IF THERE IS DIRTY WATER THAT
PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUES.
IF THERE IS DIRTY WATER THAT IS
MAKING
MAKING PEOPLE
IF THERE IS DIRTY WATER THAT IS
MAKING PEOPLE SICK,
MAKING PEOPLE SICK, WE
IF THERE IS DIRTY WATER THAT IS
MAKING PEOPLE SICK, WE ARE
EXPECTING
EXPECTING THEM
MAKING PEOPLE SICK, WE ARE
EXPECTING THEM TO
EXPECTING THEM TO TELL
MAKING PEOPLE SICK, WE ARE
EXPECTING THEM TO TELL US
EXPECTING THEM TO TELL US WHAT
TO
TO DO
EXPECTING THEM TO TELL US WHAT
TO DO TO
TO DO TO PREVENT
EXPECTING THEM TO TELL US WHAT
TO DO TO PREVENT THAT.
SO,
SO, THEY
TO DO TO PREVENT THAT.
SO, THEY WERE
SO, THEY WERE RESEARCHING
TO DO TO PREVENT THAT.
SO, THEY WERE RESEARCHING GUN
AND
AND VIOLENCE
SO, THEY WERE RESEARCHING GUN
AND VIOLENCE AND
AND VIOLENCE AND TRYING
SO, THEY WERE RESEARCHING GUN
AND VIOLENCE AND TRYING TO
FIGURE
FIGURE OUT
AND VIOLENCE AND TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHO
FIGURE OUT WHO IS
AND VIOLENCE AND TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHO IS MORE
FIGURE OUT WHO IS MORE LIKELY
AND VIOLENCE AND TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHO IS MORE LIKELY TO
COMMIT'S
COMMIT'S VIOLENCE?
WHAT
WHAT KINDS
COMMIT'S VIOLENCE?
WHAT KINDS OF
WHAT KINDS OF WARNING
COMMIT'S VIOLENCE?
WHAT KINDS OF WARNING SIGNS
MIGHT
MIGHT THERE
WHAT KINDS OF WARNING SIGNS
MIGHT THERE BE?
AND
AND FOR
MIGHT THERE BE?
AND FOR VERY
AND FOR VERY SAD
MIGHT THERE BE?
AND FOR VERY SAD REASONS,
BASICALLY,
BASICALLY, YOU'RE
AND FOR VERY SAD REASONS,
BASICALLY, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE
THE REPUBLICANS
BASICALLY, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE REPUBLICANS STOPPED
THE REPUBLICANS STOPPED THE
RESEARCH.
IT
IT EVEN
RESEARCH.
IT EVEN GOES
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER
RESEARCH.
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER THAN
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER THAN THAT.
THERE
THERE IS
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER THAN THAT.
THERE IS A
THERE IS A LAW
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER THAN THAT.
THERE IS A LAW IN
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA
IT EVEN GOES FURTHER THAN THAT.
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA --
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA -- I
WANT
WANT YOU
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA -- I
WANT YOU TO
WANT YOU TO HEAR
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA -- I
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS BECAUSE
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA -- I
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS BECAUSE IT
WAS
WAS SO
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS BECAUSE IT
WAS SO SHOCKING
WAS SO SHOCKING AT
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS BECAUSE IT
WAS SO SHOCKING AT FIRST
WAS SO SHOCKING AT FIRST THAT
WANT YOU TO HEAR THIS BECAUSE IT
WAS SO SHOCKING AT FIRST THAT I
REALLY
REALLY DIDN'T
WAS SO SHOCKING AT FIRST THAT I
REALLY DIDN'T BELIEVE
REALLY DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE
THERE IS
REALLY DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE IS A
THERE IS A LAW
REALLY DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE IS A LAW IN
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA
REALLY DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA THAT
MAKES
MAKES IT
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA THAT
MAKES IT A
MAKES IT A FELONY
THERE IS A LAW IN FLORIDA THAT
MAKES IT A FELONY FOR
MAKES IT A FELONY FOR A
PEDIATRICIAN
PEDIATRICIAN TO
MAKES IT A FELONY FOR A
PEDIATRICIAN TO TALK
PEDIATRICIAN TO TALK WITH
FAMILIES
FAMILIES ABOUT
PEDIATRICIAN TO TALK WITH
FAMILIES ABOUT BEING
FAMILIES ABOUT BEING SURE
PEDIATRICIAN TO TALK WITH
FAMILIES ABOUT BEING SURE THEY
KEEP
KEEP GUNS
FAMILIES ABOUT BEING SURE THEY
KEEP GUNS SAFELY
KEEP GUNS SAFELY AWAY
FAMILIES ABOUT BEING SURE THEY
KEEP GUNS SAFELY AWAY FROM
CHILDREN.
LITERALLY,
LITERALLY, A
CHILDREN.
LITERALLY, A DOCTOR
LITERALLY, A DOCTOR CAN
CHILDREN.
LITERALLY, A DOCTOR CAN GO
LITERALLY, A DOCTOR CAN GO TO
JAIL
JAIL IN
LITERALLY, A DOCTOR CAN GO TO
JAIL IN FLORIDA.
IF
IF YOU
JAIL IN FLORIDA.
IF YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE A
JAIL IN FLORIDA.
IF YOU ARE A PEDIATRICIAN,
IF YOU ARE A PEDIATRICIAN, AND
YOU
YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE A PEDIATRICIAN, AND
YOU ARE RUNNING
YOU ARE RUNNING THROUGH
CHECKLISTS,
CHECKLISTS, ARE
YOU ARE RUNNING THROUGH
CHECKLISTS, ARE YOU
CHECKLISTS, ARE YOU KEEPING
YOU ARE RUNNING THROUGH
CHECKLISTS, ARE YOU KEEPING THE
HOUSEHOLD
HOUSEHOLD POISONS
CHECKLISTS, ARE YOU KEEPING THE
HOUSEHOLD POISONS OUT
HOUSEHOLD POISONS OUT OF
CHECKLISTS, ARE YOU KEEPING THE
HOUSEHOLD POISONS OUT OF THE
WAVE
WAVE YOUR
HOUSEHOLD POISONS OUT OF THE
WAVE YOUR KIDS?
ESPECIALLY
ESPECIALLY IF
WAVE YOUR KIDS?
ESPECIALLY IF YOU
ESPECIALLY IF YOU HAVE
WAVE YOUR KIDS?
ESPECIALLY IF YOU HAVE TODDLERS
EXPLORING
EXPLORING EVERYTHING.
YOU
YOU MAKE
EXPLORING EVERYTHING.
YOU MAKE SURE
YOU MAKE SURE YOUR
EXPLORING EVERYTHING.
YOU MAKE SURE YOUR SHARP
YOU MAKE SURE YOUR SHARP KNIVES
ARE
ARE KEPT
YOU MAKE SURE YOUR SHARP KNIVES
ARE KEPT AWAY,
ARE KEPT AWAY, ARE
YOU MAKE SURE YOUR SHARP KNIVES
ARE KEPT AWAY, ARE THEY
ARE KEPT AWAY, ARE THEY HIGH
ENOUGH
ENOUGH UP
ARE KEPT AWAY, ARE THEY HIGH
ENOUGH UP SO
ENOUGH UP SO KIDS
ARE KEPT AWAY, ARE THEY HIGH
ENOUGH UP SO KIDS CAN'T
ACCIDENTALLY
ACCIDENTALLY GET
ENOUGH UP SO KIDS CAN'T
ACCIDENTALLY GET THEM?
IT
IT SEEMS
ACCIDENTALLY GET THEM?
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY REASONABLE
ACCIDENTALLY GET THEM?
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY REASONABLE TO
ME
ME TO
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY REASONABLE TO
ME TO SAY
ME TO SAY IF
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY REASONABLE TO
ME TO SAY IF YOU
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE
IT SEEMS PERFECTLY REASONABLE TO
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE GUNS
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE GUNS IN
THE
THE HOUSE,
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE GUNS IN
THE HOUSE, ARE
THE HOUSE, ARE YOU
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE GUNS IN
THE HOUSE, ARE YOU SURE
THE HOUSE, ARE YOU SURE THEY
ME TO SAY IF YOU HAVE GUNS IN
THE HOUSE, ARE YOU SURE THEY ARE
REALLY
REALLY SECURE?
BECAUSE
BECAUSE TOO
REALLY SECURE?
BECAUSE TOO MANY
BECAUSE TOO MANY LITTLE
REALLY SECURE?
BECAUSE TOO MANY LITTLE KIDS
BECAUSE TOO MANY LITTLE KIDS GET
A
A HOLD
BECAUSE TOO MANY LITTLE KIDS GET
A HOLD OF
A HOLD OF THEM.
WE
WE READ
A HOLD OF THEM.
WE READ ABOUT
WE READ ABOUT IT
A HOLD OF THEM.
WE READ ABOUT IT EVERY
WE READ ABOUT IT EVERY WEEK.
THEY
THEY KILL
WE READ ABOUT IT EVERY WEEK.
THEY KILL THEMSELVES,
THEY KILL THEMSELVES, THEY
WE READ ABOUT IT EVERY WEEK.
THEY KILL THEMSELVES, THEY KILL
THEIR
THEIR FRIENDS.
I
I THINK
THEIR FRIENDS.
I THINK IT
I THINK IT IS
THEIR FRIENDS.
I THINK IT IS A
I THINK IT IS A DOCTOR'S
RESPONSIBILITY
RESPONSIBILITY TO
I THINK IT IS A DOCTOR'S
RESPONSIBILITY TO TRY
RESPONSIBILITY TO TRY TO
I THINK IT IS A DOCTOR'S
RESPONSIBILITY TO TRY TO WORK
WITH
WITH THE
RESPONSIBILITY TO TRY TO WORK
WITH THE FAMILY
WITH THE FAMILY SO
RESPONSIBILITY TO TRY TO WORK
WITH THE FAMILY SO THAT
WITH THE FAMILY SO THAT THE
FAMILY
FAMILY CAN
WITH THE FAMILY SO THAT THE
FAMILY CAN TRY
FAMILY CAN TRY AND
WITH THE FAMILY SO THAT THE
FAMILY CAN TRY AND KEEP
FAMILY CAN TRY AND KEEP THEIR
BABIES
BABIES SAFE.
IF
IF YOU
BABIES SAFE.
IF YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE IN
BABIES SAFE.
IF YOU ARE IN FLORIDA,
IF YOU ARE IN FLORIDA, YOU
BABIES SAFE.
IF YOU ARE IN FLORIDA, YOU COULD
GO
GO TO
IF YOU ARE IN FLORIDA, YOU COULD
GO TO JAIL.
I
I WANT
GO TO JAIL.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO MAKE
GO TO JAIL.
I WANT TO MAKE THE
I WANT TO MAKE THE ARGUMENT
GO TO JAIL.
I WANT TO MAKE THE ARGUMENT AND
YOU
YOU WILL
I WANT TO MAKE THE ARGUMENT AND
YOU WILL WORK
YOU WILL WORK TOWARDS
I WANT TO MAKE THE ARGUMENT AND
YOU WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
AND
AND WILL
YOU WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
AND WILL WORK
AND WILL WORK TOWARDS
YOU WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
AND WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
RESULTS
RESULTS THAT
AND WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
RESULTS THAT WE
RESULTS THAT WE CAN
AND WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
RESULTS THAT WE CAN LEARN
RESULTS THAT WE CAN LEARN A
AND WILL WORK TOWARDS THE
RESULTS THAT WE CAN LEARN A LOT
MORE
MORE ABOUT
RESULTS THAT WE CAN LEARN A LOT
MORE ABOUT WHAT
MORE ABOUT WHAT ARE
RESULTS THAT WE CAN LEARN A LOT
MORE ABOUT WHAT ARE THE
CHARACTERISTICS
CHARACTERISTICS OF
MORE ABOUT WHAT ARE THE
CHARACTERISTICS OF PEOPLE
CHARACTERISTICS OF PEOPLE WHO
SHOULD
SHOULD NOT
CHARACTERISTICS OF PEOPLE WHO
SHOULD NOT HAVE
SHOULD NOT HAVE GUNS?
IN
IN YOUR
SHOULD NOT HAVE GUNS?
IN YOUR AS
IN YOUR AS WE
SHOULD NOT HAVE GUNS?
IN YOUR AS WE WERE
IN YOUR AS WE WERE JUST
SHOULD NOT HAVE GUNS?
IN YOUR AS WE WERE JUST HEARING
YOU
YOU R-ARIZONA
IN YOUR AS WE WERE JUST HEARING
YOU R-ARIZONA AND
YOU R-ARIZONA AND OR
IN YOUR AS WE WERE JUST HEARING
YOU R-ARIZONA AND OR FROM
YOU R-ARIZONA AND OR FROM THE
GENTLEMAN
GENTLEMAN FROM
YOU R-ARIZONA AND OR FROM THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA,
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA, AS
YOU R-ARIZONA AND OR FROM THE
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA, AS WE
AND
AND YOU
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA, AS WE
AND YOU ARE
AND YOU ARE GENTLEMAN
GENTLEMAN FROM ARIZONA, AS WE
AND YOU ARE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA,
ARIZONA, AS
AND YOU ARE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, AS WE
ARIZONA, AS WE ARE
AND YOU ARE GENTLEMAN FROM
ARIZONA, AS WE ARE LEARNING
YOU
YOU MORE,
ARIZONA, AS WE ARE LEARNING
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY WHAT
ARIZONA, AS WE ARE LEARNING
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY WHAT WE
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY WHAT WE KNOW
ABOUT
ABOUT THE
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY WHAT WE KNOW
ABOUT THE KILLER
ABOUT THE KILLER FROM
YOU MORE, CERTAINLY WHAT WE KNOW
ABOUT THE KILLER FROM SANDY
HOOK,
HOOK, NOW
ABOUT THE KILLER FROM SANDY
HOOK, NOW THE
HOOK, NOW THE KILLER
ABOUT THE KILLER FROM SANDY
HOOK, NOW THE KILLER FROM
WILL
WILL AND
HOOK, NOW THE KILLER FROM
WILL AND OREGON,
WILL AND OREGON, THERE
HOOK, NOW THE KILLER FROM
WILL AND OREGON, THERE PROBABLY
WERE
WERE SOME
WILL AND OREGON, THERE PROBABLY
WERE SOME COMMENTS,
WERE SOME COMMENTS, SOME
WILL AND OREGON, THERE PROBABLY
WERE SOME COMMENTS, SOME ACTIONS
THAT
THAT MIGHT
WERE SOME COMMENTS, SOME ACTIONS
THAT MIGHT HAVE
THAT MIGHT HAVE SET
WERE SOME COMMENTS, SOME ACTIONS
THAT MIGHT HAVE SET OFF
THAT MIGHT HAVE SET OFF SOME
WILL
WILL ALARMS
THAT MIGHT HAVE SET OFF SOME
WILL ALARMS AND
WILL ALARMS AND PEOPLE.
AND
AND YOU
WILL ALARMS AND PEOPLE.
AND YOU IN
AND YOU IN PEOPLE
WILL ALARMS AND PEOPLE.
AND YOU IN PEOPLE --
AND YOU IN PEOPLE -- IN
WILL ALARMS AND PEOPLE.
AND YOU IN PEOPLE -- IN PEOPLE.
BUT
BUT IF
AND YOU IN PEOPLE -- IN PEOPLE.
BUT IF WE
BUT IF WE DON'T
AND YOU IN PEOPLE -- IN PEOPLE.
BUT IF WE DON'T HAVE
BUT IF WE DON'T HAVE THE
AND YOU IN PEOPLE -- IN PEOPLE.
BUT IF WE DON'T HAVE THE GOOD
INFORMATION
INFORMATION SO
BUT IF WE DON'T HAVE THE GOOD
INFORMATION SO THAT
INFORMATION SO THAT PEOPLE
BUT IF WE DON'T HAVE THE GOOD
INFORMATION SO THAT PEOPLE CAN
BE
BE BETTER
INFORMATION SO THAT PEOPLE CAN
BE BETTER INFORMED,
BE BETTER INFORMED, HOW
INFORMATION SO THAT PEOPLE CAN
BE BETTER INFORMED, HOW DO
BE BETTER INFORMED, HOW DO WE
HELP
HELP THEM?
I
I AGREE
HELP THEM?
I AGREE WITH
I AGREE WITH YOU.
NO
NO ISSUE
I AGREE WITH YOU.
NO ISSUE SHOULD
NO ISSUE SHOULD BE
I AGREE WITH YOU.
NO ISSUE SHOULD BE BEYOND
NO ISSUE SHOULD BE BEYOND STUDY
IN
IN AMERICA.
THAT'S
THAT'S LIKE
IN AMERICA.
THAT'S LIKE A
THAT'S LIKE A DENIAL
IN AMERICA.
THAT'S LIKE A DENIAL OF
EVERYTHING
EVERYTHING WE
THAT'S LIKE A DENIAL OF
EVERYTHING WE BELIEVE
EVERYTHING WE BELIEVE IN
THAT'S LIKE A DENIAL OF
EVERYTHING WE BELIEVE IN OUR
COUNTRY.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: GOING
HILLARY CLINTON: GOING ALONG
WITH
WITH THAT,
HILLARY CLINTON: GOING ALONG
WITH THAT, SO
WITH THAT, SO FAR
HILLARY CLINTON: GOING ALONG
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS I
HILLARY CLINTON: GOING ALONG
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS I KNOW,
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS I KNOW, THE
GUN
GUN INDUSTRY
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS I KNOW, THE
GUN INDUSTRY AND
GUN INDUSTRY AND GUN
WITH THAT, SO FAR AS I KNOW, THE
GUN INDUSTRY AND GUN SELLERS
GUN INDUSTRY AND GUN SELLERS ARE
THE
THE ONLY
GUN INDUSTRY AND GUN SELLERS ARE
THE ONLY BUSINESS
THE ONLY BUSINESS IN
GUN INDUSTRY AND GUN SELLERS ARE
THE ONLY BUSINESS IN AMERICA
THAT
THAT IS
THE ONLY BUSINESS IN AMERICA
THAT IS TOTALLY
THAT IS TOTALLY FREE
THE ONLY BUSINESS IN AMERICA
THAT IS TOTALLY FREE OF
LIABILITY
LIABILITY FOR
THAT IS TOTALLY FREE OF
LIABILITY FOR THEIR
LIABILITY FOR THEIR BEHAVIOR.
NOBODY
NOBODY ELSE
LIABILITY FOR THEIR BEHAVIOR.
NOBODY ELSE IS
NOBODY ELSE IS GIVEN
LIABILITY FOR THEIR BEHAVIOR.
NOBODY ELSE IS GIVEN THAT
IMMUNITY.
AND
AND THAT
IMMUNITY.
AND THAT JUST
AND THAT JUST ILLUSTRATES
IMMUNITY.
AND THAT JUST ILLUSTRATES THE
EXTREMISM
EXTREMISM THAT
AND THAT JUST ILLUSTRATES THE
EXTREMISM THAT HAS
EXTREMISM THAT HAS TAKEN
AND THAT JUST ILLUSTRATES THE
EXTREMISM THAT HAS TAKEN OVER
THIS
THIS DEBATE.
I
I WAS
THIS DEBATE.
I WAS REALLY
I WAS REALLY STRUCK
THIS DEBATE.
I WAS REALLY STRUCK WHEN
I WAS REALLY STRUCK WHEN HE
THIS DEBATE.
I WAS REALLY STRUCK WHEN HE WAS
READING
READING THE
I WAS REALLY STRUCK WHEN HE WAS
READING THE LETTER
READING THE LETTER FROM
I WAS REALLY STRUCK WHEN HE WAS
READING THE LETTER FROM RONALD
IN
IN REAGAN.
AND
AND THE
IN REAGAN.
AND THE FACT
AND THE FACT THAT
IN REAGAN.
AND THE FACT THAT WHEN
AND THE FACT THAT WHEN HE
IN REAGAN.
AND THE FACT THAT WHEN HE WAS
FACING
FACING A
AND THE FACT THAT WHEN HE WAS
FACING A VERY
FACING A VERY HARD
AND THE FACT THAT WHEN HE WAS
FACING A VERY HARD CHOICE,
FACING A VERY HARD CHOICE, WHICH
MANY
MANY PEOPLE
FACING A VERY HARD CHOICE, WHICH
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE COST
FACING A VERY HARD CHOICE, WHICH
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE COST HIM
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE COST HIM HIS
SEAT
SEAT IN
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE COST HIM HIS
SEAT IN CONGRESS,
SEAT IN CONGRESS, BECAUSE
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE COST HIM HIS
SEAT IN CONGRESS, BECAUSE HE
WILL
WILL VOTED
SEAT IN CONGRESS, BECAUSE HE
WILL VOTED FOR
WILL VOTED FOR THE
SEAT IN CONGRESS, BECAUSE HE
WILL VOTED FOR THE CRIME
WILL VOTED FOR THE CRIME BILL
WHICH
WHICH CONTAINED
WILL VOTED FOR THE CRIME BILL
WHICH CONTAINED THE
WHICH CONTAINED THE BRADY
WILL VOTED FOR THE CRIME BILL
WHICH CONTAINED THE BRADY BILL,
WHICH
WHICH LED
WHICH CONTAINED THE BRADY BILL,
WHICH LED TO
WHICH LED TO THE
WHICH CONTAINED THE BRADY BILL,
WHICH LED TO THE BACKGROUND
CHECKS,
CHECKS, WHICH
WHICH LED TO THE BACKGROUND
CHECKS, WHICH LED
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO
WHICH LED TO THE BACKGROUND
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO MORE
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO MORE THAN
WHICH LED TO THE BACKGROUND
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO MORE THAN 2
MILLION
MILLION PEOPLE
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO MORE THAN 2
MILLION PEOPLE NOT
MILLION PEOPLE NOT GETTING
CHECKS, WHICH LED TO MORE THAN 2
MILLION PEOPLE NOT GETTING GUNS
WHO
WHO WERE
MILLION PEOPLE NOT GETTING GUNS
WHO WERE FELONS
WHO WERE FELONS OR
MILLION PEOPLE NOT GETTING GUNS
WHO WERE FELONS OR DOMESTIC
ABUSERS,
ABUSERS, OR
WHO WERE FELONS OR DOMESTIC
ABUSERS, OR OTHERWISE
ABUSERS, OR OTHERWISE INELIGIBLE
--
-- HE
ABUSERS, OR OTHERWISE INELIGIBLE
-- HE PAID
-- HE PAID A
ABUSERS, OR OTHERWISE INELIGIBLE
-- HE PAID A BIG
-- HE PAID A BIG PRICE
ABUSERS, OR OTHERWISE INELIGIBLE
-- HE PAID A BIG PRICE FOR
-- HE PAID A BIG PRICE FOR THAT.
AND
AND HERE'S
-- HE PAID A BIG PRICE FOR THAT.
AND HERE'S A
AND HERE'S A LETTER
-- HE PAID A BIG PRICE FOR THAT.
AND HERE'S A LETTER FROM
AND HERE'S A LETTER FROM RONALD
REAGAN.
IN
IN WHEN
REAGAN.
IN WHEN THE
IN WHEN THE NRA
REAGAN.
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS ON
REAGAN.
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS ON ONE
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS ON ONE OF
AN
AN THEIR
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS ON ONE OF
AN THEIR TIRADES,
AN THEIR TIRADES, CALLING
IN WHEN THE NRA WAS ON ONE OF
AN THEIR TIRADES, CALLING THE
IS
IS AN
AN THEIR TIRADES, CALLING THE
IS AN ALCOHOL
IS AN ALCOHOL TOBACCO
AN THEIR TIRADES, CALLING THE
IS AN ALCOHOL TOBACCO AND
WILL
WILL ARE
IS AN ALCOHOL TOBACCO AND
WILL ARE YOU
WILL ARE YOU AS
IS AN ALCOHOL TOBACCO AND
WILL ARE YOU AS YOU
WILL ARE YOU AS YOU YOU
IS AN ALCOHOL TOBACCO AND
WILL ARE YOU AS YOU YOU ARE
FIREARMS
FIREARMS ENFORCERS
WILL ARE YOU AS YOU YOU ARE
FIREARMS ENFORCERS JACKBOOTED
YOU
YOU THUGS,
FIREARMS ENFORCERS JACKBOOTED
YOU THUGS, PRESIDENT
YOU THUGS, PRESIDENT GEORGE
FIREARMS ENFORCERS JACKBOOTED
YOU THUGS, PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
AND
AND BUSH
YOU THUGS, PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
AND BUSH RESIGNED
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS
YOU THUGS, PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS AN
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS AN NRA
WILL
WILL MEMBER
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS AN NRA
WILL MEMBER AND
WILL MEMBER AND SAID
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS AN NRA
WILL MEMBER AND SAID NO,
WILL MEMBER AND SAID NO, I'M
AND BUSH RESIGNED AS AN NRA
WILL MEMBER AND SAID NO, I'M NOT
GOING
GOING TO
WILL MEMBER AND SAID NO, I'M NOT
GOING TO BE
GOING TO BE ASSOCIATED
WILL MEMBER AND SAID NO, I'M NOT
GOING TO BE ASSOCIATED WITH
THAT.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY,
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY, WHAT
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY, WHAT I
WOULD
WOULD LOVE
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY, WHAT I
WOULD LOVE TO
WOULD LOVE TO SEE
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY, WHAT I
WOULD LOVE TO SEE IS
WOULD LOVE TO SEE IS GUN
HILLARY CLINTON: IDEALLY, WHAT I
WOULD LOVE TO SEE IS GUN OWNERS,
RESPONSIBLE
RESPONSIBLE GUN
WOULD LOVE TO SEE IS GUN OWNERS,
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS,
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS, FORM
WOULD LOVE TO SEE IS GUN OWNERS,
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS, FORM A
DIFFERENT
DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS, FORM A
DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION AND
DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION AND TAKE
BACK
BACK THE
DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION AND TAKE
BACK THE SECOND
BACK THE SECOND AMENDMENT
DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION AND TAKE
BACK THE SECOND AMENDMENT FROM
THESE
THESE EXTREMISTS.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: OK.
[LAUGHTER]
THANK
THANK YOU.
THIS
THIS LADY
THANK YOU.
THIS LADY RIGHT
THIS LADY RIGHT THERE.
HERE
HERE COMES
THIS LADY RIGHT THERE.
HERE COMES THE
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>>
>> I'M
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>> I'M SO
>> I'M SO GLAD
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>> I'M SO GLAD TO
>> I'M SO GLAD TO SEE
HERE COMES THE MICROPHONE.
>> I'M SO GLAD TO SEE YOU,
>> I'M SO GLAD TO SEE YOU, MRS.
YOU
YOU CLINTON.
I
I KNOW
YOU CLINTON.
I KNOW THIS
I KNOW THIS IS
YOU CLINTON.
I KNOW THIS IS A
I KNOW THIS IS A BIG
YOU CLINTON.
I KNOW THIS IS A BIG ISSUE
I KNOW THIS IS A BIG ISSUE IN
THE
THE UNITED
I KNOW THIS IS A BIG ISSUE IN
THE UNITED STATES,
THE UNITED STATES, BUT
I KNOW THIS IS A BIG ISSUE IN
THE UNITED STATES, BUT I'M
THE UNITED STATES, BUT I'M FROM
YOU
YOU THE
THE UNITED STATES, BUT I'M FROM
YOU THE UNITED
YOU THE UNITED STATES,
THE UNITED STATES, BUT I'M FROM
YOU THE UNITED STATES, BUT
YOU THE UNITED STATES, BUT I'M
FROM
FROM AFGHANISTAN.
I'M
I'M THINKING
FROM AFGHANISTAN.
I'M THINKING ABOUT
I'M THINKING ABOUT MY
FROM AFGHANISTAN.
I'M THINKING ABOUT MY COUNTRY,
EVERY
EVERY DAY,
I'M THINKING ABOUT MY COUNTRY,
EVERY DAY, MORE
EVERY DAY, MORE THAN
I'M THINKING ABOUT MY COUNTRY,
EVERY DAY, MORE THAN 200
EVERY DAY, MORE THAN 200 OR
I'M THINKING ABOUT MY COUNTRY,
EVERY DAY, MORE THAN 200 OR 300
PEOPLE
PEOPLE DIED
EVERY DAY, MORE THAN 200 OR 300
PEOPLE DIED OVER
PEOPLE DIED OVER THERE.
PEOPLE
PEOPLE DIED
PEOPLE DIED OVER THERE.
PEOPLE DIED OVER
I
PEOPLE DIED OVER THERE.
I WANT
I WANT TO
PEOPLE DIED OVER THERE.
I WANT TO KNOW
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT
PEOPLE DIED OVER THERE.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOUR
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOUR OPINION
AFTER
AFTER YOU
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOUR OPINION
AFTER YOU BECOME
AFTER YOU BECOME PRESIDENT
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOUR OPINION
AFTER YOU BECOME PRESIDENT OF
THE
THE UNITED
AFTER YOU BECOME PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES,
THE UNITED STATES, DO
AFTER YOU BECOME PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES, DO YOU
THE UNITED STATES, DO YOU WANT
TO
TO PULL
THE UNITED STATES, DO YOU WANT
TO PULL OUT
TO PULL OUT ALL
THE UNITED STATES, DO YOU WANT
TO PULL OUT ALL UNITED
TO PULL OUT ALL UNITED STATES
SOLDIERS
SOLDIERS OR
TO PULL OUT ALL UNITED STATES
SOLDIERS OR ARE
SOLDIERS OR ARE YOU
TO PULL OUT ALL UNITED STATES
SOLDIERS OR ARE YOU THINKING
THEY
THEY ARE
SOLDIERS OR ARE YOU THINKING
THEY ARE GOING
THEY ARE GOING TO
SOLDIERS OR ARE YOU THINKING
THEY ARE GOING TO STAY
THEY ARE GOING TO STAY THERE?
HER
HER WE
THEY ARE GOING TO STAY THERE?
HER WE WANTED
HER WE WANTED THEM
THEY ARE GOING TO STAY THERE?
HER WE WANTED THEM TO
HER WE WANTED THEM TO STAY
THEY ARE GOING TO STAY THERE?
HER WE WANTED THEM TO STAY THERE
FOR
FOR AFGHANISTAN,
HER WE WANTED THEM TO STAY THERE
FOR AFGHANISTAN, FOR
FOR AFGHANISTAN, FOR PROTECTION.
WILL
WILL FOR
FOR AFGHANISTAN, FOR PROTECTION.
WILL FOR AFGHANISTAN,
WILL FOR AFGHANISTAN, FOR
PROTECTION.
AND
AND YOU
PROTECTION.
AND YOU AND
AND YOU AND I
PROTECTION.
AND YOU AND I WILL
AND YOU AND I WILL I
PROTECTION.
AND YOU AND I WILL I WANT
AND YOU AND I WILL I WANT TO
I
I WILL
AND YOU AND I WILL I WANT TO
I WILL I
I WILL I WANT
AND YOU AND I WILL I WANT TO
I WILL I WANT TO
I WILL I WANT TO KNOW
AND YOU AND I WILL I WANT TO
I WILL I WANT TO KNOW YOUR
OPINION
OPINION ABOUT
I WILL I WANT TO KNOW YOUR
OPINION ABOUT THAT.
AND
AND IN
OPINION ABOUT THAT.
AND IN THANK
AND IN THANK YOU.
AND
AND HILLARY
AND IN THANK YOU.
AND HILLARY CLINTON:
AND HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
AND IN THANK YOU.
AND HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
FIRST,
FIRST, I
AND HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
FIRST, I WANT
FIRST, I WANT TO
AND HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
FIRST, I WANT TO SAY
FIRST, I WANT TO SAY HOW
DISTRESSED
DISTRESSED I
FIRST, I WANT TO SAY HOW
DISTRESSED I AM
DISTRESSED I AM BY
FIRST, I WANT TO SAY HOW
DISTRESSED I AM BY THE
DISTRESSED I AM BY THE BOMBING
OF
OF THE
DISTRESSED I AM BY THE BOMBING
OF THE HOSPITAL.
IN
IN AND
OF THE HOSPITAL.
IN AND I
IN AND I KNOW
OF THE HOSPITAL.
IN AND I KNOW THAT
IN AND I KNOW THAT DEFENSE
IN
IN SECRETARY
IN AND I KNOW THAT DEFENSE
IN SECRETARY CARTER
IN SECRETARY CARTER HAS
IN AND I KNOW THAT DEFENSE
IN SECRETARY CARTER HAS SAID
HER
HER THERE
IN SECRETARY CARTER HAS SAID
HER THERE WILL
HER THERE WILL BE
IN SECRETARY CARTER HAS SAID
HER THERE WILL BE A
HER THERE WILL BE A FULL
THOROUGH
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION
HER THERE WILL BE A FULL
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION TO
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION TO TRY
AND
AND GET
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION TO TRY
AND GET TO
AND GET TO THE
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION TO TRY
AND GET TO THE BOTTOM
AND GET TO THE BOTTOM OF
THOROUGH INVESTIGATION TO TRY
AND GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THAT.
BUT
BUT IT
AND GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THAT.
BUT IT IS
BUT IT IS DEEPLY
AND GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THAT.
BUT IT IS DEEPLY REGRETTABLE.
IT
IT CAME
BUT IT IS DEEPLY REGRETTABLE.
IT CAME WITHIN
IT CAME WITHIN THE
BUT IT IS DEEPLY REGRETTABLE.
IT CAME WITHIN THE CONTEXT
IT CAME WITHIN THE CONTEXT OF
AND
AND THE
IT CAME WITHIN THE CONTEXT OF
AND THE TALIBAN
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING
IT CAME WITHIN THE CONTEXT OF
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING BACK
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING BACK OVER
YOU
YOU GO
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING BACK OVER
YOU GO A
YOU GO A CITY
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING BACK OVER
YOU GO A CITY IN
YOU GO A CITY IN THE
AND THE TALIBAN TAKING BACK OVER
YOU GO A CITY IN THE NORTH,
YOU GO A CITY IN THE NORTH, AND
TO
TO THE
YOU GO A CITY IN THE NORTH, AND
TO THE DOOR
TO THE DOOR THE
YOU GO A CITY IN THE NORTH, AND
TO THE DOOR THE AFGHAN
TO THE DOOR THE AFGHAN ARMY,
AND
AND HE
TO THE DOOR THE AFGHAN ARMY,
AND HE THE
AND HE THE AFGHAN
TO THE DOOR THE AFGHAN ARMY,
AND HE THE AFGHAN ARMY,
AND HE THE AFGHAN ARMY, WHICH
HAS
HAS PERFORMED
AND HE THE AFGHAN ARMY, WHICH
HAS PERFORMED VERY
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY
AND HE THE AFGHAN ARMY, WHICH
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --
HAS
HAS PERFORMED
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --
HAS PERFORMED VERY
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --AND
THIS
THIS IS
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --AND
THIS IS NOT
THIS IS NOT AN
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --AND
THIS IS NOT AN ARMY
THIS IS NOT AN ARMY THE
HAS PERFORMED VERY BRAVELY --AND
THIS IS NOT AN ARMY THE RUNS
I
I AND
THIS IS NOT AN ARMY THE RUNS
I AND AWAY.
THIS
THIS IS
I AND AWAY.
THIS IS AN
THIS IS AN ARMY
I AND AWAY.
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT STANDS
I AND AWAY.
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT STANDS IN
YOU
YOU WILL
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT STANDS IN
YOU WILL A
YOU WILL A LOT
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT STANDS IN
YOU WILL A LOT OF
YOU WILL A LOT OF --
THIS IS AN ARMY THAT STANDS IN
YOU WILL A LOT OF -- AND
YOU WILL A LOT OF -- AND FIGHTS.
BUT
BUT THEY
YOU WILL A LOT OF -- AND FIGHTS.
BUT THEY DON'T
BUT THEY DON'T HAVE
YOU WILL A LOT OF -- AND FIGHTS.
BUT THEY DON'T HAVE THE
EXPERIENCE,
EXPERIENCE, THEY
BUT THEY DON'T HAVE THE
EXPERIENCE, THEY DON'T
EXPERIENCE, THEY DON'T HAVE
BUT THEY DON'T HAVE THE
EXPERIENCE, THEY DON'T HAVE A
LOT
LOT OF
EXPERIENCE, THEY DON'T HAVE A
LOT OF THE
LOT OF THE SUPPORT
EXPERIENCE, THEY DON'T HAVE A
LOT OF THE SUPPORT THAT
LOT OF THE SUPPORT THAT THEY
NEED
NEED TO
LOT OF THE SUPPORT THAT THEY
NEED TO BE
NEED TO BE AS
LOT OF THE SUPPORT THAT THEY
NEED TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL
NEED TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL AS
LOT OF THE SUPPORT THAT THEY
NEED TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL AS THEY
ARE
ARE TRYING
NEED TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL AS THEY
ARE TRYING TO
ARE TRYING TO BE.
I
I THINK
ARE TRYING TO BE.
I THINK THAT
I THINK THAT WE
ARE TRYING TO BE.
I THINK THAT WE HAVE
I THINK THAT WE HAVE GOT
ARE TRYING TO BE.
I THINK THAT WE HAVE GOT TO
CONTINUE
CONTINUE TO
I THINK THAT WE HAVE GOT TO
CONTINUE TO WORK
CONTINUE TO WORK WITH
I THINK THAT WE HAVE GOT TO
CONTINUE TO WORK WITH THE
CONTINUE TO WORK WITH THE AFGHAN
GOVERNMENT
GOVERNMENT AND
CONTINUE TO WORK WITH THE AFGHAN
GOVERNMENT AND THE
GOVERNMENT AND THE AFGHAN
MILITARY
MILITARY TO
GOVERNMENT AND THE AFGHAN
MILITARY TO SUPPORT
MILITARY TO SUPPORT THEM.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE THEY
MILITARY TO SUPPORT THEM.
BECAUSE THEY ARE
BECAUSE THEY ARE FIGHTING.
IT'S
IT'S A
BECAUSE THEY ARE FIGHTING.
IT'S A DIFFERENT
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY
BECAUSE THEY ARE FIGHTING.
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY IN
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY IN OTHER
PARTS
PARTS OF
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY IN OTHER
PARTS OF THE
PARTS OF THE WORLD,
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY IN OTHER
PARTS OF THE WORLD, BUT
PARTS OF THE WORLD, BUT THEY'RE
IN
IN AFGHANISTAN,
PARTS OF THE WORLD, BUT THEY'RE
IN AFGHANISTAN, PEOPLE
IN AFGHANISTAN, PEOPLE ARE
FIGHTING
FIGHTING FOR
IN AFGHANISTAN, PEOPLE ARE
FIGHTING FOR THE
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS
IN AFGHANISTAN, PEOPLE ARE
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS THAT
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS THAT HAVE
BEEN
BEEN MADE
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS THAT HAVE
BEEN MADE IN
BEEN MADE IN THE
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS THAT HAVE
BEEN MADE IN THE LAST
BEEN MADE IN THE LAST 13,
FIGHTING FOR THE GAINS THAT HAVE
BEEN MADE IN THE LAST 13, 14
YEARS.
THERE
THERE STILL
YEARS.
THERE STILL IS
THERE STILL IS A
YEARS.
THERE STILL IS A LOT
THERE STILL IS A LOT OF
CONFLICT,
CONFLICT, THERE
THERE STILL IS A LOT OF
CONFLICT, THERE STILL
CONFLICT, THERE STILL IS
THERE STILL IS A LOT OF
CONFLICT, THERE STILL IS A
CONFLICT, THERE STILL IS A LOT
OF
OF DANGER.
BUT
BUT TALIBAN
OF DANGER.
BUT TALIBAN IS
BUT TALIBAN IS NOT
OF DANGER.
BUT TALIBAN IS NOT GOING
BUT TALIBAN IS NOT GOING AWAY.
WE
WE KNOW
BUT TALIBAN IS NOT GOING AWAY.
WE KNOW THAT.
BUT
BUT THERE
WE KNOW THAT.
BUT THERE HAS
BUT THERE HAS BEEN
WE KNOW THAT.
BUT THERE HAS BEEN SO
BUT THERE HAS BEEN SO MANY
POSITIVE
POSITIVE DEVELOPMENTS.
NUMBER
NUMBER THE
POSITIVE DEVELOPMENTS.
NUMBER THE NUMBER
NUMBER THE NUMBER OF
POSITIVE DEVELOPMENTS.
NUMBER THE NUMBER OF GIRLS
NUMBER THE NUMBER OF GIRLS AND
WOMEN
WOMEN IN
NUMBER THE NUMBER OF GIRLS AND
WOMEN IN SCHOOL,
WOMEN IN SCHOOL, AT
NUMBER THE NUMBER OF GIRLS AND
WOMEN IN SCHOOL, AT WORK,
STUDYING
STUDYING IN
WOMEN IN SCHOOL, AT WORK,
STUDYING IN THE
STUDYING IN THE UNITED
WOMEN IN SCHOOL, AT WORK,
STUDYING IN THE UNITED STATES,
GOING
GOING HOME
STUDYING IN THE UNITED STATES,
GOING HOME TO
GOING HOME TO TRY
STUDYING IN THE UNITED STATES,
GOING HOME TO TRY AND
GOING HOME TO TRY AND HELP
STUDYING IN THE UNITED STATES,
GOING HOME TO TRY AND HELP THEIR
COUNTRY,
COUNTRY, BUSINESSES
GOING HOME TO TRY AND HELP THEIR
COUNTRY, BUSINESSES THAT
COUNTRY, BUSINESSES THAT ARE
NOW
NOW ABLE
COUNTRY, BUSINESSES THAT ARE
NOW ABLE TO
NOW ABLE TO OPERATE
COUNTRY, BUSINESSES THAT ARE
NOW ABLE TO OPERATE NOW
NOW ABLE TO OPERATE NOW AS
OPPOSED
OPPOSED TO
NOW ABLE TO OPERATE NOW AS
OPPOSED TO BEING
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER
NOW ABLE TO OPERATE NOW AS
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER THE
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER THE SUM
AND
AND FOR
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER THE SUM
AND FOR THE
AND FOR THE --
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER THE SUM
AND FOR THE -- UNDER
AND FOR THE -- UNDER THE
OPPOSED TO BEING UNDER THE SUM
AND FOR THE -- UNDER THE THUMB
OF
OF THE
AND FOR THE -- UNDER THE THUMB
OF THE TALIBAN
OF THE TALIBAN AND
AND FOR THE -- UNDER THE THUMB
OF THE TALIBAN AND BEING
OF THE TALIBAN AND BEING FORCED
TO
TO BASICALLY
OF THE TALIBAN AND BEING FORCED
TO BASICALLY PAY
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE
OF THE TALIBAN AND BEING FORCED
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE ALL
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE ALL THE
TIME
TIME TO
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE ALL THE
TIME TO THE
TIME TO THE TALIBAN
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE ALL THE
TIME TO THE TALIBAN --
TIME TO THE TALIBAN -- OR
TO BASICALLY PAY TRIBUTE ALL THE
TIME TO THE TALIBAN -- OR HAVE
BEEN
BEEN A
TIME TO THE TALIBAN -- OR HAVE
BEEN A LOT
BEEN A LOT OF
TIME TO THE TALIBAN -- OR HAVE
BEEN A LOT OF ADVANCES
BEEN A LOT OF ADVANCES IN
HEALTH.
AFGHANISTAN
AFGHANISTAN HAD
HEALTH.
AFGHANISTAN HAD THE
AFGHANISTAN HAD THE WORST
MATERNAL
MATERNAL MORTALITY
AFGHANISTAN HAD THE WORST
MATERNAL MORTALITY RATE
MATERNAL MORTALITY RATE IN
AFGHANISTAN HAD THE WORST
MATERNAL MORTALITY RATE IN THE
WORLD,
WORLD, AND
MATERNAL MORTALITY RATE IN THE
WORLD, AND THINGS
WORLD, AND THINGS TO
MATERNAL MORTALITY RATE IN THE
WORLD, AND THINGS TO HELP
WORLD, AND THINGS TO HELP FOR
NOT
NOT JUST
WORLD, AND THINGS TO HELP FOR
NOT JUST THE
NOT JUST THE UNITED
WORLD, AND THINGS TO HELP FOR
NOT JUST THE UNITED STATES,
NOT JUST THE UNITED STATES, BUT
OTHER
OTHER COUNTRIES,
NOT JUST THE UNITED STATES, BUT
OTHER COUNTRIES, WORKING
OTHER COUNTRIES, WORKING WITH
AFGHAN
AFGHAN DOCTORS
OTHER COUNTRIES, WORKING WITH
AFGHAN DOCTORS AND
AFGHAN DOCTORS AND NURSES,
MOTHERS
MOTHERS ARE
AFGHAN DOCTORS AND NURSES,
MOTHERS ARE SURVIVING
AND
AND CHILDBIRTH.
SOME
SOME OF
AND CHILDBIRTH.
SOME OF THE
SOME OF THE THINGS
AND CHILDBIRTH.
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE
AND CHILDBIRTH.
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE SO
BASIC,
BASIC, THAT
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE SO
BASIC, THAT ARE
BASIC, THAT ARE NOW
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE SO
BASIC, THAT ARE NOW SO
BASIC, THAT ARE NOW SO MUCH
BETTER
BETTER IN
BASIC, THAT ARE NOW SO MUCH
BETTER IN AFGHANISTAN.
I
I DON'T
BETTER IN AFGHANISTAN.
I DON'T KNOW
I DON'T KNOW THE
BETTER IN AFGHANISTAN.
I DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS
I DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS OF
WHAT
WHAT I
I DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS OF
WHAT I WILL
WHAT I WILL BE
I DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS OF
WHAT I WILL BE FACING
WHAT I WILL BE FACING IN
I DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS OF
WHAT I WILL BE FACING IN JANUARY
OF
OF 2017.
BUT
BUT AFGHANISTAN
OF 2017.
BUT AFGHANISTAN IS
BUT AFGHANISTAN IS A
OF 2017.
BUT AFGHANISTAN IS A COUNTRY
THAT
THAT HAS
BUT AFGHANISTAN IS A COUNTRY
THAT HAS TRIED.
AND
AND THE
THAT HAS TRIED.
AND THE PEOPLE
AND THE PEOPLE ARE
THAT HAS TRIED.
AND THE PEOPLE ARE REALLY
FOCUSED
FOCUSED ON
AND THE PEOPLE ARE REALLY
FOCUSED ON GETTING
FOCUSED ON GETTING BEYOND
AND THE PEOPLE ARE REALLY
FOCUSED ON GETTING BEYOND THE
VIOLENCE
VIOLENCE IN
FOCUSED ON GETTING BEYOND THE
VIOLENCE IN THE
VIOLENCE IN THE EXTREMISM
FOCUSED ON GETTING BEYOND THE
VIOLENCE IN THE EXTREMISM FROM
THE
THE TALIBAN.
AND
AND I
THE TALIBAN.
AND I DON'T
AND I DON'T THINK
THE TALIBAN.
AND I DON'T THINK WE
AND I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD
THE TALIBAN.
AND I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD JUST
WALK
WALK AWAY.
I
I WILL
WALK AWAY.
I WILL DO
I WILL DO WHAT
WALK AWAY.
I WILL DO WHAT I
I WILL DO WHAT I CAN
WALK AWAY.
I WILL DO WHAT I CAN TO
I WILL DO WHAT I CAN TO HELP.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: HERE
HILLARY CLINTON: HERE COMES
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: HERE COMES THE
MICROPHONE.
>>
>> MY
MICROPHONE.
>> MY NAME
>> MY NAME IS
MICROPHONE.
>> MY NAME IS JEANNIE,
>> MY NAME IS JEANNIE, I
MICROPHONE.
>> MY NAME IS JEANNIE, I WAS
BORN
BORN ON
>> MY NAME IS JEANNIE, I WAS
BORN ON BELMONT
BORN ON BELMONT STREET
>> MY NAME IS JEANNIE, I WAS
BORN ON BELMONT STREET RIGHT
HERE
HERE IN
BORN ON BELMONT STREET RIGHT
HERE IN TOWN.
IT
IT IS
HERE IN TOWN.
IT IS NO
IT IS NO LONGER
HERE IN TOWN.
IT IS NO LONGER THE
IT IS NO LONGER THE CITY
HERE IN TOWN.
IT IS NO LONGER THE CITY I
IT IS NO LONGER THE CITY I WAS
RAISED
RAISED IN.
A
A LOT
RAISED IN.
A LOT OF
A LOT OF THAT
RAISED IN.
A LOT OF THAT IS
A LOT OF THAT IS BECAUSE
RAISED IN.
A LOT OF THAT IS BECAUSE OF
DRUGS,
DRUGS, AND
A LOT OF THAT IS BECAUSE OF
DRUGS, AND BECAUSE
DRUGS, AND BECAUSE OF
A LOT OF THAT IS BECAUSE OF
DRUGS, AND BECAUSE OF GUN
VIOLENCE.
IN
IN MY
VIOLENCE.
IN MY QUESTION
IN MY QUESTION TO
VIOLENCE.
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU,
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU, HILLARY,
AND
AND IN
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU, HILLARY,
AND IN IF
AND IN IF I
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU, HILLARY,
AND IN IF I CAN
AND IN IF I CAN CALL
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU, HILLARY,
AND IN IF I CAN CALL YOU
AND IN IF I CAN CALL YOU THAT
IN MY QUESTION TO YOU, HILLARY,
AND IN IF I CAN CALL YOU THAT --
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
AND IN IF I CAN CALL YOU THAT --
HILLARY CLINTON: OR
HILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU
AND IN IF I CAN CALL YOU THAT --
HILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU CAN
AHILLARY
AHILLARY CLINTON:
HILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU CAN
AHILLARY CLINTON: OR
AHILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU CAN
AHILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU CAN
CALL
CALL ME
AHILLARY CLINTON: OR YOU CAN
CALL ME VAL.
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> OR
[APPLAUSE]
>> OR VAL.
MY
MY QUESTION
>> OR VAL.
MY QUESTION IS,
MY QUESTION IS, LAST
>> OR VAL.
MY QUESTION IS, LAST WEEK
MY QUESTION IS, LAST WEEK A
REPORTER
REPORTER ASKED
MY QUESTION IS, LAST WEEK A
REPORTER ASKED DR.
REPORTER ASKED DR. BEN
MY QUESTION IS, LAST WEEK A
REPORTER ASKED DR. BEN CARSON
ONE
ONE QUESTION.
THAT
THAT QUESTION
ONE QUESTION.
THAT QUESTION WAS,
THAT QUESTION WAS, AS
ONE QUESTION.
THAT QUESTION WAS, AS PRESIDENT
OF
OF THE
THAT QUESTION WAS, AS PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED
OF THE UNITED STATES,
THAT QUESTION WAS, AS PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES, WHAT
OF THE UNITED STATES, WHAT WOULD
YOU
YOU DO
OF THE UNITED STATES, WHAT WOULD
YOU DO IN
YOU DO IN ADVANCE
OF THE UNITED STATES, WHAT WOULD
YOU DO IN ADVANCE TO
YOU DO IN ADVANCE TO ASSIST
OF THE UNITED STATES, WHAT WOULD
YOU DO IN ADVANCE TO ASSIST THE
FOLKS
FOLKS OF
YOU DO IN ADVANCE TO ASSIST THE
FOLKS OF A
FOLKS OF A HORRIBLE
YOU DO IN ADVANCE TO ASSIST THE
FOLKS OF A HORRIBLE EVENTS
FOLKS OF A HORRIBLE EVENTS LIKE
LETTER
LETTER HURRICANE
FOLKS OF A HORRIBLE EVENTS LIKE
LETTER HURRICANE JOAQUIN.
HE
HE KEPT
LETTER HURRICANE JOAQUIN.
HE KEPT A
HE KEPT A VERY
LETTER HURRICANE JOAQUIN.
HE KEPT A VERY SHORT
HE KEPT A VERY SHORT AND
TO
TO THINK
HE KEPT A VERY SHORT AND
TO THINK OR
TO THINK OR DO
HE KEPT A VERY SHORT AND
TO THINK OR DO --
TO THINK OR DO -- SUCCINCT
HE KEPT A VERY SHORT AND
TO THINK OR DO -- SUCCINCT AND
HIS
HIS THREE
TO THINK OR DO -- SUCCINCT AND
HIS THREE WORD
HIS THREE WORD ANSWER
TO THINK OR DO -- SUCCINCT AND
HIS THREE WORD ANSWER WAS
HIS THREE WORD ANSWER WAS --
TO THINK OR DO -- SUCCINCT AND
HIS THREE WORD ANSWER WAS -- I
DON'T
DON'T KNOW.
ALONG
ALONG WITH
DON'T KNOW.
ALONG WITH THAT,
ALONG WITH THAT, AS
DON'T KNOW.
ALONG WITH THAT, AS YOU
ALONG WITH THAT, AS YOU SAID
LAST
LAST WEEK,
ALONG WITH THAT, AS YOU SAID
LAST WEEK, A
LAST WEEK, A REPORTER
ALONG WITH THAT, AS YOU SAID
LAST WEEK, A REPORTER ASKED
LAST WEEK, A REPORTER ASKED JEB
BUSH
BUSH WHAT
LAST WEEK, A REPORTER ASKED JEB
BUSH WHAT HE
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT
LAST WEEK, A REPORTER ASKED JEB
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT ABOUT
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY
TRAGEDY IN
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN ORDER
TRAGEDY IN ORDER ON
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN ORDER ON --
TRAGEDY IN ORDER ON -- IN
BUSH WHAT HE THOUGHT ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN ORDER ON -- IN ORGAN
--
-- IN
TRAGEDY IN ORDER ON -- IN ORGAN
-- IN OREGON.
HIS
HIS RESPONSE
-- IN OREGON.
HIS RESPONSE TO
HIS RESPONSE TO THAT
-- IN OREGON.
HIS RESPONSE TO THAT HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY
TRAGEDY WAS
HIS RESPONSE TO THAT HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY WAS STUFF
TRAGEDY WAS STUFF HAPPENS.
I
I WOULD
TRAGEDY WAS STUFF HAPPENS.
I WOULD LIKE
I WOULD LIKE TO
TRAGEDY WAS STUFF HAPPENS.
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW FROM
TRAGEDY WAS STUFF HAPPENS.
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW FROM YOU
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW FROM YOU --
YOU
YOU EXPLAIN
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW FROM YOU --
YOU EXPLAIN TO
YOU EXPLAIN TO THIS
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW FROM YOU --
YOU EXPLAIN TO THIS AUDIENCE
YOU EXPLAIN TO THIS AUDIENCE AND
TO
TO THE
YOU EXPLAIN TO THIS AUDIENCE AND
TO THE NATION,
TO THE NATION, WHY
YOU EXPLAIN TO THIS AUDIENCE AND
TO THE NATION, WHY THOSE
TO THE NATION, WHY THOSE WOULD
NOT
NOT HAVE
TO THE NATION, WHY THOSE WOULD
NOT HAVE BEEN
NOT HAVE BEEN YOUR
TO THE NATION, WHY THOSE WOULD
NOT HAVE BEEN YOUR RESPONSES,
AND
AND WHY,
NOT HAVE BEEN YOUR RESPONSES,
AND WHY, AS
AND WHY, AS PRESIDENT
NOT HAVE BEEN YOUR RESPONSES,
AND WHY, AS PRESIDENT OF
AND WHY, AS PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED
UNITED STATES,
AND WHY, AS PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, YOU
UNITED STATES, YOU ARE
AND WHY, AS PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, YOU ARE READY
UNITED STATES, YOU ARE READY TO
LEAD
LEAD FROM
UNITED STATES, YOU ARE READY TO
LEAD FROM DAY
LEAD FROM DAY ONE.
THANK
THANK YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: LET'S
HILLARY CLINTON: LET'S TAKE
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: LET'S TAKE THE
NATURAL
NATURAL DISASTER
HILLARY CLINTON: LET'S TAKE THE
NATURAL DISASTER QUESTION
NATURAL DISASTER QUESTION FIRST.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE HURRICANE
NATURAL DISASTER QUESTION FIRST.
BECAUSE HURRICANE JOAQUIN
BECAUSE HURRICANE JOAQUIN WAS
NATURAL DISASTER QUESTION FIRST.
BECAUSE HURRICANE JOAQUIN WAS ON
EVERYONE'S
EVERYONE'S MIND.
THANKFULLY,
THANKFULLY, IT
EVERYONE'S MIND.
THANKFULLY, IT DIDN'T
THANKFULLY, IT DIDN'T HIT
EVERYONE'S MIND.
THANKFULLY, IT DIDN'T HIT AS
HARD
HARD AS
THANKFULLY, IT DIDN'T HIT AS
HARD AS THEY
HARD AS THEY FEARED,
THANKFULLY, IT DIDN'T HIT AS
HARD AS THEY FEARED, ALTHOUGH
SOUTH
SOUTH CAROLINA
HARD AS THEY FEARED, ALTHOUGH
SOUTH CAROLINA IS
SOUTH CAROLINA IS GETTING
BATTERED
BATTERED WITH
SOUTH CAROLINA IS GETTING
BATTERED WITH TERRIBLE
TORRENTIAL
TORRENTIAL RAIN.
I
I THINK
TORRENTIAL RAIN.
I THINK ONE
I THINK ONE OF
TORRENTIAL RAIN.
I THINK ONE OF THE
I THINK ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT
IMPORTANT DECISIONS
I THINK ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT DECISIONS ANY
IMPORTANT DECISIONS ANY NEW
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT HAS
IMPORTANT DECISIONS ANY NEW
PRESIDENT HAS IS
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO
IMPORTANT DECISIONS ANY NEW
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS GOING
IMPORTANT DECISIONS ANY NEW
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS GOING TO
RUN
RUN FEMA,
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS GOING TO
RUN FEMA, AND
RUN FEMA, AND WHO
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS GOING TO
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS GOING
PRESIDENT HAS IS WHO IS GOING TO
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS GOING TO
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS GOING TO BE
PREPARED
PREPARED TO
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS GOING TO BE
PREPARED TO WORK
PREPARED TO WORK WITH
RUN FEMA, AND WHO IS GOING TO BE
PREPARED TO WORK WITH CITIES,
STATES,
STATES, AND
PREPARED TO WORK WITH CITIES,
STATES, AND THE
STATES, AND THE NATIONAL
GOVERNMENT
GOVERNMENT TO
STATES, AND THE NATIONAL
GOVERNMENT TO GET
GOVERNMENT TO GET PREPARED
STATES, AND THE NATIONAL
GOVERNMENT TO GET PREPARED FOR
INCOMING
INCOMING NATURAL
GOVERNMENT TO GET PREPARED FOR
INCOMING NATURAL DISASTERS,
INCOMING NATURAL DISASTERS, TO
AND
AND GET
INCOMING NATURAL DISASTERS, TO
AND GET PRE-POSITIONED
AND GET PRE-POSITIONED THE
EQUIPMENTS
EQUIPMENTS AND
AND GET PRE-POSITIONED THE
EQUIPMENTS AND THE
EQUIPMENTS AND THE FOOD
AND GET PRE-POSITIONED THE
EQUIPMENTS AND THE FOOD AND
EQUIPMENTS AND THE FOOD AND THE
EXPERTS
EXPERTS THAT
EQUIPMENTS AND THE FOOD AND THE
EXPERTS THAT YOU
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE
EQUIPMENTS AND THE FOOD AND THE
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE GOING
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE GOING TO
NEED
NEED TO
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE GOING TO
NEED TO BE
NEED TO BE ABLE
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE GOING TO
NEED TO BE ABLE TO
NEED TO BE ABLE TO HELP
EXPERTS THAT YOU ARE GOING TO
NEED TO BE ABLE TO HELP PEOPLE.
I
I WILL
NEED TO BE ABLE TO HELP PEOPLE.
I WILL TAKE
I WILL TAKE THAT
NEED TO BE ABLE TO HELP PEOPLE.
I WILL TAKE THAT VERY
I WILL TAKE THAT VERY SERIOUSLY.
LOOKING
LOOKING FOR
I WILL TAKE THAT VERY SERIOUSLY.
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE WHO
I WILL TAKE THAT VERY SERIOUSLY.
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE WHO HAS
REAL,
REAL, HANDS-ON
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE WHO HAS
REAL, HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE,
REAL, HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE, NOT
FROM
FROM 30,000
REAL, HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE, NOT
FROM 30,000 FEET
FROM 30,000 FEET FLYING
REAL, HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE, NOT
FROM 30,000 FEET FLYING OVER
FROM 30,000 FEET FLYING OVER IT,
VERY
VERY WILL
FROM 30,000 FEET FLYING OVER IT,
VERY WILL BUT
VERY WILL BUT WHO
FROM 30,000 FEET FLYING OVER IT,
VERY WILL BUT WHO HAS
VERY WILL BUT WHO HAS BEEN
THERE,
THERE, WHO
VERY WILL BUT WHO HAS BEEN
THERE, WHO IS
THERE, WHO IS HAD
VERY WILL BUT WHO HAS BEEN
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO
VERY WILL BUT WHO HAS BEEN
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO IN
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO IN AND
FIGURE
FIGURE OUT
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO IN AND
FIGURE OUT WHAT
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO IN AND
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO
THERE, WHO IS HAD TO GO IN AND
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO HELP
AND
AND FIGURE
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO HELP
AND FIGURE OUT
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO HELP
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT TO
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO
FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO HELP
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO
HELP
HELP PEOPLE
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO
HELP PEOPLE EVACUATE,
HELP PEOPLE EVACUATE, WHAT
NEEDED
NEEDED TO
HELP PEOPLE EVACUATE, WHAT
NEEDED TO BE
NEEDED TO BE DONE
HELP PEOPLE EVACUATE, WHAT
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY
HELP PEOPLE EVACUATE, WHAT
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY TO
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY TO DO
I
I AS
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY TO DO
I AS MUCH
I AS MUCH AS
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY TO DO
I AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE
I AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE TO
NEEDED TO BE DONE TO TRY TO DO
I AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE TO HELP
WILL
WILL PEOPLE
I AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE TO HELP
WILL PEOPLE SAVE
WILL PEOPLE SAVE THEIR
I AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE TO HELP
WILL PEOPLE SAVE THEIR HOMES,
BUT
BUT NOT
WILL PEOPLE SAVE THEIR HOMES,
BUT NOT STAY
BUT NOT STAY IN
WILL PEOPLE SAVE THEIR HOMES,
BUT NOT STAY IN THEIR
BUT NOT STAY IN THEIR HOMES.
THERE'S
THERE'S JUST
BUT NOT STAY IN THEIR HOMES.
THERE'S JUST A
THERE'S JUST A LOT
BUT NOT STAY IN THEIR HOMES.
THERE'S JUST A LOT OF
THERE'S JUST A LOT OF HARD-WON
ARE
ARE WISDOM.
IN
IN BECAUSE
ARE WISDOM.
IN BECAUSE OF
IN BECAUSE OF CLIMATE
ARE WISDOM.
IN BECAUSE OF CLIMATE CHANGE,
IN BECAUSE OF CLIMATE CHANGE, WE
YOUR
YOUR ARE
IN BECAUSE OF CLIMATE CHANGE, WE
YOUR ARE SEEING
YOUR ARE SEEING AN
IN BECAUSE OF CLIMATE CHANGE, WE
YOUR ARE SEEING AN INCREASED
NUMBER
NUMBER OF
YOUR ARE SEEING AN INCREASED
NUMBER OF WEATHER
NUMBER OF WEATHER EVENTS.
WILL
WILL ALL
NUMBER OF WEATHER EVENTS.
WILL ALL OVER
WILL ALL OVER THE
NUMBER OF WEATHER EVENTS.
WILL ALL OVER THE WORLD,
WILL ALL OVER THE WORLD, NOT
JUST
JUST IN
WILL ALL OVER THE WORLD, NOT
JUST IN OUR
JUST IN OUR COUNTRY.
WE
WE NEED
JUST IN OUR COUNTRY.
WE NEED A
WE NEED A MAPPING
JUST IN OUR COUNTRY.
WE NEED A MAPPING PROJECT.
AND
AND WILL
WE NEED A MAPPING PROJECT.
AND WILL AND
AND WILL AND I
WE NEED A MAPPING PROJECT.
AND WILL AND I WILL
AND WILL AND I WILL GIVE
WE NEED A MAPPING PROJECT.
AND WILL AND I WILL GIVE YOU
AND WILL AND I WILL GIVE YOU A
PERFECT
PERFECT EXAMPLE
AND WILL AND I WILL GIVE YOU A
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF WHY
AND WILL AND I WILL GIVE YOU A
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF WHY I
WILL
WILL DISAGREE
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF WHY I
WILL DISAGREE SO
WILL DISAGREE SO PROFOUNDLY
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF WHY I
WILL DISAGREE SO PROFOUNDLY WITH
THE
THE CURRENT
WILL DISAGREE SO PROFOUNDLY WITH
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS,
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS, WE'VE
HEARD
HEARD THE
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS, WE'VE
HEARD THE LETTER
HEARD THE LETTER FROM
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS, WE'VE
HEARD THE LETTER FROM RONALD
WILL
WILL YOU
HEARD THE LETTER FROM RONALD
WILL YOU AND
WILL YOU AND REAGAN,
HEARD THE LETTER FROM RONALD
WILL YOU AND REAGAN, I
WILL YOU AND REAGAN, I TOLD
HEARD THE LETTER FROM RONALD
WILL YOU AND REAGAN, I TOLD YOU
ABOUT
ABOUT PRESIDENT
WILL YOU AND REAGAN, I TOLD YOU
ABOUT PRESIDENT GEORGE
ABOUT PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
BUSH.
THE
THE CURRENT
BUSH.
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS IN
BUSH.
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS IN THE
I
I CONGRESS
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS IN THE
I CONGRESS ARE
I CONGRESS ARE TRYING
THE CURRENT REPUBLICANS IN THE
I CONGRESS ARE TRYING TO
I CONGRESS ARE TRYING TO CUT
DRAMATICALLY
DRAMATICALLY THE
I CONGRESS ARE TRYING TO CUT
DRAMATICALLY THE MONEY
DRAMATICALLY THE MONEY THE
FEDERAL
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
DRAMATICALLY THE MONEY THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT PUTS
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT PUTS IN
DRAMATICALLY THE MONEY THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT PUTS IN TO
WEATHER
WEATHER FORECASTING.
TO
TO ME,
WEATHER FORECASTING.
TO ME, THAT
TO ME, THAT IS
WEATHER FORECASTING.
TO ME, THAT IS SO
TO ME, THAT IS SO PENNY
WEATHER FORECASTING.
TO ME, THAT IS SO PENNY WISE,
AND
AND POUND
TO ME, THAT IS SO PENNY WISE,
AND POUND FOOLISH.
A
A WIDE
AND POUND FOOLISH.
A WIDE WE
A WIDE WE HAVE
AND POUND FOOLISH.
A WIDE WE HAVE GOT
A WIDE WE HAVE GOT TO
AND POUND FOOLISH.
A WIDE WE HAVE GOT TO HAVE
A WIDE WE HAVE GOT TO HAVE THE
BEST
BEST POSSIBLE
A WIDE WE HAVE GOT TO HAVE THE
BEST POSSIBLE WEATHER
FORECASTING.
NOT
NOT ONLY
FORECASTING.
NOT ONLY FOR
NOT ONLY FOR AGRICULTURE
FORECASTING.
NOT ONLY FOR AGRICULTURE AND
NOT ONLY FOR AGRICULTURE AND YOU
WILL
WILL KNOW,
NOT ONLY FOR AGRICULTURE AND YOU
WILL KNOW, EVERYDAY
WILL KNOW, EVERYDAY OCCURRENCES,
BUT
BUT ALSO
WILL KNOW, EVERYDAY OCCURRENCES,
BUT ALSO TO
BUT ALSO TO GET
WILL KNOW, EVERYDAY OCCURRENCES,
BUT ALSO TO GET AHEAD
BUT ALSO TO GET AHEAD OF
WILL KNOW, EVERYDAY OCCURRENCES,
BUT ALSO TO GET AHEAD OF NATURAL
DISASTERS
DISASTERS AND
BUT ALSO TO GET AHEAD OF NATURAL
DISASTERS AND EVENTS
DISASTERS AND EVENTS LIKE
BUT ALSO TO GET AHEAD OF NATURAL
DISASTERS AND EVENTS LIKE BIG
STORMS.
AND
AND YOU
STORMS.
AND YOU ARE
AND YOU ARE MORE
STORMS.
AND YOU ARE MORE THAN
AND YOU ARE MORE THAN I
STORMS.
AND YOU ARE MORE THAN I WILL
A
A I
AND YOU ARE MORE THAN I WILL
A I WILL
A I WILL WILL
AND YOU ARE MORE THAN I WILL
A I WILL WILL APPOINT
A I WILL WILL APPOINT GOOD
PEOPLE,
PEOPLE, I
A I WILL WILL APPOINT GOOD
PEOPLE, I WILL
PEOPLE, I WILL LOOK
A I WILL WILL APPOINT GOOD
PEOPLE, I WILL LOOK ACROSS
PEOPLE, I WILL LOOK ACROSS THE
GOVERNMENT
GOVERNMENT TO
PEOPLE, I WILL LOOK ACROSS THE
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT
PEOPLE, I WILL LOOK ACROSS THE
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WE
NEED
NEED TO
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WE
NEED TO DO
NEED TO DO BETTER
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WE
NEED TO DO BETTER SO
NEED TO DO BETTER SO THAT
GOVERNMENT TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WE
NEED TO DO BETTER SO THAT WE
HAVE
HAVE EXCELLENT
NEED TO DO BETTER SO THAT WE
HAVE EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION
WITH
WITH STATES
HAVE EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION
WITH STATES AND
WITH STATES AND LOCAL
GOVERNMENTS,
GOVERNMENTS, AND
WITH STATES AND LOCAL
GOVERNMENTS, AND THAT
GOVERNMENTS, AND THAT WE
WITH STATES AND LOCAL
GOVERNMENTS, AND THAT WE KEEP
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WELL-INFORMED,
GOVERNMENTS, AND THAT WE KEEP
PEOPLE WELL-INFORMED, SO
PEOPLE WELL-INFORMED, SO THEY
CAN
CAN MAKE
PEOPLE WELL-INFORMED, SO THEY
CAN MAKE GOOD
CAN MAKE GOOD DECISIONS
PEOPLE WELL-INFORMED, SO THEY
CAN MAKE GOOD DECISIONS FOR
THEMSELVES.
AND
AND THAT
THEMSELVES.
AND THAT WE
AND THAT WE MOVE
THEMSELVES.
AND THAT WE MOVE REALLY
AND THAT WE MOVE REALLY QUICKLY
TO
TO COME
AND THAT WE MOVE REALLY QUICKLY
TO COME IN
TO COME IN AFTER
AND THAT WE MOVE REALLY QUICKLY
TO COME IN AFTER SOMETHING'S
OR
OR HAPPENED,
TO COME IN AFTER SOMETHING'S
OR HAPPENED, BECAUSE
OR HAPPENED, BECAUSE WE
TO COME IN AFTER SOMETHING'S
OR HAPPENED, BECAUSE WE CAN'T
WILL
WILL YOU
OR HAPPENED, BECAUSE WE CAN'T
WILL YOU AND
WILL YOU AND THEIR
OR HAPPENED, BECAUSE WE CAN'T
WILL YOU AND THEIR STOP
WILL YOU AND THEIR STOP THE
WEATHER,
WEATHER, WE
WILL YOU AND THEIR STOP THE
WEATHER, WE KNOW
WEATHER, WE KNOW THAT.
BUT
BUT TO
WEATHER, WE KNOW THAT.
BUT TO BE
BUT TO BE REALLY
WEATHER, WE KNOW THAT.
BUT TO BE REALLY READY
BUT TO BE REALLY READY TO
WEATHER, WE KNOW THAT.
BUT TO BE REALLY READY TO GET
BUT TO BE REALLY READY TO GET IN
THERE
THERE TO
BUT TO BE REALLY READY TO GET IN
THERE TO HELP
THERE TO HELP THE
BUT TO BE REALLY READY TO GET IN
THERE TO HELP THE CLEANUP
THERE TO HELP THE CLEANUP AND
THE
THE RECOVERY.
I
I THINK
THE RECOVERY.
I THINK THAT
I THINK THAT PEOPLE
THE RECOVERY.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE NEED
I THINK THAT PEOPLE NEED TO
THE RECOVERY.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE NEED TO BE
EMPOWERED
EMPOWERED TO
I THINK THAT PEOPLE NEED TO BE
EMPOWERED TO HELP
EMPOWERED TO HELP THEMSELVES
I THINK THAT PEOPLE NEED TO BE
EMPOWERED TO HELP THEMSELVES TO.
I'M
I'M A
EMPOWERED TO HELP THEMSELVES TO.
I'M A LITTLE
I'M A LITTLE WORRIED
EMPOWERED TO HELP THEMSELVES TO.
I'M A LITTLE WORRIED THAT
ARE
ARE A
I'M A LITTLE WORRIED THAT
ARE A SOMETIMES
ARE A SOMETIMES THE
I'M A LITTLE WORRIED THAT
ARE A SOMETIMES THE FEDERAL
YOU
YOU AND
ARE A SOMETIMES THE FEDERAL
YOU AND GOVERNMENT
YOU AND GOVERNMENT HAS
ARE A SOMETIMES THE FEDERAL
YOU AND GOVERNMENT HAS THE
YOU
YOU MESSAGE
YOU AND GOVERNMENT HAS THE
YOU MESSAGE OF
YOU MESSAGE OF DON'T
YOU AND GOVERNMENT HAS THE
YOU MESSAGE OF DON'T DO
YOU MESSAGE OF DON'T DO ANYTHING
WILL
WILL MESSAGE
YOU MESSAGE OF DON'T DO ANYTHING
WILL MESSAGE OF
WILL MESSAGE OF DON'T
YOU MESSAGE OF DON'T DO ANYTHING
WILL MESSAGE OF DON'T DO
ANYTHING
ANYTHING UNTIL
WILL MESSAGE OF DON'T DO
ANYTHING UNTIL WE
ANYTHING UNTIL WE GET
WILL MESSAGE OF DON'T DO
ANYTHING UNTIL WE GET THERE.
THAT'S
THAT'S NOT
ANYTHING UNTIL WE GET THERE.
THAT'S NOT MY
THAT'S NOT MY MESSAGE.
HELP
HELP EACH
THAT'S NOT MY MESSAGE.
HELP EACH OTHER,
HELP EACH OTHER, HELP
THAT'S NOT MY MESSAGE.
HELP EACH OTHER, HELP FIX
HELP EACH OTHER, HELP FIX THE
YOU
YOU AND
HELP EACH OTHER, HELP FIX THE
YOU AND PROBLEM,
YOU AND PROBLEM, HELP
HELP EACH OTHER, HELP FIX THE
YOU AND PROBLEM, HELP WORK,
YOU AND PROBLEM, HELP WORK, TAKE
PICTURES
PICTURES AND
YOU AND PROBLEM, HELP WORK, TAKE
PICTURES AND REPORT
PICTURES AND REPORT THINGS
BECAUSE
BECAUSE PEOPLE
PICTURES AND REPORT THINGS
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID
PICTURES AND REPORT THINGS
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID TO
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID TO DO
THAT
THAT BECAUSE
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID TO DO
THAT BECAUSE THEN
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID TO DO
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY SAY
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY SAY I
WANT
WANT TO
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY SAY I
WANT TO GET
WANT TO GET SOME
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY SAY I
WANT TO GET SOME HELP
WANT TO GET SOME HELP FROM
THAT BECAUSE THEN THEY SAY I
WANT TO GET SOME HELP FROM THE
DISASTER
DISASTER ASSISTANCE
WANT TO GET SOME HELP FROM THE
DISASTER ASSISTANCE FUNDING,
THEY
THEY ARE
DISASTER ASSISTANCE FUNDING,
THEY ARE TOLD
THEY ARE TOLD WE
DISASTER ASSISTANCE FUNDING,
THEY ARE TOLD WE SHOULD
THEY ARE TOLD WE SHOULD HAVE
LEFT
LEFT IT
THEY ARE TOLD WE SHOULD HAVE
LEFT IT ALONE.
NO,
NO, YOU
LEFT IT ALONE.
NO, YOU SHOULDN'T
NO, YOU SHOULDN'T LEAVE
LEFT IT ALONE.
NO, YOU SHOULDN'T LEAVE IT
ALONE.
SHOULD
SHOULD BE
ALONE.
SHOULD BE OUT
SHOULD BE OUT THERE
ALONE.
SHOULD BE OUT THERE HELPING
SHOULD BE OUT THERE HELPING YOUR
NEIGHBORS.
EVERYONE
EVERYONE IN
NEIGHBORS.
EVERYONE IN THE
EVERYONE IN THE WORLD
NEIGHBORS.
EVERYONE IN THE WORLD HAS
EVERYONE IN THE WORLD HAS A
NEIGHBORS.
EVERYONE IN THE WORLD HAS A CELL
PHONE.
KEEP
KEEP A
PHONE.
KEEP A RECORD
KEEP A RECORD OF
PHONE.
KEEP A RECORD OF IT
KEEP A RECORD OF IT SO
PHONE.
KEEP A RECORD OF IT SO WHEN
KEEP A RECORD OF IT SO WHEN THE
FEDERAL
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT,
KEEP A RECORD OF IT SO WHEN THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT, FEMA,
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT, FEMA, SMALL
BUSINESS
BUSINESS A
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT, FEMA, SMALL
BUSINESS A ADMINISTRATION,
WILL
WILL OTHERS
BUSINESS A ADMINISTRATION,
WILL OTHERS SHOW
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP
BUSINESS A ADMINISTRATION,
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU CAN
BUSINESS A ADMINISTRATION,
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU CAN SAY
HERE
HERE IS
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU CAN SAY
HERE IS WHAT
HERE IS WHAT WE
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU CAN SAY
HERE IS WHAT WE HAD
HERE IS WHAT WE HAD RIGHT
WILL OTHERS SHOW UP YOU CAN SAY
HERE IS WHAT WE HAD RIGHT AFTER
THE
THE STORM,
HERE IS WHAT WE HAD RIGHT AFTER
THE STORM, HERE
THE STORM, HERE IS
HERE IS WHAT WE HAD RIGHT AFTER
THE STORM, HERE IS WHAT
THE STORM, HERE IS WHAT WE'VE
BEEN
BEEN DOING
THE STORM, HERE IS WHAT WE'VE
BEEN DOING TO
BEEN DOING TO CLEAN
THE STORM, HERE IS WHAT WE'VE
BEEN DOING TO CLEAN UP.
HERE'S
HERE'S WHAT
BEEN DOING TO CLEAN UP.
HERE'S WHAT WE
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT
BEEN DOING TO CLEAN UP.
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT ON
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT ON WHY
IS
IS ON
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT ON WHY
IS ON YOUR
IS ON YOUR --
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT ON WHY
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT WE
HERE'S WHAT WE SPENT ON WHY
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT WE SPEND
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT WE SPEND ON
PLYWOOD
PLYWOOD AND
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT WE SPEND ON
PLYWOOD AND BOARDING,
PLYWOOD AND BOARDING, AND
IS ON YOUR -- WHAT WE SPEND ON
PLYWOOD AND BOARDING, AND THE
BIG
BIG VACUUMS
PLYWOOD AND BOARDING, AND THE
BIG VACUUMS TO
BIG VACUUMS TO CLEAN
PLYWOOD AND BOARDING, AND THE
BIG VACUUMS TO CLEAN UP
BIG VACUUMS TO CLEAN UP THE
DIRT.
I'M
I'M VERY
DIRT.
I'M VERY HANDS-ON,
I'M VERY HANDS-ON, VERY
PRACTICAL,
PRACTICAL, VERY
I'M VERY HANDS-ON, VERY
PRACTICAL, VERY LET'S
PRACTICAL, VERY LET'S GET
I'M VERY HANDS-ON, VERY
PRACTICAL, VERY LET'S GET IT
DONE.
THAT'S
THAT'S HOW
DONE.
THAT'S HOW I
THAT'S HOW I VIEW
DONE.
THAT'S HOW I VIEW THAT.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: ALL
HILLARY CLINTON: ALL MY
GOODNESS.
THIS
THIS YOUNG
GOODNESS.
THIS YOUNG LADY
THIS YOUNG LADY RIGHT
GOODNESS.
THIS YOUNG LADY RIGHT THERE.
>>
>> THANK
THIS YOUNG LADY RIGHT THERE.
>> THANK YOU.
I
I WAS
>> THANK YOU.
I WAS GOING
I WAS GOING TO
>> THANK YOU.
I WAS GOING TO SAY,
I WAS GOING TO SAY, IT
>> THANK YOU.
I WAS GOING TO SAY, IT HAS
NOTHING
NOTHING TO
I WAS GOING TO SAY, IT HAS
NOTHING TO DO
NOTHING TO DO WITH
I WAS GOING TO SAY, IT HAS
NOTHING TO DO WITH THE
NOTHING TO DO WITH THE WEATHER.
[LAUGHTER]
BY
BY THE
[LAUGHTER]
BY THE TIME
BY THE TIME I
[LAUGHTER]
BY THE TIME I GO
BY THE TIME I GO TO
[LAUGHTER]
BY THE TIME I GO TO COLLEGE,
WHAT
WHAT WOULD
BY THE TIME I GO TO COLLEGE,
WHAT WOULD YOU
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE
BY THE TIME I GO TO COLLEGE,
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE UNITED
STATES
STATES TO
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE UNITED
STATES TO BE
STATES TO BE LIKE?
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
STATES TO BE LIKE?
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT'S
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT'S A
STATES TO BE LIKE?
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT'S A GREAT
QUESTION.
CAN
CAN I
QUESTION.
CAN I ASK
CAN I ASK YOU
QUESTION.
CAN I ASK YOU HOW
CAN I ASK YOU HOW OLD
QUESTION.
CAN I ASK YOU HOW OLD YOU
CAN I ASK YOU HOW OLD YOU ARE
RIGHT
RIGHT NOW?
>>
>> 10
RIGHT NOW?
>> 10 YEARS
>> 10 YEARS OLD.
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
>> 10 YEARS OLD.
HILLARY CLINTON: SO
HILLARY CLINTON: SO I
>> 10 YEARS OLD.
HILLARY CLINTON: SO I HAVE
HILLARY CLINTON: SO I HAVE A
LITTLE
LITTLE TIME,
HILLARY CLINTON: SO I HAVE A
LITTLE TIME, BUT
LITTLE TIME, BUT NOT
HILLARY CLINTON: SO I HAVE A
LITTLE TIME, BUT NOT A
LITTLE TIME, BUT NOT A LOT.
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST OF
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST OF ALL,
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST OF ALL, I
WANTED
WANTED TO
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST OF ALL, I
WANTED TO TRULY
WANTED TO TRULY BE
HILLARY CLINTON: FIRST OF ALL, I
WANTED TO TRULY BE THE
WANTED TO TRULY BE THE COUNTRY
WE
WE ALL
WANTED TO TRULY BE THE COUNTRY
WE ALL LOVE
WE ALL LOVE AND
WANTED TO TRULY BE THE COUNTRY
WE ALL LOVE AND CHERISH.
AND
AND HAS
WE ALL LOVE AND CHERISH.
AND HAS GIVEN
AND HAS GIVEN SO
WE ALL LOVE AND CHERISH.
AND HAS GIVEN SO MUCH
AND HAS GIVEN SO MUCH TO
EVERYONE
EVERYONE OF
AND HAS GIVEN SO MUCH TO
EVERYONE OF US
EVERYONE OF US WHO
AND HAS GIVEN SO MUCH TO
EVERYONE OF US WHO IS
EVERYONE OF US WHO IS HERE
AND HAS GIVEN SO MUCH TO
EVERYONE OF US WHO IS HERE IN
THIS
THIS ROOM
EVERYONE OF US WHO IS HERE IN
THIS ROOM TODAY.
THAT
THAT STILL
THIS ROOM TODAY.
THAT STILL HOLDS
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT
THIS ROOM TODAY.
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT THAT
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT THAT SAME
PROMISE
PROMISE TO
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT THAT SAME
PROMISE TO YOU,
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT THAT SAME
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF YOU
THAT STILL HOLDS OUT THAT SAME
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF YOU WORK
HARD
HARD AND
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF YOU WORK
HARD AND YOU
HARD AND YOU DO
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF YOU WORK
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR PART,
PROMISE TO YOU, BUT IF YOU WORK
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU
WILL
WILL BE
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU
WILL BE ABLE
WILL BE ABLE TO
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU
WILL BE ABLE TO GET
WILL BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD,
HARD AND YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU
WILL BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD, AND
STAY
STAY AHEAD,
WILL BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD, AND
STAY AHEAD, AND
STAY AHEAD, AND PURSUE
WILL BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD, AND
STAY AHEAD, AND PURSUE YOUR
DREAMS.
THAT'S
THAT'S WHAT
DREAMS.
THAT'S WHAT I
THAT'S WHAT I WANT
DREAMS.
THAT'S WHAT I WANT FOR
THAT'S WHAT I WANT FOR EVERY
YOUNG
YOUNG PERSON
THAT'S WHAT I WANT FOR EVERY
YOUNG PERSON IN
YOUNG PERSON IN OUR
THAT'S WHAT I WANT FOR EVERY
YOUNG PERSON IN OUR COUNTRY.
THAT
THAT MEANS
YOUNG PERSON IN OUR COUNTRY.
THAT MEANS WE
THAT MEANS WE GOT
YOUNG PERSON IN OUR COUNTRY.
THAT MEANS WE GOT TO
THAT MEANS WE GOT TO GET
YOUNG PERSON IN OUR COUNTRY.
THAT MEANS WE GOT TO GET THE
ECONOMY
ECONOMY WORKING
THAT MEANS WE GOT TO GET THE
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER SO
THAT MEANS WE GOT TO GET THE
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER SO IT
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER SO IT IT
PRODUCES
PRODUCES MORE
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER SO IT IT
PRODUCES MORE JOBS
PRODUCES MORE JOBS WITH
ECONOMY WORKING BETTER SO IT IT
PRODUCES MORE JOBS WITH RISING
INCOMES,
INCOMES, AND
PRODUCES MORE JOBS WITH RISING
INCOMES, AND I
INCOMES, AND I HAVE
PRODUCES MORE JOBS WITH RISING
INCOMES, AND I HAVE A
INCOMES, AND I HAVE A LOT
PRODUCES MORE JOBS WITH RISING
INCOMES, AND I HAVE A LOT TO
INCOMES, AND I HAVE A LOT TO SAY
ABOUT
ABOUT THAT.
BUT
BUT IT'S
ABOUT THAT.
BUT IT'S REALLY
BUT IT'S REALLY CRITICAL,
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
BUT IT'S REALLY CRITICAL,
BECAUSE I WANT
BECAUSE I WANT YOU
BUT IT'S REALLY CRITICAL,
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO FEEL
BUT IT'S REALLY CRITICAL,
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO FEEL LIKE
WHATEVER
WHATEVER YOU
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO FEEL LIKE
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE TO
BECAUSE I WANT YOU TO FEEL LIKE
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE TO DO,
YOU'RE
YOU'RE GOING
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE TO DO,
YOU'RE GOING TO
YOU'RE GOING TO BE
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE TO DO,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE PART
YOU'RE GOING TO BE PART OF
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE TO DO,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE PART OF THIS
GREAT
GREAT COUNTRY
YOU'RE GOING TO BE PART OF THIS
GREAT COUNTRY OF
GREAT COUNTRY OF OURS.
I
I WANT
GREAT COUNTRY OF OURS.
I WANT THE
I WANT THE EDUCATION
GREAT COUNTRY OF OURS.
I WANT THE EDUCATION SYSTEM
I WANT THE EDUCATION SYSTEM --
IS
IS THAT
I WANT THE EDUCATION SYSTEM --
IS THAT LIKE
IS THAT LIKE IT'S
I WANT THE EDUCATION SYSTEM --
IS THAT LIKE IT'S WORKING
IS THAT LIKE IT'S WORKING PRETTY
WELL
WELL FOR
IS THAT LIKE IT'S WORKING PRETTY
WELL FOR YOU.
I
I WANTED
WELL FOR YOU.
I WANTED TO
I WANTED TO WORK
WELL FOR YOU.
I WANTED TO WORK FOR
I WANTED TO WORK FOR EVERYBODY.
AND
AND PARTICULARLY,
I WANTED TO WORK FOR EVERYBODY.
AND PARTICULARLY, STARTING
AND PARTICULARLY, STARTING WITH
OUR
OUR YOUNGEST
AND PARTICULARLY, STARTING WITH
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO
AND PARTICULARLY, STARTING WITH
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO GET
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO GET THEM
OFF
OFF TO
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO GET THEM
OFF TO A
OFF TO A BETTER
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO GET THEM
OFF TO A BETTER START
OFF TO A BETTER START SO
OUR YOUNGEST KIDS TO GET THEM
OFF TO A BETTER START SO THAT
THEY
THEY CAN
OFF TO A BETTER START SO THAT
THEY CAN BE
THEY CAN BE SUCCESSFUL
OFF TO A BETTER START SO THAT
THEY CAN BE SUCCESSFUL IN
SCHOOL.
AND
AND I
SCHOOL.
AND I WANT
AND I WANT COLLEGE
SCHOOL.
AND I WANT COLLEGE TO
AND I WANT COLLEGE TO BE
AFFORDABLE
AFFORDABLE FOR
AND I WANT COLLEGE TO BE
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU,
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU, SO
AND I WANT COLLEGE TO BE
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU, SO WE
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU, SO WE GOT
AND I WANT COLLEGE TO BE
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU, SO WE GOT TO
GET
GET THE
AFFORDABLE FOR YOU, SO WE GOT TO
GET THE COST
GET THE COST DOWN.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I HAVE
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I HAVE OUTLINED
WHAT
WHAT I
HILLARY CLINTON: I HAVE OUTLINED
WHAT I CALL
WHAT I CALL THE
HILLARY CLINTON: I HAVE OUTLINED
WHAT I CALL THE NEW
WHAT I CALL THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT
COMPACT TO
WHAT I CALL THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT TO DO
COMPACT TO DO JUST
WHAT I CALL THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT TO DO JUST THAT.
I
I JUST
COMPACT TO DO JUST THAT.
I JUST DON'T
I JUST DON'T WANT
COMPACT TO DO JUST THAT.
I JUST DON'T WANT TO
I JUST DON'T WANT TO SEE
COMPACT TO DO JUST THAT.
I JUST DON'T WANT TO SEE YOUNG
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WITH
I JUST DON'T WANT TO SEE YOUNG
PEOPLE WITH AMBITION,
PEOPLE WITH AMBITION, TALENTS,
I JUST DON'T WANT TO SEE YOUNG
PEOPLE WITH AMBITION, TALENTS, A
GOOD
GOOD WORK
PEOPLE WITH AMBITION, TALENTS, A
GOOD WORK ETHIC,
GOOD WORK ETHIC, NOT
PEOPLE WITH AMBITION, TALENTS, A
GOOD WORK ETHIC, NOT BE
GOOD WORK ETHIC, NOT BE ABLE
START
START SCHOOL
GOOD WORK ETHIC, NOT BE ABLE
START SCHOOL OR
START SCHOOL OR FINISH
GOOD WORK ETHIC, NOT BE ABLE
START SCHOOL OR FINISH SCHOOL
BECAUSE
BECAUSE IT'S
START SCHOOL OR FINISH SCHOOL
BECAUSE IT'S TOO
BECAUSE IT'S TOO EXPENSIVE.
AND
AND THEY
BECAUSE IT'S TOO EXPENSIVE.
AND THEY CAN'T
AND THEY CAN'T AFFORD
BECAUSE IT'S TOO EXPENSIVE.
AND THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
WE
WE HAVE
AND THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
WE HAVE GOT
WE HAVE GOT TO
AND THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL WITH
AND THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL WITH THAT,
AND
AND WE'VE
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL WITH THAT,
AND WE'VE GOT
AND WE'VE GOT TO
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL WITH THAT,
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET THE
WE HAVE GOT TO DEAL WITH THAT,
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET THE COST
DOWN
DOWN SO
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET THE COST
DOWN SO THAT
DOWN SO THAT PEOPLE
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET THE COST
DOWN SO THAT PEOPLE DON'T
DOWN SO THAT PEOPLE DON'T GO
INTO
INTO DEBT.
I
I AND
INTO DEBT.
I AND I
I AND I KNOW
INTO DEBT.
I AND I KNOW THAT
I AND I KNOW THAT THIS
INTO DEBT.
I AND I KNOW THAT THIS IS
I AND I KNOW THAT THIS IS A
PROBLEM
PROBLEM IN
I AND I KNOW THAT THIS IS A
PROBLEM IN NEW
PROBLEM IN NEW HAMPSHIRE.
WE
WE HAVE
PROBLEM IN NEW HAMPSHIRE.
WE HAVE TO
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE
PROBLEM IN NEW HAMPSHIRE.
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE THE
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE THE DEATH
OF
OF PEOPLE
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE THE DEATH
OF PEOPLE HAVE
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE THE DEATH
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO THEY
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO THEY CAN
WE HAVE TO REFINANCE THE DEATH
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO THEY CAN BE
MORE
MORE FREE
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO THEY CAN BE
MORE FREE TO
MORE FREE TO PURSUE
OF PEOPLE HAVE SO THEY CAN BE
MORE FREE TO PURSUE THEIR
MORE FREE TO PURSUE THEIR OWN
INTERESTS,
INTERESTS, AND
MORE FREE TO PURSUE THEIR OWN
INTERESTS, AND THEY
INTERESTS, AND THEY CAN
MORE FREE TO PURSUE THEIR OWN
INTERESTS, AND THEY CAN ACTUALLY
MOVE
MOVE OUT
INTERESTS, AND THEY CAN ACTUALLY
MOVE OUT OF
MOVE OUT OF THEIR
INTERESTS, AND THEY CAN ACTUALLY
MOVE OUT OF THEIR PARENTS
MOVE OUT OF THEIR PARENTS HOMES
AND
AND MAYBE
MOVE OUT OF THEIR PARENTS HOMES
AND MAYBE RENT
AND MAYBE RENT OR
MOVE OUT OF THEIR PARENTS HOMES
AND MAYBE RENT OR BUY
AND MAYBE RENT OR BUY ONE.
AND
AND GET
AND MAYBE RENT OR BUY ONE.
AND GET ON
AND GET ON WITH
AND MAYBE RENT OR BUY ONE.
AND GET ON WITH THEIR
AND GET ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
WITH
WITH HEALTH
AND GET ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
WITH HEALTH CARE,
WITH HEALTH CARE, I
AND GET ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
WITH HEALTH CARE, I WANT
WITH HEALTH CARE, I WANT US
AND GET ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
WITH HEALTH CARE, I WANT US TO
HAVE
HAVE MORE
WITH HEALTH CARE, I WANT US TO
HAVE MORE AND
HAVE MORE AND MORE
WITH HEALTH CARE, I WANT US TO
HAVE MORE AND MORE PEOPLE
HAVE MORE AND MORE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE
HAVE INSURANCE,
HAVE MORE AND MORE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE INSURANCE, SO
HAVE INSURANCE, SO THEY
HAVE MORE AND MORE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE INSURANCE, SO THEY HAVE
QUALITY,
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE
HAVE INSURANCE, SO THEY HAVE
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE HEALTH
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE HEALTH CARE.
I
I WANT
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE HEALTH CARE.
I WANT US
I WANT US TO
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE HEALTH CARE.
I WANT US TO DEAL
I WANT US TO DEAL WITH
QUALITY, AFFORDABLE HEALTH CARE.
I WANT US TO DEAL WITH THE
I WANT US TO DEAL WITH THE BIG
SUBSTANCE
SUBSTANCE ABUSE
I WANT US TO DEAL WITH THE BIG
SUBSTANCE ABUSE EPIDEMIC,
SUBSTANCE ABUSE EPIDEMIC, SO
THAT
THAT WE
SUBSTANCE ABUSE EPIDEMIC, SO
THAT WE BEGIN
THAT WE BEGIN TO
SUBSTANCE ABUSE EPIDEMIC, SO
THAT WE BEGIN TO TURN
THAT WE BEGIN TO TURN THE
SUBSTANCE ABUSE EPIDEMIC, SO
THAT WE BEGIN TO TURN THE TIDE
ON
ON HEROIN
THAT WE BEGIN TO TURN THE TIDE
ON HEROIN AND
ON HEROIN AND PILLS,
THAT WE BEGIN TO TURN THE TIDE
ON HEROIN AND PILLS, AND
ON HEROIN AND PILLS, AND OTHER
ADDICTIONS
ADDICTIONS THAT
ON HEROIN AND PILLS, AND OTHER
ADDICTIONS THAT ARE
ADDICTIONS THAT ARE RUINING
PEOPLES
PEOPLES LIVES.
AND
AND GOING
PEOPLES LIVES.
AND GOING BACK
AND GOING BACK TO
PEOPLES LIVES.
AND GOING BACK TO THE
AND GOING BACK TO THE GUN
DISCUSSION,
DISCUSSION, WE
AND GOING BACK TO THE GUN
DISCUSSION, WE HAVE
DISCUSSION, WE HAVE GOT
AND GOING BACK TO THE GUN
DISCUSSION, WE HAVE GOT TO
DISCUSSION, WE HAVE GOT TO HAVE
MORE
MORE TREATMENT
DISCUSSION, WE HAVE GOT TO HAVE
MORE TREATMENT FOR
MORE TREATMENT FOR MENTAL
HEALTH,
HEALTH, WE
MORE TREATMENT FOR MENTAL
HEALTH, WE HAVE
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO
MORE TREATMENT FOR MENTAL
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO FIGURE
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
HOW
HOW TO
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO HELP
HOW TO HELP MORE
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO HELP MORE PEOPLE
HOW TO HELP MORE PEOPLE GET
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO HELP MORE PEOPLE GET THE
TREATMENT,
TREATMENT, ASSUMING
HOW TO HELP MORE PEOPLE GET THE
TREATMENT, ASSUMING IT
TREATMENT, ASSUMING IT IS
AVAILABLE.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT THE
WORLD
WORLD TO
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT THE
WORLD TO BE
WORLD TO BE SAFER,
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT THE
WORLD TO BE SAFER, I
WORLD TO BE SAFER, I WANT
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT THE
WORLD TO BE SAFER, I WANT THE
WORLD
WORLD THAT
WORLD TO BE SAFER, I WANT THE
WORLD THAT YOU
WORLD THAT YOU WILL
WORLD TO BE SAFER, I WANT THE
WORLD THAT YOU WILL BECOME
WORLD THAT YOU WILL BECOME AN
ADULT
ADULT IN
WORLD THAT YOU WILL BECOME AN
ADULT IN THE
ADULT IN THE STILL
WORLD THAT YOU WILL BECOME AN
ADULT IN THE STILL BE
ADULT IN THE STILL BE LED
WORLD THAT YOU WILL BECOME AN
ADULT IN THE STILL BE LED BY
ADULT IN THE STILL BE LED BY THE
UNITED
UNITED STATES,
ADULT IN THE STILL BE LED BY THE
UNITED STATES, BECAUSE
UNITED STATES, BECAUSE THERE
ADULT IN THE STILL BE LED BY THE
UNITED STATES, BECAUSE THERE IS
NO
NO ALTERNATIVE.
THE
THE UNITED
NO ALTERNATIVE.
THE UNITED STATES,
THE UNITED STATES, IF
NO ALTERNATIVE.
THE UNITED STATES, IF WE
THE UNITED STATES, IF WE DON'T
LEAD,
LEAD, NOBODY
THE UNITED STATES, IF WE DON'T
LEAD, NOBODY LEADS.
WE
WE HAVE
LEAD, NOBODY LEADS.
WE HAVE A
WE HAVE A VACUUM.
THE
THE VACUUM
WE HAVE A VACUUM.
THE VACUUM IS
THE VACUUM IS FILLED
WE HAVE A VACUUM.
THE VACUUM IS FILLED BY
THE VACUUM IS FILLED BY A
WE HAVE A VACUUM.
THE VACUUM IS FILLED BY A LOT
THE VACUUM IS FILLED BY A LOT OF
BAD
BAD ACTORS,
THE VACUUM IS FILLED BY A LOT OF
BAD ACTORS, INCLUDING
BAD ACTORS, INCLUDING TERRORIST
GROUPS
GROUPS WHO
BAD ACTORS, INCLUDING TERRORIST
GROUPS WHO WILL
GROUPS WHO WILL TAKE
BAD ACTORS, INCLUDING TERRORIST
GROUPS WHO WILL TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF
OF THEIR
GROUPS WHO WILL TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THEIR NEIGHBORS
OF THEIR NEIGHBORS AND
EVENTUALLY
EVENTUALLY EVEN
OF THEIR NEIGHBORS AND
EVENTUALLY EVEN THREATEN
EVENTUALLY EVEN THREATEN US.
AND
AND I
EVENTUALLY EVEN THREATEN US.
AND I WANT
AND I WANT TO
EVENTUALLY EVEN THREATEN US.
AND I WANT TO PROTECT
AND I WANT TO PROTECT OUR
RIGHTS,
RIGHTS, OUR
AND I WANT TO PROTECT OUR
RIGHTS, OUR CIVIL
RIGHTS, OUR CIVIL RIGHTS,
AND I WANT TO PROTECT OUR
RIGHTS, OUR CIVIL RIGHTS, HUMAN
RIGHTS,
RIGHTS, GAY
RIGHTS, OUR CIVIL RIGHTS, HUMAN
RIGHTS, GAY RIGHTS,
RIGHTS, GAY RIGHTS, WOMEN'S
RIGHTS.
I
I WANT
RIGHTS.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO PROTECT
RIGHTS.
I WANT TO PROTECT THE
I WANT TO PROTECT THE RIGHTS
RIGHTS.
I WANT TO PROTECT THE RIGHTS OF
AMERICANS.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: WE
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE A
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE A LOT
OF
OF WORK
HILLARY CLINTON: WE HAVE A LOT
OF WORK TO
OF WORK TO DO.
I
I CAN'T
OF WORK TO DO.
I CAN'T POSSIBLY,
I CAN'T POSSIBLY, EVEN
OF WORK TO DO.
I CAN'T POSSIBLY, EVEN AS
PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT, DO
I CAN'T POSSIBLY, EVEN AS
PRESIDENT, DO ALL
PRESIDENT, DO ALL OF
I CAN'T POSSIBLY, EVEN AS
PRESIDENT, DO ALL OF THAT.
IT
IT HAS
PRESIDENT, DO ALL OF THAT.
IT HAS TO
IT HAS TO BE
PRESIDENT, DO ALL OF THAT.
IT HAS TO BE DONE
IT HAS TO BE DONE BY
PRESIDENT, DO ALL OF THAT.
IT HAS TO BE DONE BY EVERYBODY
WORKING
WORKING TOGETHER.
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY STANDING
WORKING TOGETHER.
EVERYBODY STANDING UP
EVERYBODY STANDING UP FOR
WORKING TOGETHER.
EVERYBODY STANDING UP FOR THE
KIND
KIND OF
EVERYBODY STANDING UP FOR THE
KIND OF COUNTRY
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT
EVERYBODY STANDING UP FOR THE
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE WANT
EVERYBODY STANDING UP FOR THE
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE WANT TO
LIVE
LIVE IN,
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE WANT TO
LIVE IN, THAT
LIVE IN, THAT WE
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE WANT TO
LIVE IN, THAT WE WANT
LIVE IN, THAT WE WANT TO
KIND OF COUNTRY THAT WE WANT TO
LIVE IN, THAT WE WANT TO SEE
LIVE IN, THAT WE WANT TO SEE FOR
OUR
OUR CHILDREN.
I'M
I'M A
OUR CHILDREN.
I'M A GRANDMOTHER,
I'M A GRANDMOTHER, AS
OUR CHILDREN.
I'M A GRANDMOTHER, AS MAYBE
I'M A GRANDMOTHER, AS MAYBE YOU
KNOW.
I
I WILL
KNOW.
I WILL JUST
I WILL JUST SAY
KNOW.
I WILL JUST SAY THIS.
I
I AM
I WILL JUST SAY THIS.
I AM THE
I AM THE GRANDDAUGHTER
I WILL JUST SAY THIS.
I AM THE GRANDDAUGHTER OF
I AM THE GRANDDAUGHTER OF A
FACTORY
FACTORY WORKER.
MY
MY GRANDFATHER
FACTORY WORKER.
MY GRANDFATHER WORKED
MY GRANDFATHER WORKED AT
FACTORY WORKER.
MY GRANDFATHER WORKED AT THIS
GRAND
GRAND LEASE
MY GRANDFATHER WORKED AT THIS
GRAND LEASE MEALS
GRAND LEASE MEALS --
MY GRANDFATHER WORKED AT THIS
GRAND LEASE MEALS -- MILLS,
GRAND LEASE MEALS -- MILLS, AND
HE
HE DID
GRAND LEASE MEALS -- MILLS, AND
HE DID IT
HE DID IT TO
GRAND LEASE MEALS -- MILLS, AND
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT HIS
GRAND LEASE MEALS -- MILLS, AND
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT HIS FAMILY
AND
AND SO
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT HIS FAMILY
AND SO HIS
AND SO HIS SONS
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT HIS FAMILY
AND SO HIS SONS OF
AND SO HIS SONS OF HAVE
HE DID IT TO SUPPORT HIS FAMILY
AND SO HIS SONS OF HAVE A
AND SO HIS SONS OF HAVE A BETTER
LIFE.
AND
AND THEY
LIFE.
AND THEY DID.
ALL
ALL THREE
AND THEY DID.
ALL THREE OF
ALL THREE OF HIS
AND THEY DID.
ALL THREE OF HIS SONS
ALL THREE OF HIS SONS ENDED
AND THEY DID.
ALL THREE OF HIS SONS ENDED UP
GOING
GOING TO
ALL THREE OF HIS SONS ENDED UP
GOING TO COLLEGE.
MY
MY DAD
GOING TO COLLEGE.
MY DAD STARTED
MY DAD STARTED A
GOING TO COLLEGE.
MY DAD STARTED A SMALL
MY DAD STARTED A SMALL BUSINESS.
IT
IT WAS
MY DAD STARTED A SMALL BUSINESS.
IT WAS REALLY
IT WAS REALLY SMALL,
MY DAD STARTED A SMALL BUSINESS.
IT WAS REALLY SMALL, BUT
IT WAS REALLY SMALL, BUT IT
PROVIDED
PROVIDED A
IT WAS REALLY SMALL, BUT IT
PROVIDED A GOOD
PROVIDED A GOOD MIDDLE-CLASS
LIFE
LIFE FOR
PROVIDED A GOOD MIDDLE-CLASS
LIFE FOR US.
HERE
HERE I
LIFE FOR US.
HERE I AM,
HERE I AM, THIRD-GENERATION,
ASKING
ASKING ALL
HERE I AM, THIRD-GENERATION,
ASKING ALL OF
ASKING ALL OF YOU
HERE I AM, THIRD-GENERATION,
ASKING ALL OF YOU TO
ASKING ALL OF YOU TO ELECT
HERE I AM, THIRD-GENERATION,
ASKING ALL OF YOU TO ELECT A
PRESIDENT.
THAT
THAT IS
PRESIDENT.
THAT IS THE
THAT IS THE AMERICAN
PRESIDENT.
THAT IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
I
I WILL
THAT IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
I WILL DO
I WILL DO WHATEVER
THAT IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
I WILL DO WHATEVER I
I WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN,
THAT IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
I WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN, AS
WILL
WILL MY
I WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN, AS
WILL MY HUSBAND,
WILL MY HUSBAND, TO
I WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN, AS
WILL MY HUSBAND, TO HELP
WILL MY HUSBAND, TO HELP OUR
GRANDDAUGHTER
GRANDDAUGHTER HAVE
WILL MY HUSBAND, TO HELP OUR
GRANDDAUGHTER HAVE THE
GRANDDAUGHTER HAVE THE BEST
POSSIBLE
POSSIBLE LIFE.
BUT
BUT YOU
POSSIBLE LIFE.
BUT YOU KNOW
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT,
POSSIBLE LIFE.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT, THAT'S
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT, THAT'S NOT
ENOUGH.
IT'S
IT'S NOT
ENOUGH.
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
AND
AND THAT'S
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
AND THAT'S WHAT
AND THAT'S WHAT I
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
AND THAT'S WHAT I WANT
AND THAT'S WHAT I WANT PEOPLE
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
AND THAT'S WHAT I WANT PEOPLE TO
UNDERSTAND.
YOU
YOU SHOULDN'T
UNDERSTAND.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO
UNDERSTAND.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO BE
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO BE THE
GRANDDAUGHTER
GRANDDAUGHTER OF
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TO BE THE
GRANDDAUGHTER OF A
GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FORMER
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT OR
GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FORMER
PRESIDENT OR SECRETARY
PRESIDENT OR SECRETARY OF
GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FORMER
PRESIDENT OR SECRETARY OF STATE
TO
TO BELIEVE
PRESIDENT OR SECRETARY OF STATE
TO BELIEVE YOU
TO BELIEVE YOU CAN
PRESIDENT OR SECRETARY OF STATE
TO BELIEVE YOU CAN FULFILL
TO BELIEVE YOU CAN FULFILL YOUR
DREAMS
DREAMS IN
TO BELIEVE YOU CAN FULFILL YOUR
DREAMS IN OUR
DREAMS IN OUR COUNTRY.
YOU
YOU SHOULD
DREAMS IN OUR COUNTRY.
YOU SHOULD BE
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE
DREAMS IN OUR COUNTRY.
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO BE
DREAMS IN OUR COUNTRY.
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO BE THE
AND
AND GRANDDAUGHTER
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO BE THE
AND GRANDDAUGHTER OF
AND GRANDDAUGHTER OF A
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO BE THE
AND GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FACTORY
WORKER
WORKER OR
AND GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FACTORY
WORKER OR THE
WORKER OR THE GRANDSON
AND GRANDDAUGHTER OF A FACTORY
WORKER OR THE GRANDSON OF
WORKER OR THE GRANDSON OF A
TRUCK
TRUCK DRIVER
WORKER OR THE GRANDSON OF A
TRUCK DRIVER AND
TRUCK DRIVER AND HAVE
WORKER OR THE GRANDSON OF A
TRUCK DRIVER AND HAVE THAT
TRUCK DRIVER AND HAVE THAT SAME
OPPORTUNITY.
SO
SO EVERY
OPPORTUNITY.
SO EVERY SINGLE
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY,
OPPORTUNITY.
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY, I'M
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY, I'M GOING
TO
TO WAKE
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY, I'M GOING
TO WAKE UP
TO WAKE UP IN
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY, I'M GOING
TO WAKE UP IN THE
TO WAKE UP IN THE WHITE
SO EVERY SINGLE DAY, I'M GOING
TO WAKE UP IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND
AND I'M
TO WAKE UP IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND I'M GOING
AND I'M GOING TO
TO WAKE UP IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND I'M GOING TO SAY
AND I'M GOING TO SAY TO
TO WAKE UP IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND I'M GOING TO SAY TO MYSELF,
WHAT
WHAT AM
AND I'M GOING TO SAY TO MYSELF,
WHAT AM I
WHAT AM I GOING
AND I'M GOING TO SAY TO MYSELF,
WHAT AM I GOING TO
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO
AND I'M GOING TO SAY TO MYSELF,
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO TODAY
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO TODAY TO
MAKE
MAKE SURE
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO TODAY TO
MAKE SURE EVERY
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO TODAY TO
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD IN
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD IN THIS
COUNTRY
COUNTRY HAS
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD IN THIS
COUNTRY HAS A
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD IN THIS
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE TO
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE TO LIVE
MAKE SURE EVERY CHILD IN THIS
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE TO LIVE UP
TO
TO HIS
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE TO LIVE UP
TO HIS OR
TO HIS OR HER
COUNTRY HAS A CHANCE TO LIVE UP
TO HIS OR HER GOD-GIVEN
POTENTIAL.
THAT
THAT IS
POTENTIAL.
THAT IS MY
THAT IS MY MISSION
POTENTIAL.
THAT IS MY MISSION AS
THAT IS MY MISSION AS PRESIDENT.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: SO
HILLARY CLINTON: SO MANY
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: SO MANY HANDS.
RIGHT
RIGHT THERE.
I
I WILL
RIGHT THERE.
I WILL GIVE
I WILL GIVE YOU
RIGHT THERE.
I WILL GIVE YOU MY
I WILL GIVE YOU MY MICROPHONE.
>>
>> GOOD
I WILL GIVE YOU MY MICROPHONE.
>> GOOD MORNING.
THANK
THANK YOU
>> GOOD MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR
THANK YOU FOR TAKING
>> GOOD MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR TAKING MY
QUESTION.
YOU
YOU ARE
QUESTION.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
EVERY
EVERY DAY
YOU ARE RIGHT.
EVERY DAY OR
EVERY DAY OR EVERY
YOU ARE RIGHT.
EVERY DAY OR EVERY WEEK
EVERY DAY OR EVERY WEEK WE'RE
HEARING
HEARING ABOUT
EVERY DAY OR EVERY WEEK WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT CHILDREN
HEARING ABOUT CHILDREN DYING
EVERY DAY OR EVERY WEEK WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT CHILDREN DYING ON
THE
THE STREETS
HEARING ABOUT CHILDREN DYING ON
THE STREETS OR
THE STREETS OR IN
HEARING ABOUT CHILDREN DYING ON
THE STREETS OR IN THEIR
THE STREETS OR IN THEIR SCHOOLS
AT
AT THE
THE STREETS OR IN THEIR SCHOOLS
AT THE HANDS
AT THE HANDS OF
THE STREETS OR IN THEIR SCHOOLS
AT THE HANDS OF STRANGERS
AT THE HANDS OF STRANGERS WITH
GUNS.
WE
WE ARE
GUNS.
WE ARE ALSO
WE ARE ALSO HEARING
GUNS.
WE ARE ALSO HEARING ABOUT
CHILDREN
CHILDREN DYING
WE ARE ALSO HEARING ABOUT
CHILDREN DYING IN
CHILDREN DYING IN THEIR
WE ARE ALSO HEARING ABOUT
CHILDREN DYING IN THEIR HOMES
CHILDREN DYING IN THEIR HOMES BY
THE
THE HANDS
CHILDREN DYING IN THEIR HOMES BY
THE HANDS OF
THE HANDS OF THEIR
CHILDREN DYING IN THEIR HOMES BY
THE HANDS OF THEIR CAREGIVERS.
WE
WE ARE
THE HANDS OF THEIR CAREGIVERS.
WE ARE SEEING
WE ARE SEEING CHILD
THE HANDS OF THEIR CAREGIVERS.
WE ARE SEEING CHILD POVERTY
CONTINUED
CONTINUED TO
WE ARE SEEING CHILD POVERTY
CONTINUED TO INCREASE
CONTINUED TO INCREASE AS
CHILDREN
CHILDREN SLEPT
CONTINUED TO INCREASE AS
CHILDREN SLEPT THROUGH
CHILDREN SLEPT THROUGH THE
SHREDDED
SHREDDED SAFETY
CHILDREN SLEPT THROUGH THE
SHREDDED SAFETY NET.
AND
AND WE'RE
SHREDDED SAFETY NET.
AND WE'RE HEARING
AND WE'RE HEARING FROM
SHREDDED SAFETY NET.
AND WE'RE HEARING FROM COLLEGE
PROFESSORS
PROFESSORS AND
AND WE'RE HEARING FROM COLLEGE
PROFESSORS AND EMPLOYERS
PROFESSORS AND EMPLOYERS THAT
YOUNG
YOUNG PEOPLE
PROFESSORS AND EMPLOYERS THAT
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE COMING
PROFESSORS AND EMPLOYERS THAT
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE COMING TO
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THEM
NOT
NOT READY
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THEM
NOT READY TO
NOT READY TO LEARN
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THEM
NOT READY TO LEARN OR
NOT READY TO LEARN OR PREPARED
FOR
FOR 20%
NOT READY TO LEARN OR PREPARED
FOR 20% THREE
FOR 20% THREE JOBS.
--
-- FOUR
FOR 20% THREE JOBS.
-- FOUR 21ST
-- FOUR 21ST CENTURY
FOR 20% THREE JOBS.
-- FOUR 21ST CENTURY JOBS.
AS
AS PRESIDENT,
-- FOUR 21ST CENTURY JOBS.
AS PRESIDENT, WHAT
AS PRESIDENT, WHAT POLICIES
WOULD
WOULD YOU
AS PRESIDENT, WHAT POLICIES
WOULD YOU LOOK
WOULD YOU LOOK TO
AS PRESIDENT, WHAT POLICIES
WOULD YOU LOOK TO MOVE
WOULD YOU LOOK TO MOVE FORWARD
IN
IN YOUR
WOULD YOU LOOK TO MOVE FORWARD
IN YOUR FIRST
IN YOUR FIRST 100
WOULD YOU LOOK TO MOVE FORWARD
IN YOUR FIRST 100 DAYS
IN YOUR FIRST 100 DAYS TO
PROTECT
PROTECT OUR
IN YOUR FIRST 100 DAYS TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN,
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN, AND
PREPARE
PREPARE THEM
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN, AND
PREPARE THEM FOR
PREPARE THEM FOR THEIR
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN, AND
PREPARE THEM FOR THEIR FUTURE?
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
PREPARE THEM FOR THEIR FUTURE?
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
SADLY,
SADLY, HER
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
SADLY, HER QUESTION
SADLY, HER QUESTION REALLY
POINTS
POINTS TO
SADLY, HER QUESTION REALLY
POINTS TO WHAT'S
POINTS TO WHAT'S BEEN
SADLY, HER QUESTION REALLY
POINTS TO WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
IN
IN OUR
POINTS TO WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
IN OUR COUNTRY,
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHERE
POINTS TO WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHERE OVER
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHERE OVER THE
LAST
LAST 10
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHERE OVER THE
LAST 10 YEARS,
LAST 10 YEARS, BECAUSE
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHERE OVER THE
LAST 10 YEARS, BECAUSE OF
LAST 10 YEARS, BECAUSE OF THE
GREAT
GREAT RECESSION,
LAST 10 YEARS, BECAUSE OF THE
GREAT RECESSION, BECAUSE
GREAT RECESSION, BECAUSE OF
LAST 10 YEARS, BECAUSE OF THE
GREAT RECESSION, BECAUSE OF THE
HUGE
HUGE LOSS
GREAT RECESSION, BECAUSE OF THE
HUGE LOSS OF
HUGE LOSS OF JOBS
GREAT RECESSION, BECAUSE OF THE
HUGE LOSS OF JOBS AND
HUGE LOSS OF JOBS AND WEALTH
THAT
THAT PEOPLE
HUGE LOSS OF JOBS AND WEALTH
THAT PEOPLE HAD
THAT PEOPLE HAD BUILT
HUGE LOSS OF JOBS AND WEALTH
THAT PEOPLE HAD BUILT UP
THAT PEOPLE HAD BUILT UP BEFORE
2007,
2007, 2008,
THAT PEOPLE HAD BUILT UP BEFORE
2007, 2008, POVERTY
2007, 2008, POVERTY IS
THAT PEOPLE HAD BUILT UP BEFORE
2007, 2008, POVERTY IS ON
2007, 2008, POVERTY IS ON THE
INCREASE.
TODAY,
TODAY, 51%
INCREASE.
TODAY, 51% OF
TODAY, 51% OF THE
INCREASE.
TODAY, 51% OF THE CHILDREN
TODAY, 51% OF THE CHILDREN IN
OUR
OUR PUBLIC
TODAY, 51% OF THE CHILDREN IN
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS ARE
TODAY, 51% OF THE CHILDREN IN
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS ARE ELIGIBLE
FOR
FOR LOW
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS ARE ELIGIBLE
FOR LOW OR
FOR LOW OR REDUCED
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS ARE ELIGIBLE
FOR LOW OR REDUCED COST
FOR LOW OR REDUCED COST OR
OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS ARE ELIGIBLE
FOR LOW OR REDUCED COST OR FREE
LUNCHES.
AND
AND WE
LUNCHES.
AND WE WERE
AND WE WERE ON
LUNCHES.
AND WE WERE ON A
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD
LUNCHES.
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS,
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS, MAY
--
-- WE
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS, MAY
-- WE WERE
-- WE WERE ON
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS, MAY
-- WE WERE ON A
-- WE WERE ON A GOOD
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS, MAY
-- WE WERE ON A GOOD PATH,
-- WE WERE ON A GOOD PATH, MAY
AND WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS, MAY
-- WE WERE ON A GOOD PATH, MAY I
SAY,
SAY, IN
-- WE WERE ON A GOOD PATH, MAY I
SAY, IN THE
SAY, IN THE 90.
--
-- 90'S.
WE
WE WERE
-- 90'S.
WE WERE ON
WE WERE ON A
-- 90'S.
WE WERE ON A GOOD
WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS
-- 90'S.
WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS TO
WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS TO LIFT
MORE
MORE PEOPLE
WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS TO LIFT
MORE PEOPLE OUT
MORE PEOPLE OUT OF
WE WERE ON A GOOD PASS TO LIFT
MORE PEOPLE OUT OF POVERTY,
MORE PEOPLE OUT OF POVERTY, AND
BY
BY LIFTING
MORE PEOPLE OUT OF POVERTY, AND
BY LIFTING FAMILIES
BY LIFTING FAMILIES OUT
MORE PEOPLE OUT OF POVERTY, AND
BY LIFTING FAMILIES OUT OF
POVERTY,
POVERTY, YOU
BY LIFTING FAMILIES OUT OF
POVERTY, YOU HELPED
POVERTY, YOU HELPED TO
BY LIFTING FAMILIES OUT OF
POVERTY, YOU HELPED TO LIFT
CHILDREN
CHILDREN OUT
POVERTY, YOU HELPED TO LIFT
CHILDREN OUT OF
CHILDREN OUT OF POVERTY.
WE
WE ARE
CHILDREN OUT OF POVERTY.
WE ARE GOING
WE ARE GOING TO
CHILDREN OUT OF POVERTY.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO
CHILDREN OUT OF POVERTY.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO REDOUBLE
OUR
OUR EFFORTS,
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO REDOUBLE
OUR EFFORTS, DO
OUR EFFORTS, DO ALL
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO REDOUBLE
OUR EFFORTS, DO ALL OF
OUR EFFORTS, DO ALL OF THAT
AGAIN.
I
I GIVE
AGAIN.
I GIVE PRESIDENT
I GIVE PRESIDENT OBAMA
AGAIN.
I GIVE PRESIDENT OBAMA ENORMOUS
CREDIT
CREDIT FOR
I GIVE PRESIDENT OBAMA ENORMOUS
CREDIT FOR TAKING
CREDIT FOR TAKING US
I GIVE PRESIDENT OBAMA ENORMOUS
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT OF
I GIVE PRESIDENT OBAMA ENORMOUS
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT OF A
DEEP
DEEP DITCH
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT OF A
DEEP DITCH THAT
DEEP DITCH THAT HE
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT OF A
DEEP DITCH THAT HE WAS
DEEP DITCH THAT HE WAS IN
CREDIT FOR TAKING US OUT OF A
DEEP DITCH THAT HE WAS IN WHEN
THE
THE REPUBLICANS
DEEP DITCH THAT HE WAS IN WHEN
THE REPUBLICANS LEFT.
THERE
THERE ARE
THE REPUBLICANS LEFT.
THERE ARE A
THERE ARE A NUMBER
THE REPUBLICANS LEFT.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF THINGS
THE REPUBLICANS LEFT.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF THINGS WE
HAVE
HAVE TO
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF THINGS WE
HAVE TO DO.
THE
THE TOP
HAVE TO DO.
THE TOP OF
THE TOP OF THE
HAVE TO DO.
THE TOP OF THE LIST
THE TOP OF THE LIST IS
HAVE TO DO.
THE TOP OF THE LIST IS MORE
JOBS,
JOBS, RAISE
THE TOP OF THE LIST IS MORE
JOBS, RAISE THEM
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN
THE TOP OF THE LIST IS MORE
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN WAGE
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN WAGE SO
THE TOP OF THE LIST IS MORE
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN WAGE SO THAT
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN WAGE SO THAT
PEOPLE WHO WORK
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL
JOBS, RAISE THEM IN WAGE SO THAT
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL TIME
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL TIME ARE
--
-- RAISE
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL TIME ARE
-- RAISE THE
-- RAISE THE MINIMUM
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL TIME ARE
-- RAISE THE MINIMUM WAGE
-- RAISE THE MINIMUM WAGE SO
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
-- RAISE THE MINIMUM WAGE SO
PEOPLE WHO WORK
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL-TIME
-- RAISE THE MINIMUM WAGE SO
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL-TIME ARE
NOT
NOT STILL
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL-TIME ARE
NOT STILL LIVING
NOT STILL LIVING IN
PEOPLE WHO WORK FULL-TIME ARE
NOT STILL LIVING IN POVERTY,
NOT STILL LIVING IN POVERTY, AND
THEY
THEY CAN
NOT STILL LIVING IN POVERTY, AND
THEY CAN PROVIDE
THEY CAN PROVIDE A
NOT STILL LIVING IN POVERTY, AND
THEY CAN PROVIDE A BETTER
THEY CAN PROVIDE A BETTER LIFE
FOR
FOR THEIR
THEY CAN PROVIDE A BETTER LIFE
FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
MORE
MORE JOBS
FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
MORE JOBS IN
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL,
FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL, AND
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL, AND THERE
ARE
ARE A
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL, AND THERE
ARE A LOT
ARE A LOT OF
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL, AND THERE
ARE A LOT OF GREAT
ARE A LOT OF GREAT PROJECTS,
MORE JOBS IN GENERAL, AND THERE
ARE A LOT OF GREAT PROJECTS, WE
HAVE
HAVE A
ARE A LOT OF GREAT PROJECTS, WE
HAVE A LOT
HAVE A LOT OF
ARE A LOT OF GREAT PROJECTS, WE
HAVE A LOT OF ROADS
HAVE A LOT OF ROADS AND
ARE A LOT OF GREAT PROJECTS, WE
HAVE A LOT OF ROADS AND BRIDGES
AND
AND RAIL
HAVE A LOT OF ROADS AND BRIDGES
AND RAIL TRACK
AND RAIL TRACK AND
HAVE A LOT OF ROADS AND BRIDGES
AND RAIL TRACK AND AIRPORTS
AND RAIL TRACK AND AIRPORTS AND
PORTS
PORTS AND
AND RAIL TRACK AND AIRPORTS AND
PORTS AND EVERYTHING
PORTS AND EVERYTHING ELSE
AND RAIL TRACK AND AIRPORTS AND
PORTS AND EVERYTHING ELSE IN
PORTS AND EVERYTHING ELSE IN OUR
COUNTRY
COUNTRY THAT
PORTS AND EVERYTHING ELSE IN OUR
COUNTRY THAT IS
COUNTRY THAT IS DETERIORATING,
ENTITIES
ENTITIES TO
COUNTRY THAT IS DETERIORATING,
ENTITIES TO BE
ENTITIES TO BE BUILT
COUNTRY THAT IS DETERIORATING,
ENTITIES TO BE BUILT UP,
YOU
YOU --
ENTITIES TO BE BUILT UP,
YOU -- AND
YOU -- AND IT
ENTITIES TO BE BUILT UP,
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS TO
ENTITIES TO BE BUILT UP,
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS TO BE
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS TO BE BUILT
UP,
UP, MAINTAINED,
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS TO BE BUILT
UP, MAINTAINED, SO
UP, MAINTAINED, SO WE
YOU -- AND IT NEEDS TO BE BUILT
UP, MAINTAINED, SO WE ARE
UP, MAINTAINED, SO WE ARE MORE
COMPETITIVE
COMPETITIVE ECONOMICALLY.
THAT
THAT WOULD
COMPETITIVE ECONOMICALLY.
THAT WOULD PUT
THAT WOULD PUT MILLIONS
COMPETITIVE ECONOMICALLY.
THAT WOULD PUT MILLIONS OF
PEOPLE
PEOPLE TO
THAT WOULD PUT MILLIONS OF
PEOPLE TO WORK.
AND
AND I
PEOPLE TO WORK.
AND I THINK
AND I THINK WE
PEOPLE TO WORK.
AND I THINK WE CAN
AND I THINK WE CAN COMBAT
CLIMATE
CLIMATE CHANGE
AND I THINK WE CAN COMBAT
CLIMATE CHANGE BY
CLIMATE CHANGE BY MORE
AND I THINK WE CAN COMBAT
CLIMATE CHANGE BY MORE CLEAN
ENERGY
ENERGY JOBS,
CLIMATE CHANGE BY MORE CLEAN
ENERGY JOBS, WHICH
ENERGY JOBS, WHICH WOULD
CLIMATE CHANGE BY MORE CLEAN
ENERGY JOBS, WHICH WOULD BE
MILLIONS
MILLIONS OF
ENERGY JOBS, WHICH WOULD BE
MILLIONS OF JOBS
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND
ENERGY JOBS, WHICH WOULD BE
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND BUSINESSES,
IF
IF WE
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND BUSINESSES,
IF WE SHIFTED
IF WE SHIFTED THE
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND BUSINESSES,
IF WE SHIFTED THE INCENTIVES
THAT
THAT ARE
IF WE SHIFTED THE INCENTIVES
THAT ARE STILL
THAT ARE STILL IN
IF WE SHIFTED THE INCENTIVES
THAT ARE STILL IN THE
THAT ARE STILL IN THE TAX
IF WE SHIFTED THE INCENTIVES
THAT ARE STILL IN THE TAX CODE
AND
AND OTHER
THAT ARE STILL IN THE TAX CODE
AND OTHER PARTS
AND OTHER PARTS OF
THAT ARE STILL IN THE TAX CODE
AND OTHER PARTS OF OUR
GOVERNMENT
GOVERNMENT FOR
AND OTHER PARTS OF OUR
GOVERNMENT FOR FOSSIL
GOVERNMENT FOR FOSSIL FUELS
AND OTHER PARTS OF OUR
GOVERNMENT FOR FOSSIL FUELS TO
WIND
WIND AND
GOVERNMENT FOR FOSSIL FUELS TO
WIND AND SOLAR
WIND AND SOLAR AND
GOVERNMENT FOR FOSSIL FUELS TO
WIND AND SOLAR AND ADVANCED
BIOFUELS,
BIOFUELS, WE
WIND AND SOLAR AND ADVANCED
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE
WIND AND SOLAR AND ADVANCED
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE A
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE A HEAD
WIND AND SOLAR AND ADVANCED
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE A HEAD ON
THE
THE CLIMATE
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE A HEAD ON
THE CLIMATE CHANGE
THE CLIMATE CHANGE FRONT,
BIOFUELS, WE WOULD BE A HEAD ON
THE CLIMATE CHANGE FRONT, AND
THE CLIMATE CHANGE FRONT, AND WE
WOULD
WOULD BE
THE CLIMATE CHANGE FRONT, AND WE
WOULD BE PUTTING
WOULD BE PUTTING PEOPLE
THE CLIMATE CHANGE FRONT, AND WE
WOULD BE PUTTING PEOPLE TO
WOULD BE PUTTING PEOPLE TO WORK,
AND
AND WE
WOULD BE PUTTING PEOPLE TO WORK,
AND WE ARE
AND WE ARE ALREADY
WOULD BE PUTTING PEOPLE TO WORK,
AND WE ARE ALREADY SEEING
AND WE ARE ALREADY SEEING THAT
IN
IN SOME
AND WE ARE ALREADY SEEING THAT
IN SOME PARTS
IN SOME PARTS OF
AND WE ARE ALREADY SEEING THAT
IN SOME PARTS OF OUR
IN SOME PARTS OF OUR COUNTRY.
WE
WE JUST
IN SOME PARTS OF OUR COUNTRY.
WE JUST NEED
WE JUST NEED TO
IN SOME PARTS OF OUR COUNTRY.
WE JUST NEED TO DO
WE JUST NEED TO DO IT
IN SOME PARTS OF OUR COUNTRY.
WE JUST NEED TO DO IT ALL
WE JUST NEED TO DO IT ALL THE
WAY
WAY ACROSS.
I
I THINK
WAY ACROSS.
I THINK PEOPLE
I THINK PEOPLE WHO
WAY ACROSS.
I THINK PEOPLE WHO WORK
I THINK PEOPLE WHO WORK FOR
CORPORATIONS
CORPORATIONS SHOULD
I THINK PEOPLE WHO WORK FOR
CORPORATIONS SHOULD BE
CORPORATIONS SHOULD BE ABLE
I THINK PEOPLE WHO WORK FOR
CORPORATIONS SHOULD BE ABLE TO
SHARE
SHARE IN
CORPORATIONS SHOULD BE ABLE TO
SHARE IN THE
SHARE IN THE PROFITS,
CORPORATIONS SHOULD BE ABLE TO
SHARE IN THE PROFITS, NOT
SHARE IN THE PROFITS, NOT JUST
THE
THE CEOS,
SHARE IN THE PROFITS, NOT JUST
THE CEOS, BUT
THE CEOS, BUT EVERYBODY.
UP
UP AND
THE CEOS, BUT EVERYBODY.
UP AND DOWN
UP AND DOWN THE
THE CEOS, BUT EVERYBODY.
UP AND DOWN THE LINE
UP AND DOWN THE LINE IN
THE CEOS, BUT EVERYBODY.
UP AND DOWN THE LINE IN THOSE
COMPANIES.
VERY
VERY MUCH
COMPANIES.
VERY MUCH LIKE
VERY MUCH LIKE MARKET
COMPANIES.
VERY MUCH LIKE MARKET BASKET,
PLACE
PLACE YOU
VERY MUCH LIKE MARKET BASKET,
PLACE YOU ALL
PLACE YOU ALL KNOW,
VERY MUCH LIKE MARKET BASKET,
PLACE YOU ALL KNOW, BECAUSE
PLACE YOU ALL KNOW, BECAUSE THEY
NOW
NOW HAVE
PLACE YOU ALL KNOW, BECAUSE THEY
NOW HAVE PROFIT-SHARING
NOW HAVE PROFIT-SHARING FOR
THEIR
THEIR EMPLOYEES.
I
I THINK
THEIR EMPLOYEES.
I THINK WE
I THINK WE NEED
THEIR EMPLOYEES.
I THINK WE NEED TO
I THINK WE NEED TO DO
THEIR EMPLOYEES.
I THINK WE NEED TO DO MORE
I THINK WE NEED TO DO MORE TO
SUPPORT
SUPPORT SMALL
I THINK WE NEED TO DO MORE TO
SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESS,
SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESS, WHICH
CREATES
CREATES 60%
SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESS, WHICH
CREATES 60% OF
CREATES 60% OF THE
SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESS, WHICH
CREATES 60% OF THE JOBS
CREATES 60% OF THE JOBS IN
AMERICA.
RIGHT
RIGHT NOW,
AMERICA.
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE BEHIND
AMERICA.
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE BEHIND IN
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE BEHIND IN SMALL
BUSINESS
BUSINESS CREATION
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE BEHIND IN SMALL
BUSINESS CREATION AND
BUSINESS CREATION AND GROWTH.
WE
WE USED
BUSINESS CREATION AND GROWTH.
WE USED TO
WE USED TO BE
BUSINESS CREATION AND GROWTH.
WE USED TO BE NUMBER
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE,
BUSINESS CREATION AND GROWTH.
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE, WE
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE, WE ARE
NOW
NOW NOT
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE, WE ARE
NOW NOT EVEN
NOW NOT EVEN IN
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE, WE ARE
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE TOP
WE USED TO BE NUMBER ONE, WE ARE
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE TOP 10.
I
I WANT
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE TOP 10.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO DO
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE TOP 10.
I WANT TO DO MORE
I WANT TO DO MORE AND
NOW NOT EVEN IN THE TOP 10.
I WANT TO DO MORE AND MORE
CREDIT,
CREDIT, GET
I WANT TO DO MORE AND MORE
CREDIT, GET RID
CREDIT, GET RID OF
I WANT TO DO MORE AND MORE
CREDIT, GET RID OF REGULATIONS
AND
AND LICENSING
CREDIT, GET RID OF REGULATIONS
AND LICENSING IN
AND LICENSING IN THE
CREDIT, GET RID OF REGULATIONS
AND LICENSING IN THE BARRIERS
THAT
THAT STAND
AND LICENSING IN THE BARRIERS
THAT STAND IN
THAT STAND IN THE
AND LICENSING IN THE BARRIERS
THAT STAND IN THE WAY
THAT STAND IN THE WAY FOR
AND LICENSING IN THE BARRIERS
THAT STAND IN THE WAY FOR PEOPLE
TO
TO START
THAT STAND IN THE WAY FOR PEOPLE
TO START THEIR
TO START THEIR BUSINESS,
THAT STAND IN THE WAY FOR PEOPLE
TO START THEIR BUSINESS, LIKE
TO START THEIR BUSINESS, LIKE MY
DAD
DAD DID.
AND
AND BE
DAD DID.
AND BE ABLE
AND BE ABLE TO
DAD DID.
AND BE ABLE TO PROVIDE
AND BE ABLE TO PROVIDE A
DAD DID.
AND BE ABLE TO PROVIDE A GOOD
MIDDLE-CLASS
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND
AND ONCE
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND ONCE WE
AND ONCE WE GET
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND ONCE WE GET THE
AND ONCE WE GET THE ECONOMY
MOVING
MOVING AGAIN,
AND ONCE WE GET THE ECONOMY
MOVING AGAIN, THEN
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE
AND ONCE WE GET THE ECONOMY
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE CAN
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE CAN TURN
OUR
OUR ATTENTION
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE CAN TURN
OUR ATTENTION TO
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE CAN TURN
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW WE
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW WE CAN
MOVING AGAIN, THEN WE CAN TURN
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW WE CAN BE
GOOD
GOOD PARTNERS
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW WE CAN BE
GOOD PARTNERS WITH
GOOD PARTNERS WITH FAMILIES
OUR ATTENTION TO HOW WE CAN BE
GOOD PARTNERS WITH FAMILIES WITH
CHILDREN
CHILDREN ARE
GOOD PARTNERS WITH FAMILIES WITH
CHILDREN ARE AT
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE
GOOD PARTNERS WITH FAMILIES WITH
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE ARE
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE ARE SOME
GOOD PARTNERS WITH FAMILIES WITH
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE ARE SOME OF
MY
MY THOUGHTS,
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE ARE SOME OF
MY THOUGHTS, AND
MY THOUGHTS, AND I
CHILDREN ARE AT HERE ARE SOME OF
MY THOUGHTS, AND I HAVE
MY THOUGHTS, AND I HAVE WORKED
IN
IN THIS
MY THOUGHTS, AND I HAVE WORKED
IN THIS AREA
IN THIS AREA FOR
MY THOUGHTS, AND I HAVE WORKED
IN THIS AREA FOR A
IN THIS AREA FOR A VERY
MY THOUGHTS, AND I HAVE WORKED
IN THIS AREA FOR A VERY LONG
TIME.
FIRST
FIRST AND
TIME.
FIRST AND FOREMOST,
FIRST AND FOREMOST, WE
TIME.
FIRST AND FOREMOST, WE HAVE
FIRST AND FOREMOST, WE HAVE TO
KEEP
KEEP THEM
FIRST AND FOREMOST, WE HAVE TO
KEEP THEM SAFE.
AND
AND FREE
KEEP THEM SAFE.
AND FREE FROM
AND FREE FROM VIOLENCE
KEEP THEM SAFE.
AND FREE FROM VIOLENCE BY
STRANGERS
STRANGERS OR
AND FREE FROM VIOLENCE BY
STRANGERS OR THOSE
STRANGERS OR THOSE WITHIN
AND FREE FROM VIOLENCE BY
STRANGERS OR THOSE WITHIN THEIR
OWN
OWN HOMES
STRANGERS OR THOSE WITHIN THEIR
OWN HOMES AND
OWN HOMES AND FAMILIES.
WE
WE ALSO
OWN HOMES AND FAMILIES.
WE ALSO NEED
WE ALSO NEED TO
OWN HOMES AND FAMILIES.
WE ALSO NEED TO HELP
WE ALSO NEED TO HELP KIDS
OWN HOMES AND FAMILIES.
WE ALSO NEED TO HELP KIDS WHO
MAY
MAY NOT
WE ALSO NEED TO HELP KIDS WHO
MAY NOT HAVE
MAY NOT HAVE THE
WE ALSO NEED TO HELP KIDS WHO
MAY NOT HAVE THE OPPORTUNITIES
THAT
THAT MANY
MAY NOT HAVE THE OPPORTUNITIES
THAT MANY OF
THAT MANY OF OUR
MAY NOT HAVE THE OPPORTUNITIES
THAT MANY OF OUR KIDS,
THAT MANY OF OUR KIDS, AND
MAY NOT HAVE THE OPPORTUNITIES
THAT MANY OF OUR KIDS, AND MY
GRANDCHILD
GRANDCHILD HAS
THAT MANY OF OUR KIDS, AND MY
GRANDCHILD HAS TO
GRANDCHILD HAS TO GET
THAT MANY OF OUR KIDS, AND MY
GRANDCHILD HAS TO GET AHEAD,
THAT
THAT MEANS
GRANDCHILD HAS TO GET AHEAD,
THAT MEANS YOU
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE
GRANDCHILD HAS TO GET AHEAD,
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE TO
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE TO HAVE
EARLY
EARLY CHILDHOOD
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE TO HAVE
EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT JUST
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT JUST A
NICE
NICE THING
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT JUST A
NICE THING TO
NICE THING TO DO,
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT JUST A
NICE THING TO DO, IF
NICE THING TO DO, IF YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: IT'S NOT JUST A
NICE THING TO DO, IF YOU DON'T
PREPARE
PREPARE KIDS
NICE THING TO DO, IF YOU DON'T
PREPARE KIDS IN
PREPARE KIDS IN THEIR
NICE THING TO DO, IF YOU DON'T
PREPARE KIDS IN THEIR FIRST
PREPARE KIDS IN THEIR FIRST FIVE
YEARS,
YEARS, WHEN
PREPARE KIDS IN THEIR FIRST FIVE
YEARS, WHEN THEY
YEARS, WHEN THEY GET
PREPARE KIDS IN THEIR FIRST FIVE
YEARS, WHEN THEY GET TO
YEARS, WHEN THEY GET TO SCHOOL,
THEY
THEY WILL
YEARS, WHEN THEY GET TO SCHOOL,
THEY WILL BE
THEY WILL BE BEHIND.
THERE
THERE WILL
THEY WILL BE BEHIND.
THERE WILL BE
THERE WILL BE AN
THEY WILL BE BEHIND.
THERE WILL BE AN ACHIEVEMENT
GAP.
AND
AND THEN
GAP.
AND THEN IT'S
AND THEN IT'S REALLY
GAP.
AND THEN IT'S REALLY HARD
AND THEN IT'S REALLY HARD FOR
THE
THE KID
AND THEN IT'S REALLY HARD FOR
THE KID IN
THE KID IN THE
AND THEN IT'S REALLY HARD FOR
THE KID IN THE FAMILY
THE KID IN THE FAMILY OF
AND THEN IT'S REALLY HARD FOR
THE KID IN THE FAMILY OF THE
SCHOOL
SCHOOL TO
THE KID IN THE FAMILY OF THE
SCHOOL TO CLOSE
SCHOOL TO CLOSE THAT
THE KID IN THE FAMILY OF THE
SCHOOL TO CLOSE THAT GAP.
I
I HAPPEN
SCHOOL TO CLOSE THAT GAP.
I HAPPEN TO
I HAPPEN TO THINK
SCHOOL TO CLOSE THAT GAP.
I HAPPEN TO THINK TALENT
I HAPPEN TO THINK TALENT IS
EVERYWHERE.
BUT
BUT I
EVERYWHERE.
BUT I DON'T
BUT I DON'T THINK
EVERYWHERE.
BUT I DON'T THINK OPPORTUNITY
IS.
I
I DON'T
IS.
I DON'T KNOW
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
IS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE LOSING
BECAUSE
BECAUSE WE
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE LOSING
BECAUSE WE HAVE
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE LOSING
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR KIDS
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR KIDS WHO
ARE
ARE NOT
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR KIDS WHO
ARE NOT GIVEN
ARE NOT GIVEN A
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR KIDS WHO
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE TO
BECAUSE WE HAVE POOR KIDS WHO
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE TO REALLY
GET
GET OFF
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE TO REALLY
GET OFF TO
GET OFF TO A
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE TO REALLY
GET OFF TO A GOOD
GET OFF TO A GOOD START,
ARE NOT GIVEN A CHANCE TO REALLY
GET OFF TO A GOOD START, WHOSE
BRAINS
BRAINS ARE
GET OFF TO A GOOD START, WHOSE
BRAINS ARE NOT
BRAINS ARE NOT BEING
GET OFF TO A GOOD START, WHOSE
BRAINS ARE NOT BEING STIMULATED
THIN
THIN --
BRAINS ARE NOT BEING STIMULATED
THIN -- IN
THIN -- IN THE
BRAINS ARE NOT BEING STIMULATED
THIN -- IN THE WAY
THIN -- IN THE WAY THAT
BRAINS ARE NOT BEING STIMULATED
THIN -- IN THE WAY THAT WILL
HELP
HELP THEM
THIN -- IN THE WAY THAT WILL
HELP THEM GET
HELP THEM GET A
THIN -- IN THE WAY THAT WILL
HELP THEM GET A VOCABULARY
HELP THEM GET A VOCABULARY SO
THAT
THAT THEY
HELP THEM GET A VOCABULARY SO
THAT THEY CAN
THAT THEY CAN BE
HELP THEM GET A VOCABULARY SO
THAT THEY CAN BE SUCCESSFUL
THAT THEY CAN BE SUCCESSFUL IN
SCHOOL.
I
I THINK
SCHOOL.
I THINK THE
I THINK THE EARLY
SCHOOL.
I THINK THE EARLY CHILDHOOD
PEACE
PEACE OF
I THINK THE EARLY CHILDHOOD
PEACE OF THIS
PEACE OF THIS IS
I THINK THE EARLY CHILDHOOD
PEACE OF THIS IS VERY
PEACE OF THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
HEALTH
HEALTH CARE
PEACE OF THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
HEALTH CARE IS
HEALTH CARE IS ESSENTIAL.
I
I HELPED
HEALTH CARE IS ESSENTIAL.
I HELPED START
I HELPED START THE
HEALTH CARE IS ESSENTIAL.
I HELPED START THE CHILDREN'S
HEALTH
HEALTH INSURANCE
I HELPED START THE CHILDREN'S
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM BACK
I HELPED START THE CHILDREN'S
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM BACK IN
THE
THE 90'S
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM BACK IN
THE 90'S TO
THE 90'S TO TAKE
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM BACK IN
THE 90'S TO TAKE CARE
THE 90'S TO TAKE CARE OF
HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM BACK IN
THE 90'S TO TAKE CARE OF 8
MILLION
MILLION KIDS.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND
HILLARY CLINTON: AND THAT'S
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: AND THAT'S WHY
I
I FIND
HILLARY CLINTON: AND THAT'S WHY
I FIND STATES
I FIND STATES THAT
HILLARY CLINTON: AND THAT'S WHY
I FIND STATES THAT DON'T
I FIND STATES THAT DON'T WANT
HILLARY CLINTON: AND THAT'S WHY
I FIND STATES THAT DON'T WANT TO
EXPAND
EXPAND MEDICAID
I FIND STATES THAT DON'T WANT TO
EXPAND MEDICAID TO
EXPAND MEDICAID TO BE
I FIND STATES THAT DON'T WANT TO
EXPAND MEDICAID TO BE REALLY
MISSING
MISSING THE
EXPAND MEDICAID TO BE REALLY
MISSING THE BOAT.
WE
WE NEED
MISSING THE BOAT.
WE NEED TO
WE NEED TO HAVE
MISSING THE BOAT.
WE NEED TO HAVE PEOPLE
WE NEED TO HAVE PEOPLE HEALTHY.
HOW
HOW CAN
WE NEED TO HAVE PEOPLE HEALTHY.
HOW CAN WE
HOW CAN WE HAVE
WE NEED TO HAVE PEOPLE HEALTHY.
HOW CAN WE HAVE A
HOW CAN WE HAVE A COMPETITIVE
ECONOMY
ECONOMY IF
HOW CAN WE HAVE A COMPETITIVE
ECONOMY IF THEY
ECONOMY IF THEY CAN'T
HOW CAN WE HAVE A COMPETITIVE
ECONOMY IF THEY CAN'T GET
ECONOMY IF THEY CAN'T GET THEIR
BASIC
BASIC HEALTH
ECONOMY IF THEY CAN'T GET THEIR
BASIC HEALTH NEEDS
BASIC HEALTH NEEDS MET?
THAT'S
THAT'S PARTICULARLY
BASIC HEALTH NEEDS MET?
THAT'S PARTICULARLY TRUE
THAT'S PARTICULARLY TRUE FOR
KIDS.
MY
MY FIRST
KIDS.
MY FIRST JOB
MY FIRST JOB OUT
KIDS.
MY FIRST JOB OUT OF
MY FIRST JOB OUT OF LAW
KIDS.
MY FIRST JOB OUT OF LAW SCHOOL
WAS
WAS WITH
MY FIRST JOB OUT OF LAW SCHOOL
WAS WITH THE
WAS WITH THE CHILDREN'S
MY FIRST JOB OUT OF LAW SCHOOL
WAS WITH THE CHILDREN'S DEFENSE
FUND.
WE
WE WOULD
FUND.
WE WOULD GO
WE WOULD GO INTO
FUND.
WE WOULD GO INTO AREAS
WE WOULD GO INTO AREAS IN
FUND.
WE WOULD GO INTO AREAS IN THE
SCHOOLS
SCHOOLS AND
WE WOULD GO INTO AREAS IN THE
SCHOOLS AND KIDS
SCHOOLS AND KIDS COULDN'T
WE WOULD GO INTO AREAS IN THE
SCHOOLS AND KIDS COULDN'T SEE,
WE
WE STOPPED
SCHOOLS AND KIDS COULDN'T SEE,
WE STOPPED HAVING
WE STOPPED HAVING SCHOOL
SCHOOLS AND KIDS COULDN'T SEE,
WE STOPPED HAVING SCHOOL NURSES,
WE
WE STOPPED
WE STOPPED HAVING SCHOOL NURSES,
WE STOPPED TESTING
WE STOPPED TESTING THEIR
EYESIGHT.
I
I FOUND
EYESIGHT.
I FOUND OUT
I FOUND OUT THAT
EYESIGHT.
I FOUND OUT THAT I
I FOUND OUT THAT I COULDN'T
EYESIGHT.
I FOUND OUT THAT I COULDN'T SEE
IN
IN FOURTH-GRADE.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
IN FOURTH-GRADE.
BECAUSE I DIDN'T
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW
IN FOURTH-GRADE.
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW I
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW I COULDN'T
SEE
SEE VERY
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW I COULDN'T
SEE VERY MY
SEE VERY MY MOTHER
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW I COULDN'T
SEE VERY MY MOTHER WOULD
SEE VERY MY MOTHER WOULD HAVE
TAKEN
TAKEN ME
SEE VERY MY MOTHER WOULD HAVE
TAKEN ME TO
TAKEN ME TO FIND
SEE VERY MY MOTHER WOULD HAVE
TAKEN ME TO FIND OUT,
TAKEN ME TO FIND OUT, BUT
SEE VERY MY MOTHER WOULD HAVE
TAKEN ME TO FIND OUT, BUT I
THOUGHT
THOUGHT THE
TAKEN ME TO FIND OUT, BUT I
THOUGHT THE WORLD
THOUGHT THE WORLD WAS
TAKEN ME TO FIND OUT, BUT I
THOUGHT THE WORLD WAS A
THOUGHT THE WORLD WAS A BIG
IMPRESSIONIST
IMPRESSIONIST PAINTING.
I
I JUST
IMPRESSIONIST PAINTING.
I JUST GOT
I JUST GOT UP
IMPRESSIONIST PAINTING.
I JUST GOT UP REALLY
I JUST GOT UP REALLY CLOSE
IMPRESSIONIST PAINTING.
I JUST GOT UP REALLY CLOSE TO
THE
THE TV
I JUST GOT UP REALLY CLOSE TO
THE TV SET.
THEN
THEN WE
THE TV SET.
THEN WE HAD
THEN WE HAD AND
THE TV SET.
THEN WE HAD AND I
THEN WE HAD AND I EXAMINE
THE TV SET.
THEN WE HAD AND I EXAMINE SCHOOL
--
-- THEN
THEN WE HAD AND I EXAMINE SCHOOL
-- THEN WE
-- THEN WE HAD
THEN WE HAD AND I EXAMINE SCHOOL
-- THEN WE HAD AN
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE
THEN WE HAD AND I EXAMINE SCHOOL
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE EXAM
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE EXAM IN
SCHOOL
SCHOOL AND
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE EXAM IN
SCHOOL AND I
SCHOOL AND I FOUND
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE EXAM IN
SCHOOL AND I FOUND OUT
SCHOOL AND I FOUND OUT I
-- THEN WE HAD AN EYE EXAM IN
SCHOOL AND I FOUND OUT I REALLY
CAN'T
CAN'T SEE.
THERE
THERE ARE
CAN'T SEE.
THERE ARE SO
THERE ARE SO MANY
CAN'T SEE.
THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS
THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS THAT
CAN'T SEE.
THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS THAT ARE
NOT
NOT GETTING
THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS THAT ARE
NOT GETTING THOSE
NOT GETTING THOSE BASIC
THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS THAT ARE
NOT GETTING THOSE BASIC HEALTH
NEEDS
NEEDS MET.
THAT
THAT ALSO
NEEDS MET.
THAT ALSO HOLDS
THAT ALSO HOLDS THEM
NEEDS MET.
THAT ALSO HOLDS THEM BACK.
AND
AND THEN
THAT ALSO HOLDS THEM BACK.
AND THEN OF
AND THEN OF COURSE,
THAT ALSO HOLDS THEM BACK.
AND THEN OF COURSE, ONCE
AND THEN OF COURSE, ONCE WE
THAT ALSO HOLDS THEM BACK.
AND THEN OF COURSE, ONCE WE ARE
IN
IN SCHOOL,
AND THEN OF COURSE, ONCE WE ARE
IN SCHOOL, I
IN SCHOOL, I THINK
AND THEN OF COURSE, ONCE WE ARE
IN SCHOOL, I THINK WE
IN SCHOOL, I THINK WE SHOULD
START
START RESPECTING
IN SCHOOL, I THINK WE SHOULD
START RESPECTING TEACHERS
START RESPECTING TEACHERS AGAIN
WHO
WHO ARE
START RESPECTING TEACHERS AGAIN
WHO ARE ACTUALLY
WHO ARE ACTUALLY IN
START RESPECTING TEACHERS AGAIN
WHO ARE ACTUALLY IN THE
CLASSROOM
CLASSROOM WITH
WHO ARE ACTUALLY IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH THE
CLASSROOM WITH THE KIDS,
WHO ARE ACTUALLY IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH THE KIDS, AND
CLASSROOM WITH THE KIDS, AND TRY
TO
TO HELP
CLASSROOM WITH THE KIDS, AND TRY
TO HELP THEM
TO HELP THEM HELP
CLASSROOM WITH THE KIDS, AND TRY
TO HELP THEM HELP THE
TO HELP THEM HELP THE CHILDREN.
I
I LITERALLY
TO HELP THEM HELP THE CHILDREN.
I LITERALLY COULD
I LITERALLY COULD GO
TO HELP THEM HELP THE CHILDREN.
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON ALL
TO HELP THEM HELP THE CHILDREN.
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON ALL DAY.
I
I WILL
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON ALL DAY.
I WILL JUST
I WILL JUST SAY
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON ALL DAY.
I WILL JUST SAY ONE
I WILL JUST SAY ONE MORE
I LITERALLY COULD GO ON ALL DAY.
I WILL JUST SAY ONE MORE THING.
WE
WE NOW
I WILL JUST SAY ONE MORE THING.
WE NOW HAVE
WE NOW HAVE A
I WILL JUST SAY ONE MORE THING.
WE NOW HAVE A HUNGER
WE NOW HAVE A HUNGER PROBLEM
AGAIN.
A
A LOT
AGAIN.
A LOT OF
A LOT OF US
AGAIN.
A LOT OF US THOUGHT
A LOT OF US THOUGHT THAT
AGAIN.
A LOT OF US THOUGHT THAT WAS
BEHIND
BEHIND US.
WE
WE HAVE
BEHIND US.
WE HAVE BOTH
WE HAVE BOTH A
BEHIND US.
WE HAVE BOTH A HUNGER
WE HAVE BOTH A HUNGER AND
BEHIND US.
WE HAVE BOTH A HUNGER AND A
NUTRITION
NUTRITION PROBLEM.
WE
WE HAVE
NUTRITION PROBLEM.
WE HAVE MAYBE
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT
NUTRITION PROBLEM.
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT THE
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT THE KIND
NUTRITION PROBLEM.
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT THE KIND OF
HUNGER
HUNGER THAT
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT THE KIND OF
HUNGER THAT TURNS
HUNGER THAT TURNS PEOPLE
WE HAVE MAYBE NOT THE KIND OF
HUNGER THAT TURNS PEOPLE INTO
WHAT
WHAT IS
HUNGER THAT TURNS PEOPLE INTO
WHAT IS OBVIOUSLY
WHAT IS OBVIOUSLY PHYSICAL
MALNUTRITION.
BUT
BUT WE
MALNUTRITION.
BUT WE DON'T
BUT WE DON'T HAVE
MALNUTRITION.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE ADEQUATE
NUTRITION
NUTRITION IN
BUT WE DON'T HAVE ADEQUATE
NUTRITION IN A
NUTRITION IN A LOT
BUT WE DON'T HAVE ADEQUATE
NUTRITION IN A LOT OF
NEIGHBORHOODS
NEIGHBORHOODS AND
NUTRITION IN A LOT OF
NEIGHBORHOODS AND COMMUNITIES,
AND
AND WE
NEIGHBORHOODS AND COMMUNITIES,
AND WE DON'T
AND WE DON'T HAVE
NEIGHBORHOODS AND COMMUNITIES,
AND WE DON'T HAVE A
AND WE DON'T HAVE A LOT
NEIGHBORHOODS AND COMMUNITIES,
AND WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
FAMILIES
FAMILIES WHO
AND WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
FAMILIES WHO UNDERSTAND
FAMILIES WHO UNDERSTAND HOW
AND WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
FAMILIES WHO UNDERSTAND HOW TO
BEST
BEST FEED
FAMILIES WHO UNDERSTAND HOW TO
BEST FEED THEIR
BEST FEED THEIR KIDS,
FAMILIES WHO UNDERSTAND HOW TO
BEST FEED THEIR KIDS, BECAUSE
WHAT
WHAT THEY
BEST FEED THEIR KIDS, BECAUSE
WHAT THEY CAN
WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD
BEST FEED THEIR KIDS, BECAUSE
WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD IS
WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD IS NOT
NECESSARILY
NECESSARILY GOOD
WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD IS NOT
NECESSARILY GOOD FOR
NECESSARILY GOOD FOR THEIR
WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD IS NOT
NECESSARILY GOOD FOR THEIR KIDS.
BUT
BUT IT'S
NECESSARILY GOOD FOR THEIR KIDS.
BUT IT'S AFFORDABLE.
YOU
YOU KNOW
BUT IT'S AFFORDABLE.
YOU KNOW WE
YOU KNOW WE NEED
BUT IT'S AFFORDABLE.
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO
BUT IT'S AFFORDABLE.
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO MORE
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO MORE WORK
ON
ON THIS
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO MORE WORK
ON THIS TO
ON THIS TO GET
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO MORE WORK
ON THIS TO GET BACK
ON THIS TO GET BACK TO
YOU KNOW WE NEED TO DO MORE WORK
ON THIS TO GET BACK TO WHERE
THERE
THERE ISN'T
ON THIS TO GET BACK TO WHERE
THERE ISN'T THAT
THERE ISN'T THAT SENSE
ON THIS TO GET BACK TO WHERE
THERE ISN'T THAT SENSE OF
THERE ISN'T THAT SENSE OF EITHER
HUNGER
HUNGER OR
THERE ISN'T THAT SENSE OF EITHER
HUNGER OR POOR
HUNGER OR POOR NUTRITION
THERE ISN'T THAT SENSE OF EITHER
HUNGER OR POOR NUTRITION I
HUNGER OR POOR NUTRITION I CAN
REALLY
REALLY AFFECT
HUNGER OR POOR NUTRITION I CAN
REALLY AFFECT A
REALLY AFFECT A CHILD'S
DEVELOPED.
THIS
THIS IS
DEVELOPED.
THIS IS SOMETHING
THIS IS SOMETHING I
DEVELOPED.
THIS IS SOMETHING I WOULD
THIS IS SOMETHING I WOULD DO
DEVELOPED.
THIS IS SOMETHING I WOULD DO AS
PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT, BUT
THIS IS SOMETHING I WOULD DO AS
PRESIDENT, BUT I
PRESIDENT, BUT I WOULD
THIS IS SOMETHING I WOULD DO AS
PRESIDENT, BUT I WOULD ASK
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY TO
PRESIDENT, BUT I WOULD ASK
EVERYBODY TO HELP
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME
PRESIDENT, BUT I WOULD ASK
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME DO,
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME DO, BECAUSE
THERE
THERE IS
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME DO, BECAUSE
THERE IS WORK
THERE IS WORK TO
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME DO, BECAUSE
THERE IS WORK TO BE
THERE IS WORK TO BE DONE
EVERYBODY TO HELP ME DO, BECAUSE
THERE IS WORK TO BE DONE IN
EVERY
EVERY COMMUNITY,
THERE IS WORK TO BE DONE IN
EVERY COMMUNITY, INCLUDING
MANCHESTER.
THE
THE GENTLEMAN
MANCHESTER.
THE GENTLEMAN IN
THE GENTLEMAN IN THE
MANCHESTER.
THE GENTLEMAN IN THE BLUE
THE GENTLEMAN IN THE BLUE SHIRT.
[APPLAUSE]
>>
>> HELLO.
I
I GUESS
>> HELLO.
I GUESS I'M
I GUESS I'M WONDERING
>> HELLO.
I GUESS I'M WONDERING WHAT
I GUESS I'M WONDERING WHAT WE'RE
GOING
GOING TO
I GUESS I'M WONDERING WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO DO
GOING TO DO ABOUT
I GUESS I'M WONDERING WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO DO ABOUT MENTAL
GOING TO DO ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH
IN
IN THIS
GOING TO DO ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH
IN THIS COUNTRY?
THIS
THIS COME
IN THIS COUNTRY?
THIS COME UP
THIS COME UP SO
IN THIS COUNTRY?
THIS COME UP SO MUCH
THIS COME UP SO MUCH WITH
SUBSTANCE
SUBSTANCE ABUSE
THIS COME UP SO MUCH WITH
SUBSTANCE ABUSE TO
SUBSTANCE ABUSE TO VARIOUS
SHOOTINGS
SHOOTINGS --
SUBSTANCE ABUSE TO VARIOUS
SHOOTINGS -- JUST
SHOOTINGS -- JUST THE
SUBSTANCE ABUSE TO VARIOUS
SHOOTINGS -- JUST THE GENERAL
STATE
STATE OF
SHOOTINGS -- JUST THE GENERAL
STATE OF OUR
STATE OF OUR LACK
SHOOTINGS -- JUST THE GENERAL
STATE OF OUR LACK OF
STATE OF OUR LACK OF FUNDING
SHOOTINGS -- JUST THE GENERAL
STATE OF OUR LACK OF FUNDING FOR
ALL
ALL OF
STATE OF OUR LACK OF FUNDING FOR
ALL OF THE
ALL OF THE SERVICE
STATE OF OUR LACK OF FUNDING FOR
ALL OF THE SERVICE PROVIDERS
ALL OF THE SERVICE PROVIDERS OUT
THERE.
I
I THINK
THERE.
I THINK THIS
I THINK THIS ALL
THERE.
I THINK THIS ALL HAPPENED
I THINK THIS ALL HAPPENED AFTER
WE
WE DE-INSTITUTIONALIZED
I THINK THIS ALL HAPPENED AFTER
WE DE-INSTITUTIONALIZED MENTAL
HEALTH,
HEALTH, AND
WE DE-INSTITUTIONALIZED MENTAL
HEALTH, AND WE
HEALTH, AND WE HAD
WE DE-INSTITUTIONALIZED MENTAL
HEALTH, AND WE HAD A
HEALTH, AND WE HAD A PROMISE
WE DE-INSTITUTIONALIZED MENTAL
HEALTH, AND WE HAD A PROMISE TO
FUND
FUND IT,
HEALTH, AND WE HAD A PROMISE TO
FUND IT, BUT
FUND IT, BUT WE
HEALTH, AND WE HAD A PROMISE TO
FUND IT, BUT WE NEVER
FUND IT, BUT WE NEVER DID.
HOW
HOW ARE
FUND IT, BUT WE NEVER DID.
HOW ARE YOU
HOW ARE YOU GOING
FUND IT, BUT WE NEVER DID.
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO CHANGE
THAT?
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
THAT?
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU
HILLARY CLINTON: YOU ARE
ABSOLUTELY
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
SOME
SOME OF
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
SOME OF YOU
SOME OF YOU ARE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
SOME OF YOU ARE MEMBER
SOME OF YOU ARE MEMBER THAT.
--
-- SOME
SOME OF YOU ARE MEMBER THAT.
-- SOME OF
-- SOME OF YOU
SOME OF YOU ARE MEMBER THAT.
-- SOME OF YOU REMEMBER
-- SOME OF YOU REMEMBER THAT,
RIGHT?
BACK
BACK IN
RIGHT?
BACK IN THE
BACK IN THE 1980'S,
RIGHT?
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE HAD
RIGHT?
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE HAD A
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE HAD A LOT
OF
OF DEBATE
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE HAD A LOT
OF DEBATE OVER
OF DEBATE OVER BIG
BACK IN THE 1980'S, WE HAD A LOT
OF DEBATE OVER BIG INSTITUTIONS,
WHERE
WHERE PEOPLE
OF DEBATE OVER BIG INSTITUTIONS,
WHERE PEOPLE WERE
WHERE PEOPLE WERE HOUSED,
OF DEBATE OVER BIG INSTITUTIONS,
WHERE PEOPLE WERE HOUSED, BUT
WHERE PEOPLE WERE HOUSED, BUT IN
MANY
MANY CASES,
WHERE PEOPLE WERE HOUSED, BUT IN
MANY CASES, THEY
MANY CASES, THEY WERE
WAREHOUSED.
AND
AND THE
WAREHOUSED.
AND THE RESULTS
AND THE RESULTS OF
WAREHOUSED.
AND THE RESULTS OF A
AND THE RESULTS OF A LOT
WAREHOUSED.
AND THE RESULTS OF A LOT OF
INVESTIGATIONS
INVESTIGATIONS WHICH
AND THE RESULTS OF A LOT OF
INVESTIGATIONS WHICH SHOWED
INVESTIGATIONS WHICH SHOWED HOW
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WERE
INVESTIGATIONS WHICH SHOWED HOW
PEOPLE WERE NOT
PEOPLE WERE NOT BE
INVESTIGATIONS WHICH SHOWED HOW
PEOPLE WERE NOT BE ADEQUATELY
CARED
CARED FOR
PEOPLE WERE NOT BE ADEQUATELY
CARED FOR WAS
CARED FOR WAS TO
PEOPLE WERE NOT BE ADEQUATELY
CARED FOR WAS TO SHUT
CARED FOR WAS TO SHUT DOWN
PEOPLE WERE NOT BE ADEQUATELY
CARED FOR WAS TO SHUT DOWN A
CARED FOR WAS TO SHUT DOWN A LOT
OF
OF THE
CARED FOR WAS TO SHUT DOWN A LOT
OF THE INSTITUTIONS.
AT
AT THE
OF THE INSTITUTIONS.
AT THE SAME
AT THE SAME TIME,
OF THE INSTITUTIONS.
AT THE SAME TIME, THOSE
AT THE SAME TIME, THOSE WHO
OF THE INSTITUTIONS.
AT THE SAME TIME, THOSE WHO ARE
WORRIED
WORRIED ABOUT
AT THE SAME TIME, THOSE WHO ARE
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT WOULD
AT THE SAME TIME, THOSE WHO ARE
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO
TO PEOPLE
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO PEOPLE IF
TO PEOPLE IF THERE
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO PEOPLE IF THERE WERE
TO PEOPLE IF THERE WERE NO
WORRIED ABOUT WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO PEOPLE IF THERE WERE NO PLACE
FOR
FOR THEM
TO PEOPLE IF THERE WERE NO PLACE
FOR THEM WERE
FOR THEM WERE GUARANTEED
TO PEOPLE IF THERE WERE NO PLACE
FOR THEM WERE GUARANTEED WE
WOULD
WOULD HAVE
FOR THEM WERE GUARANTEED WE
WOULD HAVE FUNDING
WOULD HAVE FUNDING AND
FOR THEM WERE GUARANTEED WE
WOULD HAVE FUNDING AND TIMIDITY
ALTERNATIVES
ALTERNATIVES FOR
WOULD HAVE FUNDING AND TIMIDITY
ALTERNATIVES FOR MENTAL
ALTERNATIVES FOR MENTAL HEALTH.
SO
SO WE
ALTERNATIVES FOR MENTAL HEALTH.
SO WE SHUT
SO WE SHUT DOWN
ALTERNATIVES FOR MENTAL HEALTH.
SO WE SHUT DOWN THE
INSTITUTIONS,
INSTITUTIONS, BY
SO WE SHUT DOWN THE
INSTITUTIONS, BY AND
INSTITUTIONS, BY AND LARGE,
SO WE SHUT DOWN THE
INSTITUTIONS, BY AND LARGE, AND
WE
WE NEVER
INSTITUTIONS, BY AND LARGE, AND
WE NEVER REALLY
WE NEVER REALLY INVESTED
INSTITUTIONS, BY AND LARGE, AND
WE NEVER REALLY INVESTED WHAT
WE NEVER REALLY INVESTED WHAT WE
SHOULD
SHOULD IN
WE NEVER REALLY INVESTED WHAT WE
SHOULD IN MENTAL
SHOULD IN MENTAL HEALTH
ALTERNATIVES.
THAT'S
THAT'S GOING
ALTERNATIVES.
THAT'S GOING TO
THAT'S GOING TO BE
ALTERNATIVES.
THAT'S GOING TO BE SOMETHING
THAT
THAT I
THAT'S GOING TO BE SOMETHING
THAT I PUSH
THAT I PUSH VERY
THAT'S GOING TO BE SOMETHING
THAT I PUSH VERY HARD.
AS
AS YOU
THAT I PUSH VERY HARD.
AS YOU MENTIONED
AS YOU MENTIONED GUN
THAT I PUSH VERY HARD.
AS YOU MENTIONED GUN VIOLENCE,
WHICH
WHICH IS
AS YOU MENTIONED GUN VIOLENCE,
WHICH IS SOMETHING
WHICH IS SOMETHING THAT
AS YOU MENTIONED GUN VIOLENCE,
WHICH IS SOMETHING THAT IS
WHICH IS SOMETHING THAT IS OFTEN
DIRECTLY
DIRECTLY RELATED
WHICH IS SOMETHING THAT IS OFTEN
DIRECTLY RELATED TO
DIRECTLY RELATED TO MENTAL
HEALTH
HEALTH PROBLEMS.
THE
THE ADDICTION
HEALTH PROBLEMS.
THE ADDICTION ISSUE,
THE ADDICTION ISSUE, A
HEALTH PROBLEMS.
THE ADDICTION ISSUE, A LOT
THE ADDICTION ISSUE, A LOT OF
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WITH
THE ADDICTION ISSUE, A LOT OF
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH
CHALLENGES
CHALLENGES ARE
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH
CHALLENGES ARE SELF-MEDICATING
WITH
WITH ALCOHOL
CHALLENGES ARE SELF-MEDICATING
WITH ALCOHOL AND
WITH ALCOHOL AND DRUGS.
SO
SO THAN
WITH ALCOHOL AND DRUGS.
SO THAN THEY
SO THAN THEY HAVE
WITH ALCOHOL AND DRUGS.
SO THAN THEY HAVE A
SO THAN THEY HAVE A DUAL
WITH ALCOHOL AND DRUGS.
SO THAN THEY HAVE A DUAL PROBLEM
THAT
THAT HAS
SO THAN THEY HAVE A DUAL PROBLEM
THAT HAS TO
THAT HAS TO BE
SO THAN THEY HAVE A DUAL PROBLEM
THAT HAS TO BE ADDRESSED.
I
I THINK
THAT HAS TO BE ADDRESSED.
I THINK AS
I THINK AS WE
THAT HAS TO BE ADDRESSED.
I THINK AS WE MOVE
I THINK AS WE MOVE FORWARD
THAT HAS TO BE ADDRESSED.
I THINK AS WE MOVE FORWARD WITH
THE
THE A
I THINK AS WE MOVE FORWARD WITH
THE A AFFORDABLE
THE A AFFORDABLE CARE
I THINK AS WE MOVE FORWARD WITH
THE A AFFORDABLE CARE ACT,
THE A AFFORDABLE CARE ACT, WE
HAVE
HAVE TO
THE A AFFORDABLE CARE ACT, WE
HAVE TO ENFORCE
HAVE TO ENFORCE THE
THE A AFFORDABLE CARE ACT, WE
HAVE TO ENFORCE THE DECISION
THAT
THAT WAS
HAVE TO ENFORCE THE DECISION
THAT WAS MADE,
THAT WAS MADE, THAT
HAVE TO ENFORCE THE DECISION
THAT WAS MADE, THAT PEOPLE
THAT WAS MADE, THAT PEOPLE WITH
PHYSICAL
PHYSICAL HEALTH
THAT WAS MADE, THAT PEOPLE WITH
PHYSICAL HEALTH AND
PHYSICAL HEALTH AND MENTAL
HEALTH
HEALTH CAN
PHYSICAL HEALTH AND MENTAL
HEALTH CAN GET
HEALTH CAN GET TREATMENT.
THE
THE RIGHT
HEALTH CAN GET TREATMENT.
THE RIGHT NOW,
THE RIGHT NOW, A
HEALTH CAN GET TREATMENT.
THE RIGHT NOW, A LOT
THE RIGHT NOW, A LOT OF
INSURANCE
INSURANCE COMPANIES,
THE RIGHT NOW, A LOT OF
INSURANCE COMPANIES, A
INSURANCE COMPANIES, A LOT
THE RIGHT NOW, A LOT OF
INSURANCE COMPANIES, A LOT OF
STATES,
STATES, A
INSURANCE COMPANIES, A LOT OF
STATES, A LOT
STATES, A LOT OF
INSURANCE COMPANIES, A LOT OF
STATES, A LOT OF BUSINESSES
STATES, A LOT OF BUSINESSES ARE
NOT
NOT PROVIDING
STATES, A LOT OF BUSINESSES ARE
NOT PROVIDING THE
NOT PROVIDING THE KIND
STATES, A LOT OF BUSINESSES ARE
NOT PROVIDING THE KIND OF
SUPPORT
SUPPORT YOU
NOT PROVIDING THE KIND OF
SUPPORT YOU NEED
SUPPORT YOU NEED FOR
NOT PROVIDING THE KIND OF
SUPPORT YOU NEED FOR MENTAL
HEALTH.
WHEN
WHEN SOMEBODY
HEALTH.
WHEN SOMEBODY IS
WHEN SOMEBODY IS EITHER
CONVINCED,
CONVINCED, OR
WHEN SOMEBODY IS EITHER
CONVINCED, OR DECIDES
CONVINCED, OR DECIDES TO
WHEN SOMEBODY IS EITHER
CONVINCED, OR DECIDES TO SEEK
MENTAL
MENTAL HEALTH
CONVINCED, OR DECIDES TO SEEK
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS, THEY
VERY
VERY OFTEN
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS, THEY
VERY OFTEN ARE
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS, THEY
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE HAVE
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS, THEY
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE HAVE NO
PLACE
PLACE FOR
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE HAVE NO
PLACE FOR YOU,
PLACE FOR YOU, COME
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE HAVE NO
PLACE FOR YOU, COME BACK
PLACE FOR YOU, COME BACK IN
VERY OFTEN ARE TOLD WE HAVE NO
PLACE FOR YOU, COME BACK IN SIX
WEEKS
WEEKS OR
PLACE FOR YOU, COME BACK IN SIX
WEEKS OR THREE
WEEKS OR THREE MONTHS,
PLACE FOR YOU, COME BACK IN SIX
WEEKS OR THREE MONTHS, AND
WEEKS OR THREE MONTHS, AND WHO
KNOWS
KNOWS WHAT
WEEKS OR THREE MONTHS, AND WHO
KNOWS WHAT WILL
KNOWS WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
YOU
YOU KNOW
KNOWS WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU KNOW WHERE MOST
KNOWS WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
YOU KNOW WHERE MOST PEOPLE
YOU KNOW WHERE MOST PEOPLE NOW
WHO
WHO ARE
YOU KNOW WHERE MOST PEOPLE NOW
WHO ARE PRESENTING
WHO ARE PRESENTING WITH
YOU KNOW WHERE MOST PEOPLE NOW
WHO ARE PRESENTING WITH MENTAL
HEALTH
HEALTH PROBLEMS
WHO ARE PRESENTING WITH MENTAL
HEALTH PROBLEMS SHOW
HEALTH PROBLEMS SHOW UP?
THEY
THEY ARE
HEALTH PROBLEMS SHOW UP?
THEY ARE IN
THEY ARE IN OUR
HEALTH PROBLEMS SHOW UP?
THEY ARE IN OUR JAILS
THEY ARE IN OUR JAILS IN
HEALTH PROBLEMS SHOW UP?
THEY ARE IN OUR JAILS IN OUR
PRISONS.
IT'S
IT'S UNDERSTANDABLE,
PRISONS.
IT'S UNDERSTANDABLE, BECAUSE
THEY
THEY ARE
IT'S UNDERSTANDABLE, BECAUSE
THEY ARE HARM
THEY ARE HARM TO
IT'S UNDERSTANDABLE, BECAUSE
THEY ARE HARM TO THEMSELVES
THEY ARE HARM TO THEMSELVES OR
TO
TO OTHERS.
THEY
THEY OFTEN
TO OTHERS.
THEY OFTEN ACT
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT
TO OTHERS.
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT IN
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT IN A
TO OTHERS.
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT IN A WAY
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT IN A WAY THAT
DRAWS
DRAWS ATTENTION
THEY OFTEN ACT OUT IN A WAY THAT
DRAWS ATTENTION OF
DRAWS ATTENTION OF LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
AND
AND IN
ENFORCEMENT.
AND IN MOST
AND IN MOST PLACES
ENFORCEMENT.
AND IN MOST PLACES IN
AND IN MOST PLACES IN THE
COUNTRY,
COUNTRY, THERE
AND IN MOST PLACES IN THE
COUNTRY, THERE IS
COUNTRY, THERE IS NOWHERE
AND IN MOST PLACES IN THE
COUNTRY, THERE IS NOWHERE ELSE
FOR
FOR THEM
COUNTRY, THERE IS NOWHERE ELSE
FOR THEM TO
FOR THEM TO GO,
COUNTRY, THERE IS NOWHERE ELSE
FOR THEM TO GO, SO
FOR THEM TO GO, SO THEY
COUNTRY, THERE IS NOWHERE ELSE
FOR THEM TO GO, SO THEY ARE
FOR THEM TO GO, SO THEY ARE PUT
IN
IN JAIL.
AND
AND THEY
IN JAIL.
AND THEY MAY
AND THEY MAY BE
IN JAIL.
AND THEY MAY BE HELD
AND THEY MAY BE HELD THERE
IN JAIL.
AND THEY MAY BE HELD THERE FOR
AND THEY MAY BE HELD THERE FOR A
LONG
LONG TIME.
WITHOUT
WITHOUT ANY
LONG TIME.
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT,
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT, AND
LONG TIME.
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT, AND IN
THE
THE END
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT, AND IN
THE END OF
THE END OF IN
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT, AND IN
THE END OF IN PRISON,
THE END OF IN PRISON, THEY
WITHOUT ANY TREATMENT, AND IN
THE END OF IN PRISON, THEY ARE
STILL
STILL NOT
THE END OF IN PRISON, THEY ARE
STILL NOT GETTING
STILL NOT GETTING ADEQUATE
TREATMENTS.
THE
THE OTHER
TREATMENTS.
THE OTHER POINT
THE OTHER POINT I
TREATMENTS.
THE OTHER POINT I WANT
THE OTHER POINT I WANT TO
TREATMENTS.
THE OTHER POINT I WANT TO SAY
ABOUT
ABOUT THIS
THE OTHER POINT I WANT TO SAY
ABOUT THIS IS,
ABOUT THIS IS, BECAUSE
THE OTHER POINT I WANT TO SAY
ABOUT THIS IS, BECAUSE WE
ABOUT THIS IS, BECAUSE WE HAVE
OVER
OVER PRESCRIBED
ABOUT THIS IS, BECAUSE WE HAVE
OVER PRESCRIBED PAINKILLERS,
OVER PRESCRIBED PAINKILLERS, THE
OPIOIDS
OPIOIDS WE
OVER PRESCRIBED PAINKILLERS, THE
OPIOIDS WE HAVE
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A
OVER PRESCRIBED PAINKILLERS, THE
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A LOT
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A LOT OF
OVER PRESCRIBED PAINKILLERS, THE
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO
WHO HAVE
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE GOTTEN
WHO HAVE GOTTEN VERY
OPIOIDS WE HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE GOTTEN VERY ADDICTED
WHO HAVE GOTTEN VERY ADDICTED TO
THEM.
AND
AND THAT
THEM.
AND THAT CREATES
AND THAT CREATES A
THEM.
AND THAT CREATES A MENTAL
AND THAT CREATES A MENTAL STRAIN
ON
ON TOP
AND THAT CREATES A MENTAL STRAIN
ON TOP OF
ON TOP OF WHATEVER
AND THAT CREATES A MENTAL STRAIN
ON TOP OF WHATEVER OTHER
PROBLEMS
PROBLEMS YOU
ON TOP OF WHATEVER OTHER
PROBLEMS YOU MIGHT
PROBLEMS YOU MIGHT HAVE.
AND
AND SO
PROBLEMS YOU MIGHT HAVE.
AND SO WE
AND SO WE NOW
PROBLEMS YOU MIGHT HAVE.
AND SO WE NOW HAVE
AND SO WE NOW HAVE A
PROBLEMS YOU MIGHT HAVE.
AND SO WE NOW HAVE A LOT
AND SO WE NOW HAVE A LOT OF
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
AND SO WE NOW HAVE A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE TO
AND SO WE NOW HAVE A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE TO TRY
PEOPLE WHO HAVE TO TRY AND
WITHDRAW.
AND
AND WE
WITHDRAW.
AND WE HAVE
AND WE HAVE ABOUT
WITHDRAW.
AND WE HAVE ABOUT 23
AND WE HAVE ABOUT 23 MILLION
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
AND WE HAVE ABOUT 23 MILLION
PEOPLE WHO ARE
PEOPLE WHO ARE ADDICTED
AND WE HAVE ABOUT 23 MILLION
PEOPLE WHO ARE ADDICTED IN
AMERICA.
SO
SO WHEN
AMERICA.
SO WHEN THEY
SO WHEN THEY GO
AMERICA.
SO WHEN THEY GO FOR
SO WHEN THEY GO FOR HELP,
AMERICA.
SO WHEN THEY GO FOR HELP, ONLY
ONE
ONE IN
SO WHEN THEY GO FOR HELP, ONLY
ONE IN 10
ONE IN 10 CAN
SO WHEN THEY GO FOR HELP, ONLY
ONE IN 10 CAN GET
ONE IN 10 CAN GET IT.
SEE
SEE YOU
ONE IN 10 CAN GET IT.
SEE YOU GOT
SEE YOU GOT THIS
ONE IN 10 CAN GET IT.
SEE YOU GOT THIS REAL
SEE YOU GOT THIS REAL DOUBLE
WHAMMY,
WHAMMY, PEOPLE
SEE YOU GOT THIS REAL DOUBLE
WHAMMY, PEOPLE WITH
WHAMMY, PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
HEALTH
HEALTH PROBLEMS
WHAMMY, PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
HEALTH PROBLEMS ARE
HEALTH PROBLEMS ARE GETTING
--
-- ARE
HEALTH PROBLEMS ARE GETTING
-- ARE NOT
-- ARE NOT GETTING
HEALTH PROBLEMS ARE GETTING
-- ARE NOT GETTING HELP,
-- ARE NOT GETTING HELP, PEOPLE
WITH
WITH ADDICTION
-- ARE NOT GETTING HELP, PEOPLE
WITH ADDICTION AND
WITH ADDICTION AND SUBSTANCE
ABUSE
ABUSE PROBLEMS
WITH ADDICTION AND SUBSTANCE
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE NOT
WITH ADDICTION AND SUBSTANCE
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE NOT GETTING
HELP,
HELP, AND
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE NOT GETTING
HELP, AND YOU
HELP, AND YOU GOT
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE NOT GETTING
HELP, AND YOU GOT TO
HELP, AND YOU GOT TO FIGURE
ABUSE PROBLEMS ARE NOT GETTING
HELP, AND YOU GOT TO FIGURE OUT
HOW
HOW WE
HELP, AND YOU GOT TO FIGURE OUT
HOW WE TAKE
HOW WE TAKE RESOURCES
HELP, AND YOU GOT TO FIGURE OUT
HOW WE TAKE RESOURCES AND
HOW WE TAKE RESOURCES AND TREAT
BOTH
BOTH PEOPLE
HOW WE TAKE RESOURCES AND TREAT
BOTH PEOPLE SIMULTANEOUSLY,
BECAUSE
BECAUSE TOO
BOTH PEOPLE SIMULTANEOUSLY,
BECAUSE TOO OFTEN,
BECAUSE TOO OFTEN, THEY
BOTH PEOPLE SIMULTANEOUSLY,
BECAUSE TOO OFTEN, THEY BECOME
INTERCONNECTED.
AND
AND THEN
INTERCONNECTED.
AND THEN WE
AND THEN WE HAVE
INTERCONNECTED.
AND THEN WE HAVE A
AND THEN WE HAVE A REAL
INTERCONNECTED.
AND THEN WE HAVE A REAL PROBLEM.
I
I PLEDGE
AND THEN WE HAVE A REAL PROBLEM.
I PLEDGE TO
I PLEDGE TO YOU,
AND THEN WE HAVE A REAL PROBLEM.
I PLEDGE TO YOU, I'M
I PLEDGE TO YOU, I'M GOING
AND THEN WE HAVE A REAL PROBLEM.
I PLEDGE TO YOU, I'M GOING TO
I PLEDGE TO YOU, I'M GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING
EVERYTHING I
I PLEDGE TO YOU, I'M GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING I CAN,
EVERYTHING I CAN, MORE
FACILITIES,
FACILITIES, MORE
EVERYTHING I CAN, MORE
FACILITIES, MORE TRAINED
FACILITIES, MORE TRAINED PEOPLE,
MORE
MORE INSURANCE
FACILITIES, MORE TRAINED PEOPLE,
MORE INSURANCE COVERAGE,
MORE INSURANCE COVERAGE, MORE
REVENUES.
YOU
YOU CAN
REVENUES.
YOU CAN CALL
YOU CAN CALL ON
REVENUES.
YOU CAN CALL ON SOMEBODY,
YOU CAN CALL ON SOMEBODY, YOU
KNOW
KNOW EVERYBODY.
[LAUGHTER]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[LAUGHTER]
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT,
HILLARY CLINTON: THAT, AND
ATTENTION.
HE
HE TOLD
ATTENTION.
HE TOLD ME
HE TOLD ME WE
ATTENTION.
HE TOLD ME WE ONLY
HE TOLD ME WE ONLY HAVE
ATTENTION.
HE TOLD ME WE ONLY HAVE TIME
HE TOLD ME WE ONLY HAVE TIME FOR
MORE
MORE QUESTION.
>>
>> A
MORE QUESTION.
>> A MAN
>> A MAN WHO
MORE QUESTION.
>> A MAN WHO LIVES
>> A MAN WHO LIVES NEXT
MORE QUESTION.
>> A MAN WHO LIVES NEXT DOOR
>> A MAN WHO LIVES NEXT DOOR TO
HEAR,
HEAR, HIS
>> A MAN WHO LIVES NEXT DOOR TO
HEAR, HIS NAME
HEAR, HIS NAME IS
>> A MAN WHO LIVES NEXT DOOR TO
HEAR, HIS NAME IS SANDERS,
HEAR, HIS NAME IS SANDERS, I
THINK.
HE
HE HAS
THINK.
HE HAS AN
HE HAS AN IDEA
THINK.
HE HAS AN IDEA ABOUT
HE HAS AN IDEA ABOUT SENDING
KIDS
KIDS TO
HE HAS AN IDEA ABOUT SENDING
KIDS TO COLLEGE
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR
HE HAS AN IDEA ABOUT SENDING
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR FREE,
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR FREE, AS
HE HAS AN IDEA ABOUT SENDING
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR FREE, AS HE
THINKS
THINKS THEY
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR FREE, AS HE
THINKS THEY DO
THINKS THEY DO IN
KIDS TO COLLEGE FOR FREE, AS HE
THINKS THEY DO IN EUROPE.
IT'S
IT'S NOT
THINKS THEY DO IN EUROPE.
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE,
THINKS THEY DO IN EUROPE.
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE, BUT
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE, BUT YOU
HAVE
HAVE A
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE, BUT YOU
HAVE A PLAN
HAVE A PLAN THAT
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE, BUT YOU
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD SORT
IT'S NOT ACTUALLY FREE, BUT YOU
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD SORT OF
MAKE
MAKE HIM
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD SORT OF
MAKE HIM BACK
MAKE HIM BACK DOWN
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD SORT OF
MAKE HIM BACK DOWN A
MAKE HIM BACK DOWN A LITTLE
HAVE A PLAN THAT WOULD SORT OF
MAKE HIM BACK DOWN A LITTLE BIT
ON
ON THIS?
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
ON THIS?
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I WILL
ON THIS?
HILLARY CLINTON: I WILL SPEAK
FOR
FOR MYSELF.
HE
HE IS
FOR MYSELF.
HE IS CLEARLY
HE IS CLEARLY MORE
FOR MYSELF.
HE IS CLEARLY MORE THAN
HE IS CLEARLY MORE THAN CAPABLE
OF
OF SPEAKING
HE IS CLEARLY MORE THAN CAPABLE
OF SPEAKING FOR
OF SPEAKING FOR HIMSELF.
WE'RE
WE'RE GOING
OF SPEAKING FOR HIMSELF.
WE'RE GOING TO
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
OF SPEAKING FOR HIMSELF.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A DEBATE
OF SPEAKING FOR HIMSELF.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A DEBATE IN
ABOUT
ABOUT EIGHT
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A DEBATE IN
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS,
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS, SO
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A DEBATE IN
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS, SO WE
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS, SO WE WILL
HAVE
HAVE A
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS, SO WE WILL
HAVE A CHANCE
HAVE A CHANCE TO
ABOUT EIGHT DAYS, SO WE WILL
HAVE A CHANCE TO CONTRAST.
BUT
BUT IF
HAVE A CHANCE TO CONTRAST.
BUT IF YOU
BUT IF YOU ARE
HAVE A CHANCE TO CONTRAST.
BUT IF YOU ARE INTERESTED
BUT IF YOU ARE INTERESTED IN
THIS
THIS ISSUE,
BUT IF YOU ARE INTERESTED IN
THIS ISSUE, AND
THIS ISSUE, AND I
BUT IF YOU ARE INTERESTED IN
THIS ISSUE, AND I THINK
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY IS,
THIS ISSUE, AND I THINK
EVERYBODY IS, HOW
EVERYBODY IS, HOW WE
THIS ISSUE, AND I THINK
EVERYBODY IS, HOW WE GET
EVERYBODY IS, HOW WE GET COLLEGE
MORE
MORE AFFORDABLE,
EVERYBODY IS, HOW WE GET COLLEGE
MORE AFFORDABLE, AND
MORE AFFORDABLE, AND HOW
EVERYBODY IS, HOW WE GET COLLEGE
MORE AFFORDABLE, AND HOW WE
REFINANCE
REFINANCE STUDENT
MORE AFFORDABLE, AND HOW WE
REFINANCE STUDENT DEBT
REFINANCE STUDENT DEBT --
MORE AFFORDABLE, AND HOW WE
REFINANCE STUDENT DEBT -- GO
REFINANCE STUDENT DEBT -- GO TO
MY
MY WEBSITE,
REFINANCE STUDENT DEBT -- GO TO
MY WEBSITE, HILLARY
MY WEBSITE, HILLARY CLINTON.COM.
IT'S
IT'S CALLED
MY WEBSITE, HILLARY CLINTON.COM.
IT'S CALLED THE
IT'S CALLED THE NEW
MY WEBSITE, HILLARY CLINTON.COM.
IT'S CALLED THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT,
COMPACT, BUT
IT'S CALLED THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT, BUT VERY
COMPACT, BUT VERY BRIEFLY,
IT'S CALLED THE NEW COLLEGE
COMPACT, BUT VERY BRIEFLY, I
COMPACT, BUT VERY BRIEFLY, I DO
HAVE
HAVE A
COMPACT, BUT VERY BRIEFLY, I DO
HAVE A DIFFERENT
HAVE A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
FIRST
FIRST OF
HAVE A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
FIRST OF ALL,
FIRST OF ALL, MY
HAVE A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
FIRST OF ALL, MY APPROACH
FIRST OF ALL, MY APPROACH IS
BEEN,
BEEN, THANKFULLY,
FIRST OF ALL, MY APPROACH IS
BEEN, THANKFULLY, ENDORSED
BEEN, THANKFULLY, ENDORSED BY
FIRST OF ALL, MY APPROACH IS
BEEN, THANKFULLY, ENDORSED BY A
LOT
LOT OF
BEEN, THANKFULLY, ENDORSED BY A
LOT OF PEOPLE
LOT OF PEOPLE BECAUSE
BEEN, THANKFULLY, ENDORSED BY A
LOT OF PEOPLE BECAUSE I
LOT OF PEOPLE BECAUSE I THINK
WHAT
WHAT IT
LOT OF PEOPLE BECAUSE I THINK
WHAT IT DOES
WHAT IT DOES IS
LOT OF PEOPLE BECAUSE I THINK
WHAT IT DOES IS IT
WHAT IT DOES IS IT ADDRESSES
MANY
MANY ASPECTS
WHAT IT DOES IS IT ADDRESSES
MANY ASPECTS OF
MANY ASPECTS OF THIS
WHAT IT DOES IS IT ADDRESSES
MANY ASPECTS OF THIS PROBLEM.
FIRST,
FIRST, WE'VE
MANY ASPECTS OF THIS PROBLEM.
FIRST, WE'VE GOT
FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO
MANY ASPECTS OF THIS PROBLEM.
FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO GET
FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO GET THE
MANY ASPECTS OF THIS PROBLEM.
FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO GET THE COST
OF
OF COLLEGE
FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO GET THE COST
OF COLLEGE DOWN.
COLLEGES
COLLEGES AND
OF COLLEGE DOWN.
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES HAVE
TO
TO QUIT
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES HAVE
TO QUIT RAISING
TO QUIT RAISING TUITION
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES HAVE
TO QUIT RAISING TUITION AND
COSTS
COSTS ON
TO QUIT RAISING TUITION AND
COSTS ON STUDENTS
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND
TO QUIT RAISING TUITION AND
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND FAMILIES.
IF
IF ALL
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND FAMILIES.
IF ALL WE
IF ALL WE DO
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND FAMILIES.
IF ALL WE DO IS
IF ALL WE DO IS TO
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND FAMILIES.
IF ALL WE DO IS TO SAY
IF ALL WE DO IS TO SAY WE
COSTS ON STUDENTS AND FAMILIES.
IF ALL WE DO IS TO SAY WE ARE
GOING
GOING TO
IF ALL WE DO IS TO SAY WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE
GOING TO HAVE FREE
IF ALL WE DO IS TO SAY WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE FREE COLLEGE,
GOING TO HAVE FREE COLLEGE, BUT
WE
WE DON'T
GOING TO HAVE FREE COLLEGE, BUT
WE DON'T REALLY
WE DON'T REALLY PUT
GOING TO HAVE FREE COLLEGE, BUT
WE DON'T REALLY PUT PRESSURE
WE DON'T REALLY PUT PRESSURE ON
THE
THE COLLEGES
WE DON'T REALLY PUT PRESSURE ON
THE COLLEGES AND
THE COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
WE DON'T REALLY PUT PRESSURE ON
THE COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO
LOWER
LOWER THE
THE COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO
LOWER THE COST,
LOWER THE COST, YOU'RE
THE COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO
LOWER THE COST, YOU'RE GOING
LOWER THE COST, YOU'RE GOING TO
CONTINUE
CONTINUE TO
LOWER THE COST, YOU'RE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO SEE
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS
LOWER THE COST, YOU'RE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS GOING
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS GOING UP,
AND
AND THEN
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS GOING UP,
AND THEN THE
AND THEN THE COST
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS GOING UP,
AND THEN THE COST OF
AND THEN THE COST OF THE
CONTINUE TO SEE COSTS GOING UP,
AND THEN THE COST OF THE QUOTE
FREE
FREE COLLEGE
AND THEN THE COST OF THE QUOTE
FREE COLLEGE WILL
FREE COLLEGE WILL GO
AND THEN THE COST OF THE QUOTE
FREE COLLEGE WILL GO UP.
THAT
THAT TO
FREE COLLEGE WILL GO UP.
THAT TO ME
THAT TO ME IS
FREE COLLEGE WILL GO UP.
THAT TO ME IS UNSUSTAINABLE.
FIRST
FIRST AND
THAT TO ME IS UNSUSTAINABLE.
FIRST AND FOREMOST,
FIRST AND FOREMOST, I
THAT TO ME IS UNSUSTAINABLE.
FIRST AND FOREMOST, I WANT
COLLEGES
COLLEGES AND
FIRST AND FOREMOST, I WANT
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
LOOKING
LOOKING AT,
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
LOOKING AT, AND
LOOKING AT, AND ADMINISTRATORS
THEY
THEY NEED,
LOOKING AT, AND ADMINISTRATORS
THEY NEED, HOW
THEY NEED, HOW MANY
LOOKING AT, AND ADMINISTRATORS
THEY NEED, HOW MANY BUILDINGS
THEY
THEY NEED,
THEY NEED, HOW MANY BUILDINGS
THEY NEED, CONNIE
THEY NEED, CONNIE DIFFERENT
COURSES
COURSES ARE
THEY NEED, CONNIE DIFFERENT
COURSES ARE NO
COURSES ARE NO LONGER
THEY NEED, CONNIE DIFFERENT
COURSES ARE NO LONGER REALLY
RELEVANT.
LET'S
LET'S TAKE
RELEVANT.
LET'S TAKE A
LET'S TAKE A HARD
RELEVANT.
LET'S TAKE A HARD LOOK
LET'S TAKE A HARD LOOK AT
RELEVANT.
LET'S TAKE A HARD LOOK AT WHAT
WE'RE
WE'RE DOING
LET'S TAKE A HARD LOOK AT WHAT
WE'RE DOING ON
WE'RE DOING ON CAMPUS.
YET
YET THOSE
WE'RE DOING ON CAMPUS.
YET THOSE COSTS
YET THOSE COSTS DOWN
WE'RE DOING ON CAMPUS.
YET THOSE COSTS DOWN SO
YET THOSE COSTS DOWN SO WE
WE'RE DOING ON CAMPUS.
YET THOSE COSTS DOWN SO WE CAN
KEEP
KEEP TUITION
YET THOSE COSTS DOWN SO WE CAN
KEEP TUITION DOWN.
SECONDLY,
SECONDLY, I
KEEP TUITION DOWN.
SECONDLY, I HAVE
SECONDLY, I HAVE SAID
KEEP TUITION DOWN.
SECONDLY, I HAVE SAID THAT
SECONDLY, I HAVE SAID THAT THE
FEDERAL
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
SECONDLY, I HAVE SAID THAT THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT --
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT -- I
SECONDLY, I HAVE SAID THAT THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT -- I HAVE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT -- I HAVE A
PLAN,
PLAN, $350
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT -- I HAVE A
PLAN, $350 BILLION
PLAN, $350 BILLION OVER
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT -- I HAVE A
PLAN, $350 BILLION OVER 10
YEARS.
ABOUT
ABOUT $35
YEARS.
ABOUT $35 BILLION
ABOUT $35 BILLION A
YEARS.
ABOUT $35 BILLION A YEAR,
ABOUT $35 BILLION A YEAR, WHERE
WE
WE WOULD
ABOUT $35 BILLION A YEAR, WHERE
WE WOULD MATCH
WE WOULD MATCH FOR
ABOUT $35 BILLION A YEAR, WHERE
WE WOULD MATCH FOR EVERY
WE WOULD MATCH FOR EVERY DOLLAR
THAT
THAT THE
WE WOULD MATCH FOR EVERY DOLLAR
THAT THE STATE
THAT THE STATE WOULD
WE WOULD MATCH FOR EVERY DOLLAR
THAT THE STATE WOULD PUT
THAT THE STATE WOULD PUT IN
WE WOULD MATCH FOR EVERY DOLLAR
THAT THE STATE WOULD PUT IN TO
MAKING
MAKING COLLEGE
THAT THE STATE WOULD PUT IN TO
MAKING COLLEGE MORE
MAKING COLLEGE MORE AFFORDABLE
FOR
FOR THEIR
MAKING COLLEGE MORE AFFORDABLE
FOR THEIR STUDENTS,
FOR THEIR STUDENTS, WE
MAKING COLLEGE MORE AFFORDABLE
FOR THEIR STUDENTS, WE WOULD
MATCH
MATCH THEM
FOR THEIR STUDENTS, WE WOULD
MATCH THEM FOR
MATCH THEM FOR TO
FOR THEIR STUDENTS, WE WOULD
MATCH THEM FOR TO ONE.
THEY
THEY WOULD
MATCH THEM FOR TO ONE.
THEY WOULD HAVE
THEY WOULD HAVE TO
MATCH THEM FOR TO ONE.
THEY WOULD HAVE TO AGREE
THEY WOULD HAVE TO AGREE ON
MATCH THEM FOR TO ONE.
THEY WOULD HAVE TO AGREE ON SOME
OF
OF THESE
THEY WOULD HAVE TO AGREE ON SOME
OF THESE CHANGES
OF THESE CHANGES THE
THEY WOULD HAVE TO AGREE ON SOME
OF THESE CHANGES THE PUBLIC
COLLEGES
COLLEGES AND
OF THESE CHANGES THE PUBLIC
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO
OF THESE CHANGES THE PUBLIC
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES TO GET
THE
THE MONEY.
AND
AND THEN,
THE MONEY.
AND THEN, IF
AND THEN, IF YOU
THE MONEY.
AND THEN, IF YOU CHOOSE
AND THEN, IF YOU CHOOSE A
THE MONEY.
AND THEN, IF YOU CHOOSE A PUBLIC
COLLEGE
COLLEGE OR
AND THEN, IF YOU CHOOSE A PUBLIC
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY,
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, I
AND THEN, IF YOU CHOOSE A PUBLIC
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, I WILL
MAKE
MAKE IT
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, I WILL
MAKE IT POSSIBLE
MAKE IT POSSIBLE FOR
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, I WILL
MAKE IT POSSIBLE FOR YOU
MAKE IT POSSIBLE FOR YOU TO
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, I WILL
MAKE IT POSSIBLE FOR YOU TO GO
WITHOUT
WITHOUT BORROWING
MAKE IT POSSIBLE FOR YOU TO GO
WITHOUT BORROWING MONEY
WITHOUT BORROWING MONEY FOR
TUITION,
TUITION, BUT
WITHOUT BORROWING MONEY FOR
TUITION, BUT I
TUITION, BUT I WILL
WITHOUT BORROWING MONEY FOR
TUITION, BUT I WILL EXPECT
SOMETHING
SOMETHING FROM
TUITION, BUT I WILL EXPECT
SOMETHING FROM YOU.
LIKE,
LIKE, FOR
SOMETHING FROM YOU.
LIKE, FOR EXAMPLE,
LIKE, FOR EXAMPLE, 10
SOMETHING FROM YOU.
LIKE, FOR EXAMPLE, 10 HOURS
LIKE, FOR EXAMPLE, 10 HOURS OF
WORK
WORK WEEK.
I
I WORKED
WORK WEEK.
I WORKED WHEN
I WORKED WHEN I
WORK WEEK.
I WORKED WHEN I WAS
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN
WORK WEEK.
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I
I WORKED
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I WORKED WHEN
I WORKED WHEN I
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I WORKED WHEN I WAS
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I WORKED WHEN I WAS IN LAW
SCHOOL.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT YOUNG
PEOPLE
PEOPLE TO
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT YOUNG
PEOPLE TO KNOW
PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT YOUNG
PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT THIS
PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT THIS IS
HILLARY CLINTON: I WANT YOUNG
PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT THIS IS AN
IMPORTANT
IMPORTANT VALUE.
AND
AND YES,
IMPORTANT VALUE.
AND YES, YOU
AND YES, YOU HAVE
IMPORTANT VALUE.
AND YES, YOU HAVE TO
AND YES, YOU HAVE TO WORK
IMPORTANT VALUE.
AND YES, YOU HAVE TO WORK FOR
IT.
BUT
BUT IT
IT.
BUT IT WILL
BUT IT WILL BE
IT.
BUT IT WILL BE FOR
BUT IT WILL BE FOR A
IT.
BUT IT WILL BE FOR A PUBLIC
COLLEGE
COLLEGE OR
BUT IT WILL BE FOR A PUBLIC
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY,
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, POSSIBLE
TO
TO NOT
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, POSSIBLE
TO NOT BORROW
TO NOT BORROW MONEY
COLLEGE OR UNIVERSITY, POSSIBLE
TO NOT BORROW MONEY FOR
TO NOT BORROW MONEY FOR TUITION.
FOR
FOR LIVING
TO NOT BORROW MONEY FOR TUITION.
FOR LIVING EXPENSES,
FOR LIVING EXPENSES, I
TO NOT BORROW MONEY FOR TUITION.
FOR LIVING EXPENSES, I WILL
FOR LIVING EXPENSES, I WILL MAKE
IT
IT POSSIBLE
FOR LIVING EXPENSES, I WILL MAKE
IT POSSIBLE FOR
IT POSSIBLE FOR THE
FOR LIVING EXPENSES, I WILL MAKE
IT POSSIBLE FOR THE PELL
IT POSSIBLE FOR THE PELL GRANTS
TO
TO BE
IT POSSIBLE FOR THE PELL GRANTS
TO BE USED
TO BE USED FOR
IT POSSIBLE FOR THE PELL GRANTS
TO BE USED FOR LIVING
TO BE USED FOR LIVING EXPENSES.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE WHAT
TO BE USED FOR LIVING EXPENSES.
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENS
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENS NOW
TO BE USED FOR LIVING EXPENSES.
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENS NOW IS
YOUNG
YOUNG PEOPLE
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENS NOW IS
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO GET
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENS NOW IS
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO GET A
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO GET A PELL
GRANT,
GRANT, THEY
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO GET A PELL
GRANT, THEY OFTEN
GRANT, THEY OFTEN FIND
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO GET A PELL
GRANT, THEY OFTEN FIND IT
DOESN'T
DOESN'T EVEN
GRANT, THEY OFTEN FIND IT
DOESN'T EVEN COVER
DOESN'T EVEN COVER TUITION
ANYMORE.
SO
SO WE
ANYMORE.
SO WE WILL
SO WE WILL DEAL
ANYMORE.
SO WE WILL DEAL WITH
SO WE WILL DEAL WITH THE
ANYMORE.
SO WE WILL DEAL WITH THE TUITION
SIDE
SIDE ON
SO WE WILL DEAL WITH THE TUITION
SIDE ON THE
SIDE ON THE PUBLIC
SO WE WILL DEAL WITH THE TUITION
SIDE ON THE PUBLIC COLLEGE
SIDE ON THE PUBLIC COLLEGE AND
UNIVERSITY.
AND
AND THEN
UNIVERSITY.
AND THEN WE
AND THEN WE WILL
UNIVERSITY.
AND THEN WE WILL DEAL
AND THEN WE WILL DEAL WITH
UNIVERSITY.
AND THEN WE WILL DEAL WITH THE
LIVING
LIVING EXPENSE
AND THEN WE WILL DEAL WITH THE
LIVING EXPENSE SIDE.
IF
IF YOU
LIVING EXPENSE SIDE.
IF YOU DO
IF YOU DO HAVE
LIVING EXPENSE SIDE.
IF YOU DO HAVE TO
IF YOU DO HAVE TO BORROW
LIVING EXPENSE SIDE.
IF YOU DO HAVE TO BORROW MONEY,
IT
IT WILL
IF YOU DO HAVE TO BORROW MONEY,
IT WILL BE
IT WILL BE WITH
IF YOU DO HAVE TO BORROW MONEY,
IT WILL BE WITH A
IT WILL BE WITH A LOW
IF YOU DO HAVE TO BORROW MONEY,
IT WILL BE WITH A LOW INTEREST
RATE.
AND
AND I
RATE.
AND I WILL
AND I WILL FORGIVE
RATE.
AND I WILL FORGIVE LOANS
AND I WILL FORGIVE LOANS TO
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
AND I WILL FORGIVE LOANS TO
PEOPLE WHO DO
PEOPLE WHO DO PUBLIC
AND I WILL FORGIVE LOANS TO
PEOPLE WHO DO PUBLIC SERVICE
JOBS
JOBS AFTER
PEOPLE WHO DO PUBLIC SERVICE
JOBS AFTER A
JOBS AFTER A PERIOD
PEOPLE WHO DO PUBLIC SERVICE
JOBS AFTER A PERIOD OF
JOBS AFTER A PERIOD OF TIME
PEOPLE WHO DO PUBLIC SERVICE
JOBS AFTER A PERIOD OF TIME --
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: SO
HILLARY CLINTON: SO --
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: SO -- I
HILLARY CLINTON: SO -- I HAVE
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: SO -- I HAVE TO
TELL
TELL YOU.
I
I DON'T
TELL YOU.
I DON'T THINK
I DON'T THINK COLLEGE
TELL YOU.
I DON'T THINK COLLEGE SHOULD
I DON'T THINK COLLEGE SHOULD BE
FREE
FREE FOR
I DON'T THINK COLLEGE SHOULD BE
FREE FOR DONALD
FREE FOR DONALD TRUMP'S
CHILDREN.
I
I THINK
CHILDREN.
I THINK PEOPLE
I THINK PEOPLE WHO
CHILDREN.
I THINK PEOPLE WHO ARE
I THINK PEOPLE WHO ARE WELL
CHILDREN.
I THINK PEOPLE WHO ARE WELL OFF
SHOULD
SHOULD HAVE
I THINK PEOPLE WHO ARE WELL OFF
SHOULD HAVE TO
SHOULD HAVE TO PAY
I THINK PEOPLE WHO ARE WELL OFF
SHOULD HAVE TO PAY FOR
SHOULD HAVE TO PAY FOR COLLEGE.
I'M
I'M INTERESTED
SHOULD HAVE TO PAY FOR COLLEGE.
I'M INTERESTED IN
I'M INTERESTED IN THE
SHOULD HAVE TO PAY FOR COLLEGE.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE MIDDLE
CLASS,
CLASS, AND
I'M INTERESTED IN THE MIDDLE
CLASS, AND WORKING
CLASS, AND WORKING PEOPLE,
I'M INTERESTED IN THE MIDDLE
CLASS, AND WORKING PEOPLE, AND
POOR
POOR KIDS
CLASS, AND WORKING PEOPLE, AND
POOR KIDS WHO
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE
CLASS, AND WORKING PEOPLE, AND
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE TO
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE TO HAVE
CLASS, AND WORKING PEOPLE, AND
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE TO HAVE A
BETTER
BETTER SHOT
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE TO HAVE A
BETTER SHOT AT
BETTER SHOT AT GOING
POOR KIDS WHO DESERVE TO HAVE A
BETTER SHOT AT GOING TO
BETTER SHOT AT GOING TO COLLEGE
AND
AND GRADUATING.
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I
HILLARY CLINTON: I FEEL
[APPLAUSE]
HILLARY CLINTON: I FEEL STRONGLY
THAT,
THAT, WHEN
HILLARY CLINTON: I FEEL STRONGLY
THAT, WHEN YOU
THAT, WHEN YOU ALREADY
HILLARY CLINTON: I FEEL STRONGLY
THAT, WHEN YOU ALREADY HAVE
THAT, WHEN YOU ALREADY HAVE TO
--
-- WHO
THAT, WHEN YOU ALREADY HAVE TO
-- WHO HAS
-- WHO HAS STUDENT
THAT, WHEN YOU ALREADY HAVE TO
-- WHO HAS STUDENT DEBT
-- WHO HAS STUDENT DEBT STILL?
OH,
OH, YEAH.
WE
WE HAVE
OH, YEAH.
WE HAVE 40
WE HAVE 40 MILLION
OH, YEAH.
WE HAVE 40 MILLION PEOPLE
WE HAVE 40 MILLION PEOPLE IN
AMERICA
AMERICA WAS
WE HAVE 40 MILLION PEOPLE IN
AMERICA WAS DOING
AMERICA WAS DOING DEBT.
WHAT
WHAT I
AMERICA WAS DOING DEBT.
WHAT I WANT
WHAT I WANT IS
AMERICA WAS DOING DEBT.
WHAT I WANT IS TO
WHAT I WANT IS TO REFINANCE
AMERICA WAS DOING DEBT.
WHAT I WANT IS TO REFINANCE ALL
THE
THE STUDENT
WHAT I WANT IS TO REFINANCE ALL
THE STUDENT DEBT.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE RIGHT
THE STUDENT DEBT.
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW,
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF
THE STUDENT DEBT.
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF YOU
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF YOU HAVE
THE STUDENT DEBT.
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF YOU HAVE A
HOME
HOME MORTGAGE,
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF YOU HAVE A
HOME MORTGAGE, OR
HOME MORTGAGE, OR YOU'RE
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IF YOU HAVE A
HOME MORTGAGE, OR YOU'RE MAKING
CAR
CAR PAYMENTS,
HOME MORTGAGE, OR YOU'RE MAKING
CAR PAYMENTS, YOU
CAR PAYMENTS, YOU CAN
HOME MORTGAGE, OR YOU'RE MAKING
CAR PAYMENTS, YOU CAN REFINANCE
IT.
WE
WE FOR
IT.
WE FOR BID
WE FOR BID YOU
IT.
WE FOR BID YOU FROM
WE FOR BID YOU FROM REFINANCING
STUDENT
STUDENT DEBT.
AND
AND AT
STUDENT DEBT.
AND AT THE
AND AT THE EVENT
STUDENT DEBT.
AND AT THE EVENT I
AND AT THE EVENT I DID
STUDENT DEBT.
AND AT THE EVENT I DID EARLIER
IN
IN HOLLAND,
AND AT THE EVENT I DID EARLIER
IN HOLLAND, A
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG
AND AT THE EVENT I DID EARLIER
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN WAY
AND AT THE EVENT I DID EARLIER
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN WAY IN
THE
THE BACK
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN WAY IN
THE BACK WHO
THE BACK WHO SAID
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN WAY IN
THE BACK WHO SAID HER
THE BACK WHO SAID HER JUST
IN HOLLAND, A YOUNG WOMAN WAY IN
THE BACK WHO SAID HER JUST RATE
IS
IS 12%.
I
I WANT
IS 12%.
I WANT US
I WANT US TO
IS 12%.
I WANT US TO REFINANCE
I WANT US TO REFINANCE IT,
IS 12%.
I WANT US TO REFINANCE IT, I
WANT
WANT TO
I WANT US TO REFINANCE IT, I
WANT TO PROVIDE
WANT TO PROVIDE EVERYBODY
I WANT US TO REFINANCE IT, I
WANT TO PROVIDE EVERYBODY THE
CHANCE
CHANCE TO
WANT TO PROVIDE EVERYBODY THE
CHANCE TO PAY
CHANCE TO PAY BACK
WANT TO PROVIDE EVERYBODY THE
CHANCE TO PAY BACK THEIR
CHANCE TO PAY BACK THEIR LOANS
AS
AS A
CHANCE TO PAY BACK THEIR LOANS
AS A PERCENTAGE
AS A PERCENTAGE OF
CHANCE TO PAY BACK THEIR LOANS
AS A PERCENTAGE OF THEIR
AS A PERCENTAGE OF THEIR INCOME.
IF
IF YOU
AS A PERCENTAGE OF THEIR INCOME.
IF YOU ARE
IF YOU ARE A
AS A PERCENTAGE OF THEIR INCOME.
IF YOU ARE A FIREFIGHTER
IF YOU ARE A FIREFIGHTER OR
SCHOOL
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL,
IF YOU ARE A FIREFIGHTER OR
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, OR
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, OR SOCIAL
WORKER,
WORKER, OR
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, OR SOCIAL
WORKER, OR A
WORKER, OR A POLICE
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, OR SOCIAL
WORKER, OR A POLICE OFFICER
WORKER, OR A POLICE OFFICER --
WHATEVER
WHATEVER YOU
WORKER, OR A POLICE OFFICER --
WHATEVER YOU ARE
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING
WORKER, OR A POLICE OFFICER --
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING THAT
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING THAT YOU
WANT
WANT TO
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING THAT YOU
WANT TO DO,
WANT TO DO, BUT
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING THAT YOU
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU ARE
WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING THAT YOU
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU ARE NOT
MAKING
MAKING A
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU ARE NOT
MAKING A LOT
MAKING A LOT OF
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU ARE NOT
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY,
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY, YOU
WANT TO DO, BUT YOU ARE NOT
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY, YOU ARE
NOT
NOT GOING
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY, YOU ARE
NOT GOING TO
NOT GOING TO HAVE
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY, YOU ARE
NOT GOING TO HAVE TO
NOT GOING TO HAVE TO PAY
MAKING A LOT OF MONEY, YOU ARE
NOT GOING TO HAVE TO PAY BACK
NOT GOING TO HAVE TO PAY BACK AT
THAT
THAT HIGH
NOT GOING TO HAVE TO PAY BACK AT
THAT HIGH INTEREST
THAT HIGH INTEREST RATE.
YOU
YOU ARE
THAT HIGH INTEREST RATE.
YOU ARE GOING
YOU ARE GOING TO
THAT HIGH INTEREST RATE.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE
THAT HIGH INTEREST RATE.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO PAY
BACK
BACK AT
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO PAY
BACK AT ABOUT
BACK AT ABOUT 10%
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO PAY
BACK AT ABOUT 10% OF
BACK AT ABOUT 10% OF YOUR
INCOME.
WHEN
WHEN I
INCOME.
WHEN I GOT
WHEN I GOT OUT
INCOME.
WHEN I GOT OUT OF
WHEN I GOT OUT OF LAW
INCOME.
WHEN I GOT OUT OF LAW SCHOOL
WHEN I GOT OUT OF LAW SCHOOL I
WENT
WENT TO
WHEN I GOT OUT OF LAW SCHOOL I
WENT TO WORK
WENT TO WORK FOR
WHEN I GOT OUT OF LAW SCHOOL I
WENT TO WORK FOR THE
WENT TO WORK FOR THE CHILDREN'S
DEFENSE
DEFENSE FUND,
WENT TO WORK FOR THE CHILDREN'S
DEFENSE FUND, I
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T
WENT TO WORK FOR THE CHILDREN'S
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO TO
WENT TO WORK FOR THE CHILDREN'S
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO TO A
BIG
BIG LAW
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO TO A
BIG LAW FIRM,
BIG LAW FIRM, I
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO TO A
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT TO
DEFENSE FUND, I DIDN'T GO TO A
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT TO WORK
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT TO WORK FOR
A
A NONPROFIT
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT TO WORK FOR
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE I
BIG LAW FIRM, I WENT TO WORK FOR
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE I WANTED
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE I WANTED TO
WORK
WORK ON
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE I WANTED TO
WORK ON BEHALF
WORK ON BEHALF OF
A NONPROFIT BECAUSE I WANTED TO
WORK ON BEHALF OF KIDS.
I
I WAS
WORK ON BEHALF OF KIDS.
I WAS LUCKY
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH
WORK ON BEHALF OF KIDS.
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH THAT
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH THAT THE
UNIVERSITY
UNIVERSITY AT
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH THAT THE
UNIVERSITY AT THAT
UNIVERSITY AT THAT TIME
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH THAT THE
UNIVERSITY AT THAT TIME OFFERED
ME
ME THE
UNIVERSITY AT THAT TIME OFFERED
ME THE CHANCE
ME THE CHANCE TO
UNIVERSITY AT THAT TIME OFFERED
ME THE CHANCE TO PAY
ME THE CHANCE TO PAY IT
UNIVERSITY AT THAT TIME OFFERED
ME THE CHANCE TO PAY IT BACK
ME THE CHANCE TO PAY IT BACK AS
A
A PERCENTAGE.
BOTH
BOTH BILL
A PERCENTAGE.
BOTH BILL AND
BOTH BILL AND I
A PERCENTAGE.
BOTH BILL AND I HAD
BOTH BILL AND I HAD LOANS,
A PERCENTAGE.
BOTH BILL AND I HAD LOANS, AND
HE
HE WAS
BOTH BILL AND I HAD LOANS, AND
HE WAS A
HE WAS A LAW
BOTH BILL AND I HAD LOANS, AND
HE WAS A LAW PROFESSOR
HE WAS A LAW PROFESSOR AND
BOTH BILL AND I HAD LOANS, AND
HE WAS A LAW PROFESSOR AND I
BECAME
BECAME A
HE WAS A LAW PROFESSOR AND I
BECAME A LAW
BECAME A LAW PROFESSOR.
WE
WE WERE
BECAME A LAW PROFESSOR.
WE WERE MAKING
WE WERE MAKING $14,000,
BECAME A LAW PROFESSOR.
WE WERE MAKING $14,000, $17,000
A
A YEAR.
WE
WE WERE
A YEAR.
WE WERE PAYING
WE WERE PAYING BACK
A YEAR.
WE WERE PAYING BACK OUR
WE WERE PAYING BACK OUR LOANS
A YEAR.
WE WERE PAYING BACK OUR LOANS BY
WHAT
WHAT WE
WE WERE PAYING BACK OUR LOANS BY
WHAT WE CAN
WHAT WE CAN AFFORD.
I
I WANT
WHAT WE CAN AFFORD.
I WANT THIS
I WANT THIS TO
WHAT WE CAN AFFORD.
I WANT THIS TO BE,
I WANT THIS TO BE, AS
WHAT WE CAN AFFORD.
I WANT THIS TO BE, AS I
I WANT THIS TO BE, AS I SAY,
WHAT WE CAN AFFORD.
I WANT THIS TO BE, AS I SAY, A
COMPACT.
WHERE
WHERE PEOPLE
COMPACT.
WHERE PEOPLE DO
WHERE PEOPLE DO THEIR
COMPACT.
WHERE PEOPLE DO THEIR PART,
OBVIOUSLY,
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG
WHERE PEOPLE DO THEIR PART,
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG PEOPLE
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG PEOPLE HOW
WHERE PEOPLE DO THEIR PART,
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG PEOPLE HOW TO
DO
DO THEIR
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG PEOPLE HOW TO
DO THEIR PART,
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES
OBVIOUSLY, YOUNG PEOPLE HOW TO
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES HAVE
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES HAVE TO
DO
DO WHAT
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES HAVE TO
DO WHAT THEY
DO WHAT THEY CAN
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES HAVE TO
DO WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD
DO WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD TO
DO THEIR PART, FAMILIES HAVE TO
DO WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD TO DO.
COLLEGES
COLLEGES HAVE
DO WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD TO DO.
COLLEGES HAVE TO
COLLEGES HAVE TO PITCH
DO WHAT THEY CAN AFFORD TO DO.
COLLEGES HAVE TO PITCH IN
COLLEGES HAVE TO PITCH IN AND
GET
GET THE
COLLEGES HAVE TO PITCH IN AND
GET THE COSTS
GET THE COSTS DOWN.
AND
AND THE
GET THE COSTS DOWN.
AND THE FEDERAL
AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
GET THE COSTS DOWN.
AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WILL
PARTNER
PARTNER WITH
AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WILL
PARTNER WITH STATES.
WE'VE
WE'VE HAD
PARTNER WITH STATES.
WE'VE HAD THIS
WE'VE HAD THIS EXAMPLE
PARTNER WITH STATES.
WE'VE HAD THIS EXAMPLE OF
MEDICAID.
IF
IF THE
MEDICAID.
IF THE STATE
IF THE STATE SAYS
MEDICAID.
IF THE STATE SAYS NO,
IF THE STATE SAYS NO, WE
MEDICAID.
IF THE STATE SAYS NO, WE DON'T
WANT
WANT TO
IF THE STATE SAYS NO, WE DON'T
WANT TO PARTNER
WANT TO PARTNER WITH
IF THE STATE SAYS NO, WE DON'T
WANT TO PARTNER WITH THE
WANT TO PARTNER WITH THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT,
GOVERNMENT, THEN
WANT TO PARTNER WITH THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT, THEN I
GOVERNMENT, THEN I WILL
WANT TO PARTNER WITH THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT, THEN I WILL WRITE
INSTITUTIONS
INSTITUTIONS LIKE
GOVERNMENT, THEN I WILL WRITE
INSTITUTIONS LIKE THIS
INSTITUTIONS LIKE THIS ONE.
I
I DO
INSTITUTIONS LIKE THIS ONE.
I DO WANT
I DO WANT TO
INSTITUTIONS LIKE THIS ONE.
I DO WANT TO ME
I DO WANT TO ME TO
INSTITUTIONS LIKE THIS ONE.
I DO WANT TO ME TO COLLEGES
I DO WANT TO ME TO COLLEGES TO
--
-- I
I DO WANT TO ME TO COLLEGES TO
-- I DO
-- I DO WANT
I DO WANT TO ME TO COLLEGES TO
-- I DO WANT COMMUNITY
-- I DO WANT COMMUNITY COLLEGES
TO
TO BE
-- I DO WANT COMMUNITY COLLEGES
TO BE AS
TO BE AS INEXPENSIVE
-- I DO WANT COMMUNITY COLLEGES
TO BE AS INEXPENSIVE AS
POSSIBLE,
POSSIBLE, BECAUSE
TO BE AS INEXPENSIVE AS
POSSIBLE, BECAUSE IT'S
POSSIBLE, BECAUSE IT'S AN
IMPORTANT
IMPORTANT STEP
POSSIBLE, BECAUSE IT'S AN
IMPORTANT STEP FOR
IMPORTANT STEP FOR A
POSSIBLE, BECAUSE IT'S AN
IMPORTANT STEP FOR A LOT
IMPORTANT STEP FOR A LOT OF
YOUNG
YOUNG PEOPLE
IMPORTANT STEP FOR A LOT OF
YOUNG PEOPLE TO
YOUNG PEOPLE TO TAKE.
THANK
THANK YOU
YOUNG PEOPLE TO TAKE.
THANK YOU ALL
THANK YOU ALL VERY
YOUNG PEOPLE TO TAKE.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
[APPLAUSE]
[CAPTIONS
[CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT
[APPLAUSE]
[CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT NATIONAL
CABLE
CABLE SATELLITE
[CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT NATIONAL
CABLE SATELLITE CORP.
CABLE SATELLITE CORP. 2015]
[CAPTIONING
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED
CABLE SATELLITE CORP. 2015]
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL
NATIONAL CAPTIONING
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH
WHICH IS
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION
CAPTION CONTENT
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION CONTENT AND
CAPTION CONTENT AND ACCURACY.
VISIT
VISIT NCICAP.ORG]
[INDISCERNIBLE
[INDISCERNIBLE CONVERSATIONS]
>>
>> ALSO
[INDISCERNIBLE CONVERSATIONS]
>> ALSO IN
>> ALSO IN NEW
[INDISCERNIBLE CONVERSATIONS]
>> ALSO IN NEW HAMPSHIRE
>> ALSO IN NEW HAMPSHIRE TODAY,
THE
THE STATE'S
>> ALSO IN NEW HAMPSHIRE TODAY,
THE STATE'S DEMOCRATIC
THE STATE'S DEMOCRATIC GOVERNOR
ANNOUNCED
ANNOUNCED SHE
THE STATE'S DEMOCRATIC GOVERNOR
ANNOUNCED SHE WILL
ANNOUNCED SHE WILL BE
THE STATE'S DEMOCRATIC GOVERNOR
ANNOUNCED SHE WILL BE RUNNING
FOR
FOR U.S.
ANNOUNCED SHE WILL BE RUNNING
FOR U.S. SENATE
FOR U.S. SENATE AGAINST
ANNOUNCED SHE WILL BE RUNNING
FOR U.S. SENATE AGAINST KELLY
AYOTTE.
SHE
SHE MADE
AYOTTE.
SHE MADE HER